[
{
'ID': 1,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MANZANA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'APPLE'
},
{
'ID': 2,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MALO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BAD'
},
{
'ID': 3,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GRANDE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BIG'
},
{
'ID': 4,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NEGRO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BLACK'
},
{
'ID': 5,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AZUL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BLUE'
},
{
'ID': 6,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LIBRO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BOOK'
},
{
'ID': 7,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MUCHACHO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BOY'
},
{
'ID': 8,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COCHE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CAR'
},
{
'ID': 9,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GATO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CAT'
},
{
'ID': 10,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SILLA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CHAIR'
},
{
'ID': 11,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CIUDAD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CITY'
},
{
'ID': 12,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CLASE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CLASS'
},
{
'ID': 13,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PERRO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DOG'
},
{
'ID': 14,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BIEN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FINE'
},
{
'ID': 15,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MUCHACHA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GIRL'
},
{
'ID': 16,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BUENO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GOOD'
},
{
'ID': 17,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CASA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HOUSE'
},
{
'ID': 18,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NOMBRE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NAME'
},
{
'ID': 19,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BOLÍGRAFO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PEN'
},
{
'ID': 20,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LÁPIZ',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PENCIL'
},
{
'ID': 21,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TELÉFONO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PHONE'
},
{
'ID': 22,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PEQUEÑO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SMALL'
},
{
'ID': 23,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESTACIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'STATION'
},
{
'ID': 24,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CALLE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'STREET'
},
{
'ID': 25,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'APARCAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO PARK'
},
{
'ID': 26,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'APARTAMENTO,PISO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'APARTMENT'
},
{
'ID': 27,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CERVEZA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BEER'
},
{
'ID': 28,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BOTELLA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BOTTLE'
},
{
'ID': 29,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MARRÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BROWN'
},
{
'ID': 30,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CALENDARIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CALENDAR'
},
{
'ID': 31,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RELOJ (DE MESA O PARED)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CLOCK'
},
{
'ID': 32,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PAÍS,CAMPO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'COUNTRY'
},
{
'ID': 33,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MESA DE TRABAJO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DESK'
},
{
'ID': 34,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PUERTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DOOR'
},
{
'ID': 35,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FRANCIA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FRANCE'
},
{
'ID': 36,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FRANCÉS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FRENCH'
},
{
'ID': 37,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SOMBRERO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HAT'
},
{
'ID': 38,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ITALIA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ITALY'
},
{
'ID': 39,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'IDIOMA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LANGUAGE'
},
{
'ID': 40,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LECCIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LESSON'
},
{
'ID': 41,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PERIÓDICO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NEWSPAPER'
},
{
'ID': 42,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NUMERO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NUMBER'
},
{
'ID': 43,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'OFICINA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'OFFICE'
},
{
'ID': 44,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PAPEL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PAPER'
},
{
'ID': 45,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CUADRO,FOTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PICTURE'
},
{
'ID': 46,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ALUMNO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'STUDENT'
},
{
'ID': 47,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AZÚCAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SUGAR'
},
{
'ID': 48,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MESA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TABLE'
},
{
'ID': 49,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESE,ESO,AQUEL,AQUELLO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THAT'
},
{
'ID': 50,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESTE,ESTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THIS'
},
{
'ID': 51,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AEROPUERTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AIRPORT'
},
{
'ID': 52,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONTESTACIÓN,RESPUESTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ANSWER'
},
{
'ID': 53,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CAMA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BED'
},
{
'ID': 54,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CAJA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BOX'
},
{
'ID': 55,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CIGARRILLO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CIGARETTE'
},
{
'ID': 56,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CORRECTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CORRECT'
},
{
'ID': 57,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TAZA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CUP'
},
{
'ID': 58,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DICIEMBRE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DECEMBER'
},
{
'ID': 59,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VESTIDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DRESS'
},
{
'ID': 60,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FÁCIL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EASY'
},
{
'ID': 61,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FAMILIA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FAMILY'
},
{
'ID': 62,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ADIÓS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GOODBYE'
},
{
'ID': 63,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VERDE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GREEN'
},
{
'ID': 64,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AQUÍ',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HERE'
},
{
'ID': 65,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CABALLO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HORSE'
},
{
'ID': 66,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MARIDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HUSBAND'
},
{
'ID': 67,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ITALIANO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ITALIAN'
},
{
'ID': 68,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LARGO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LONG'
},
{
'ID': 69,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HOMBRE,SEÑOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MAN'
},
{
'ID': 70,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CUADERNO,BLOC',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NOTEBOOK'
},
{
'ID': 71,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PLATO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PLATE'
},
{
'ID': 72,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BONITO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PRETTY'
},
{
'ID': 73,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RÍO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RIVER'
},
{
'ID': 74,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESCUELA,COLEGIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SCHOOL'
},
{
'ID': 75,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BARCO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SHIP'
},
{
'ID': 76,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'UNA NECESIDAD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'A NEED'
},
{
'ID': 77,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TARDE (DESPUÉS DE MEDIODÍA)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AFTERNOON'
},
{
'ID': 78,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DORMITORIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BEDROOM'
},
{
'ID': 79,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PÁJARO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BIRD'
},
{
'ID': 80,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LIMPIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CLEAN'
},
{
'ID': 81,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CAFÉ',
        'RESPUESTA': 'COFFEE'
},
{
'ID': 82,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ALEMÁN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GERMAN'
},
{
'ID': 83,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BOLSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HANDBAG'
},
{
'ID': 84,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DEBERES (DE CLASE)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HOMEWORK'
},
{
'ID': 85,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CALUROSO,CALIENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HOT'
},
{
'ID': 86,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HORA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HOUR'
},
{
'ID': 87,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DELANTE DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IN FRONT OF'
},
{
'ID': 88,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'REVISTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MAGAZINE'
},
{
'ID': 89,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MAPA,PLANO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MAP'
},
{
'ID': 90,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESTRECHO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NARROW'
},
{
'ID': 91,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NUEVO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NEW'
},
{
'ID': 92,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AL LADO DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NEXT TO'
},
{
'ID': 93,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AGRADABLE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NICE'
},
{
'ID': 94,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SECRETARIA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SECRETARY'
},
{
'ID': 95,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TIENDA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SHOP'
},
{
'ID': 96,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CORTO,BAJO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SHORT'
},
{
'ID': 97,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HERMANA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SISTER'
},
{
'ID': 98,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LENTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SLOW'
},
{
'ID': 99,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FUERTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'STRONG'
},
{
'ID': 100,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TREN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TRAIN'
},
{
'ID': 101,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BRAZO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ARM'
},
{
'ID': 102,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BANCO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BANK'
},
{
'ID': 103,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'JEFE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BOSS'
},
{
'ID': 104,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NIÑOS,HIJOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CHILDREN'
},
{
'ID': 105,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AULA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CLASSROOM'
},
{
'ID': 106,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ABRIGO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'COAT'
},
{
'ID': 107,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FLOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FLOWER'
},
{
'ID': 108,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ALEMANIA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GERMANY'
},
{
'ID': 109,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'IDEA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IDEA'
},
{
'ID': 110,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENERO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'JANUARY'
},
{
'ID': 111,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LUZ',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LIGHT'
},
{
'ID': 112,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MINUTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MINUTE'
},
{
'ID': 113,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ERROR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MISTAKE'
},
{
'ID': 114,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MONTAÑA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MOUNTAIN'
},
{
'ID': 115,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BOCA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MOUTH'
},
{
'ID': 116,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PLANTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PLANT'
},
{
'ID': 117,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SILENCIOSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'QUIET'
},
{
'ID': 118,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ROJO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RED'
},
{
'ID': 119,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HABITACIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ROOM'
},
{
'ID': 120,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CANSADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TIRED'
},
{
'ID': 121,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DEBAJO DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'UNDER'
},
{
'ID': 122,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MUY',
        'RESPUESTA': 'VERY'
},
{
'ID': 123,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CAMARERO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WAITER'
},
{
'ID': 124,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PARED,MURO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WALL'
},
{
'ID': 125,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AGUA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WATER'
},
{
'ID': 126,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENTRE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AMONG'
},
{
'ID': 127,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENFADADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ANGRY'
},
{
'ID': 128,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESAYUNO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BREAKFAST'
},
{
'ID': 129,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FRÍO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'COLD'
},
{
'ID': 130,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PADRE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FATHER'
},
{
'ID': 131,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PEZ,PESCADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FISH'
},
{
'ID': 132,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BOSQUE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FOREST'
},
{
'ID': 133,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FRUTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FRUIT'
},
{
'ID': 134,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PELO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HAIR'
},
{
'ID': 135,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DURO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HARD'
},
{
'ID': 136,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CABEZA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HEAD'
},
{
'ID': 137,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'JULIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'JULY'
},
{
'ID': 138,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LÁMPARA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LAMP'
},
{
'ID': 139,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'IZQUIERDA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LEFT'
},
{
'ID': 140,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MERCADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MARKET'
},
{
'ID': 141,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MADRE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MOTHER'
},
{
'ID': 142,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RUIDOSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NOISY'
},
{
'ID': 143,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PLANTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PLANT'
},
{
'ID': 144,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PREGUNTA,CUESTIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'QUESTION'
},
{
'ID': 145,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENFERMO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SICK'
},
{
'ID': 146,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HIJO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SON'
},
{
'ID': 147,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ALTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TALL'
},
{
'ID': 148,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PROFESOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TEACHER'
},
{
'ID': 149,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TELÉFONO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TELEPHONE'
},
{
'ID': 150,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RELOJ (DE PULSERA)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WATCH'
},
{
'ID': 151,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'OTRO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ANOTHER'
},
{
'ID': 152,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ARTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ART'
},
{
'ID': 153,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EDIFICIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BUILDING'
},
{
'ID': 154,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PERO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BUT'
},
{
'ID': 155,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'IGLESIA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CHURCH'
},
{
'ID': 156,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'OSCURO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DARK'
},
{
'ID': 157,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EJEMPLO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EXAMPLE'
},
{
'ID': 158,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ARCHIVO,EXPEDIENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FILE'
},
{
'ID': 159,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SUELO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FLOOR'
},
{
'ID': 160,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VIERNES',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FRIDAY'
},
{
'ID': 161,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'JAMÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HAM'
},
{
'ID': 162,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HAMBRIENTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HUNGRY'
},
{
'ID': 163,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LLAVE,CLAVE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'KEY'
},
{
'ID': 164,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MAQUINA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MACHINE'
},
{
'ID': 165,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CERCA DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NEAR'
},
{
'ID': 166,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NECESARIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NECESSARY'
},
{
'ID': 167,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PERSONA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PERSON'
},
{
'ID': 168,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'POBRE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'POOR'
},
{
'ID': 169,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PROBLEMA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PROBLEM'
},
{
'ID': 170,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RADIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RADIO'
},
{
'ID': 171,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LISTO,PREPARADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'READY'
},
{
'ID': 172,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SIMILAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SIMILAR'
},
{
'ID': 173,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MUJER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WOMAN'
},
{
'ID': 174,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AÑO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'YEAR'
},
{
'ID': 175,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'JOVEN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'YOUNG'
},
{
'ID': 176,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'A CERCA DE,SOBRE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ABOUT'
},
{
'ID': 177,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SEÑAS,DIRECCIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ADDRESS'
},
{
'ID': 178,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TARDE (DESPUÉS DE MEDIODÍA)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AFTERNOON'
},
{
'ID': 179,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DETRÁS DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BEHIND'
},
{
'ID': 180,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENTRE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BETWEEN'
},
{
'ID': 181,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BARATO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CHEAP'
},
{
'ID': 182,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DIFÍCIL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DIFFICULT'
},
{
'ID': 183,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SUCIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DIRTY'
},
{
'ID': 184,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'JUEGO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GAME'
},
{
'ID': 185,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GUANTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GLOVE'
},
{
'ID': 186,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DIA FESTIVO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HOLYDAY'
},
{
'ID': 187,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'IMPORTANTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IMPORTANT'
},
{
'ID': 188,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'JAPÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'JAPAN'
},
{
'ID': 189,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CLASE,TIPO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'KIND'
},
{
'ID': 190,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LIMÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LEMON'
},
{
'ID': 191,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LEÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LION'
},
{
'ID': 192,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SALÓN,CUARTO DE ESTAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LIVING ROOM'
},
{
'ID': 193,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NARIZ',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NOSE'
},
{
'ID': 194,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PADRES',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PARENTS'
},
{
'ID': 195,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CERDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PIG'
},
{
'ID': 196,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'POSIBLE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'POSSIBLE'
},
{
'ID': 197,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PROGRAMA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PROGRAM'
},
{
'ID': 198,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RATA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RAT'
},
{
'ID': 199,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DE VERDAD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'REALLY'
},
{
'ID': 200,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INFORME',
        'RESPUESTA': 'REPORT'
},
{
'ID': 201,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ALREDEDOR DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AROUND'
},
{
'ID': 202,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PAN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BREAD'
},
{
'ID': 203,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TECHO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CEILING'
},
{
'ID': 204,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ORDENADOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'COMPUTER'
},
{
'ID': 205,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DIA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DAY'
},
{
'ID': 206,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SECO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DRY'
},
{
'ID': 207,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EUROPA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EUROPE'
},
{
'ID': 208,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RÁPIDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FAST'
},
{
'ID': 209,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PASILLO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HALL'
},
{
'ID': 210,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'REUNIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MEETING'
},
{
'ID': 211,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DINERO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MONEY'
},
{
'ID': 212,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MES',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MONTH'
},
{
'ID': 213,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MÚSICA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MUSIC'
},
{
'ID': 214,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NERVIOSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NERVOUS'
},
{
'ID': 215,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RUIDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NOISE'
},
{
'ID': 216,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FIESTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PARTY'
},
{
'ID': 217,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PEOPLE'
},
{
'ID': 218,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BOLSILLO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'POCKET'
},
{
'ID': 219,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PUERTO (DE MAR)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PORT'
},
{
'ID': 220,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PROGRESO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PROGRESS'
},
{
'ID': 221,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HISTORIA,CUENTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'STORY'
},
{
'ID': 222,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SEMANA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WEEK'
},
{
'ID': 223,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BIEN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WELL'
},
{
'ID': 224,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ANCHO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WIDE'
},
{
'ID': 225,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VENTANA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WINDOW'
},
{
'ID': 226,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HERMOSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BEAUTIFUL'
},
{
'ID': 227,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AUTOBÚS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BUS'
},
{
'ID': 228,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PELIGROSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DANGEROUS'
},
{
'ID': 229,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FECHA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DATE'
},
{
'ID': 230,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DIBUJO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DRAWING'
},
{
'ID': 231,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GORDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FAT'
},
{
'ID': 232,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FEBRERO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FEBRUARY'
},
{
'ID': 233,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PRIMERO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FIRST'
},
{
'ID': 234,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VASO,VIDRIO,CRISTAL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GLASS'
},
{
'ID': 235,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EMPLEO,TRABAJO,TAREA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'JOB'
},
{
'ID': 236,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TARDE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LATE'
},
{
'ID': 237,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LÍNEA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LINE'
},
{
'ID': 238,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AFORTUNADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LUCKY'
},
{
'ID': 239,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PARQUE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PARK'
},
{
'ID': 240,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LLAMADA TELEFÓNICA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PHONE CALL'
},
{
'ID': 241,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AVIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PLANE'
},
{
'ID': 242,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PROFESIONAL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PROFESSION'
},
{
'ID': 243,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RICO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RICH'
},
{
'ID': 244,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FRASE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SENTENCE'
},
{
'ID': 245,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SISTEMA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SYSTEM'
},
{
'ID': 246,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ÁRBOL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TREE'
},
{
'ID': 247,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'POR QUÉ?',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WHY?'
},
{
'ID': 248,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESPOSA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WIFE'
},
{
'ID': 249,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VINO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WINE'
},
{
'ID': 250,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CON',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WITH'
},
{
'ID': 251,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MUCHO,MUCHOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'A LOT OF'
},
{
'ID': 252,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ÁREA,ZONA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AREA'
},
{
'ID': 253,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PRINCIPIANTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BEGINNER'
},
{
'ID': 254,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RUBIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BLOND'
},
{
'ID': 255,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LIBRERÍA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BOOK SHOP'
},
{
'ID': 256,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MANTEQUILLA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BUTTER'
},
{
'ID': 257,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'QUESO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CHEESE'
},
{
'ID': 258,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CLARO,TRANSPARENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CLEAR'
},
{
'ID': 259,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VACA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'COW'
},
{
'ID': 260,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HIJA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DAUGHTER'
},
{
'ID': 261,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DIFERENTE,DISTINTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DIFFERENT'
},
{
'ID': 262,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ABAJO,HACIA ABAJO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DOWN'
},
{
'ID': 263,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EAST'
},
{
'ID': 264,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ELEFANTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ELEPHANT'
},
{
'ID': 265,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'OJO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EYE'
},
{
'ID': 266,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INCENDIO,FUEGO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FIRE'
},
{
'ID': 267,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NIEBLA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FOG'
},
{
'ID': 268,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AMIGO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FRIEND'
},
{
'ID': 269,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GARAJE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GARAGE'
},
{
'ID': 270,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PEQUEÑO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LITTLE'
},
{
'ID': 271,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LECHE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MILK'
},
{
'ID': 272,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PAGINA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PAGE'
},
{
'ID': 273,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PRECIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PRICE'
},
{
'ID': 274,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TEMA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SUBJECT'
},
{
'ID': 275,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GRUESO,ESPESO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THICK'
},
{
'ID': 276,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ACCIDENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ACCIDENT'
},
{
'ID': 277,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TODO,TODOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ALL'
},
{
'ID': 278,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EN CASA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AT HOME'
},
{
'ID': 279,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HERMANO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BROTHER'
},
{
'ID': 280,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VIAJE DE NEGOCIOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BUSINESS TRIP'
},
{
'ID': 281,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ROPA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CLOSE'
},
{
'ID': 282,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ALGODÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'COTTON'
},
{
'ID': 283,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COMEDOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DINING ROOM'
},
{
'ID': 284,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'OÍDO,OREJA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EAR'
},
{
'ID': 285,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CADA,TODOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EVERY'
},
{
'ID': 286,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CARA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FACE'
},
{
'ID': 287,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PIE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FOOT'
},
{
'ID': 288,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MANO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HAND'
},
{
'ID': 289,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ALTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HIGH'
},
{
'ID': 290,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HOTEL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HOTEL'
},
{
'ID': 291,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CUANTOS?',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HOW MANY?'
},
{
'ID': 292,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CUANTO?',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HOW MUCH?'
},
{
'ID': 293,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LA INDIA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'INDIA'
},
{
'ID': 294,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MUCHOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MANY'
},
{
'ID': 295,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CARNE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MEAT'
},
{
'ID': 296,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PELÍCULA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MOVIE'
},
{
'ID': 297,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CAMINO,CARRETERA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ROAD'
},
{
'ID': 298,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NIEVE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SNOW'
},
{
'ID': 299,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SOPA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SOUP'
},
{
'ID': 300,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SORPRESA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SURPRISE'
},
{
'ID': 301,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'OTRA VEZ',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AGAIN'
},
{
'ID': 302,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PLAYA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BEACH'
},
{
'ID': 303,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TIMBRE,CAMPANA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BELL'
},
{
'ID': 304,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BOTE,BARCA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BOAT'
},
{
'ID': 305,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AMBOS,LOS DOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BOTH'
},
{
'ID': 306,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TARTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CAKE'
},
{
'ID': 307,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EMPRESA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'COMPANY'
},
{
'ID': 308,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RINCÓN,ESQUINA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CORNER'
},
{
'ID': 309,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TARDE (DESPUÉS DEL OSCURECER)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EVENING'
},
{
'ID': 310,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DEDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FINGER'
},
{
'ID': 311,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MUEBLES',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FURNITURE'
},
{
'ID': 312,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ABUELOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GRANDPARENTS'
},
{
'ID': 313,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GRECIA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GREECE'
},
{
'ID': 314,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FELIZ,CONTENTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HAPPY'
},
{
'ID': 315,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PESADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HEAVY'
},
{
'ID': 316,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CASA,HOGAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HOME'
},
{
'ID': 317,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ULTIMO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LAST'
},
{
'ID': 318,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CARTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LETTER'
},
{
'ID': 319,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ALMUERZO,COMIDA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LUNCH'
},
{
'ID': 320,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AHORA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NOW'
},
{
'ID': 321,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PATATA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'POTATO'
},
{
'ID': 322,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'REDONDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ROUND'
},
{
'ID': 323,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VARIOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SEVERAL'
},
{
'ID': 324,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ZAPATOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SHOES'
},
{
'ID': 325,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BLANDO,SUAVE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SOFT'
},
{
'ID': 326,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BOLSA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BAG'
},
{
'ID': 327,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CUARTO DE BAÑO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BATHROOM'
},
{
'ID': 328,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HOMBRE DE NEGOCIOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BUSINESS MAN'
},
{
'ID': 329,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CENA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DINNER'
},
{
'ID': 330,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TEMPRANO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EARLY'
},
{
'ID': 331,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FABRICA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FACTORY'
},
{
'ID': 332,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LEJOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FAR'
},
{
'ID': 333,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PIES',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FEET'
},
{
'ID': 334,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PLANO,LLANO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FLAT'
},
{
'ID': 335,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COMIDA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FOOD'
},
{
'ID': 336,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LIBRE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FREE'
},
{
'ID': 337,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HOSPITAL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HOSPITAL'
},
{
'ID': 338,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MÁS TARDE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LATER'
},
{
'ID': 339,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NOCHE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NIGHT'
},
{
'ID': 340,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CARTERO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'POSTMAN'
},
{
'ID': 341,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RESULTADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RESULT'
},
{
'ID': 342,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AHORA MISMO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RIGHT NOW'
},
{
'ID': 343,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SUELDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SALARY'
},
{
'ID': 344,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EXTRAÑO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'STRANGE'
},
{
'ID': 345,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LA POLICÍA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THE POLICE'
},
{
'ID': 346,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TIEMPO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TIME'
},
{
'ID': 347,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HOY',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TODAY'
},
{
'ID': 348,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MAÑANA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TOMORROW'
},
{
'ID': 349,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INVIERNO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WINTER'
},
{
'ID': 350,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EQUIVOCADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WRONG'
},
{
'ID': 351,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'POR ENCIMA DE,SOBRE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ABOVE'
},
{
'ID': 352,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ACCIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ACTION'
},
{
'ID': 353,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TAMBIÉN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ALSO'
},
{
'ID': 354,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PORQUE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BECAUSE'
},
{
'ID': 355,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FRONTERA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BORDER'
},
{
'ID': 356,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PUENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BRIDGE'
},
{
'ID': 357,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ROTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BROKEN'
},
{
'ID': 358,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CADA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EACH'
},
{
'ID': 359,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ECONOMÍA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ECONOMY'
},
{
'ID': 360,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TODOS LOS DÍAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EVERYDAY'
},
{
'ID': 361,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EXCEPTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EXCEPT'
},
{
'ID': 362,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'POR EJEMPLO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FOR EXAMPLE'
},
{
'ID': 363,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'JARDÍN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GARDEN'
},
{
'ID': 364,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GRUPO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GROUP'
},
{
'ID': 365,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INMEDIATAMENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IMMEDIATELY'
},
{
'ID': 366,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MÉTODO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'METHOD'
},
{
'ID': 367,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PARTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PART'
},
{
'ID': 368,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LUGAR,SITIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PLACE'
},
{
'ID': 369,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CAMISA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SHIRT'
},
{
'ID': 370,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ALGUNOS,ALGO DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SOME'
},
{
'ID': 371,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VERANO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SUMMER'
},
{
'ID': 372,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LA PARTE SUPERIOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THE TOP'
},
{
'ID': 373,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FUMAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SMOKE'
},
{
'ID': 374,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'URGENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'URGENT'
},
{
'ID': 375,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ÚTIL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'USEFUL'
},
{
'ID': 376,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EDAD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AGE'
},
{
'ID': 377,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LO ANTES POSIBLE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AS SOON AS POSSIBLE'
},
{
'ID': 378,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AYUDANTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ASSISTANT'
},
{
'ID': 379,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESPALDA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BACK'
},
{
'ID': 380,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TRANQUILO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CALM'
},
{
'ID': 381,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COMÚN,CORRIENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'COMMON'
},
{
'ID': 382,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESFUERZO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EFFORT'
},
{
'ID': 383,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EVALUACIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EVALUATION'
},
{
'ID': 384,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AFORTUNADAMENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FORTUNATELY'
},
{
'ID': 385,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GENEROSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GENEROUS'
},
{
'ID': 386,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'POR LA TARDE (DESPUÉS DEL OSCURECER)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IN THE EVENING'
},
{
'ID': 387,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DENTRO,DENTRO DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'INSIDE'
},
{
'ID': 388,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INTERESANTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'INTERESTING'
},
{
'ID': 389,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PUNTO DE VISTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'POINT OF VIEW'
},
{
'ID': 390,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TAMAÑO,TALLA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SIZE'
},
{
'ID': 391,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ALLÍ,AHÍ',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THERE'
},
{
'ID': 392,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESTOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THESE'
},
{
'ID': 393,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COSA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THING'
},
{
'ID': 394,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AQUELLOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THOSE'
},
{
'ID': 395,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VENIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO COME'
},
{
'ID': 396,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BEBER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO DRINK'
},
{
'ID': 397,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TENER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO HAVE'
},
{
'ID': 398,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'APRENDER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO LEARN'
},
{
'ID': 399,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'APRECIAR,GUSTARLE A UNO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO LIKE'
},
{
'ID': 400,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MIRAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO LOOK AT'
},
{
'ID': 401,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CUALQUIERA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ANYONE'
},
{
'ID': 402,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CESTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BASKET'
},
{
'ID': 403,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CUERPO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BODY'
},
{
'ID': 404,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TORO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BULL'
},
{
'ID': 405,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COMPLETAMENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'COMPLETELY'
},
{
'ID': 406,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DICCIONARIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DICTIONARY'
},
{
'ID': 407,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ERROR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ERROR'
},
{
'ID': 408,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CARO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EXPENSIVE'
},
{
'ID': 409,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EXPLOTACIÓN AGRÍCOLA,GRANJA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FARM'
},
{
'ID': 410,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'REGALO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GIFT'
},
{
'ID': 411,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ABUELO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GRANDFATHER'
},
{
'ID': 412,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SANO,SALUDABLE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HEALTHY'
},
{
'ID': 413,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': '¿CÓMO SE DICE...?',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HOW DO YOU SAY...?'
},
{
'ID': 414,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENFERMO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ILL'
},
{
'ID': 415,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DA IGUAL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IT DOESN\'T MATTER'
},
{
'ID': 416,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PRACTICO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PRACTICAL'
},
{
'ID': 417,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PROBABLEMENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PROBABLY'
},
{
'ID': 418,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RÁPIDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'QUICK'
},
{
'ID': 419,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RUTINA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ROUTINE'
},
{
'ID': 420,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TRAJE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SUIT'
},
{
'ID': 421,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LLAMAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO CALL'
},
{
'ID': 422,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CERRAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO CLOSE'
},
{
'ID': 423,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESCUCHAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO LISTEN TO'
},
{
'ID': 424,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BUSCAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO LOOK FOR'
},
{
'ID': 425,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'JUGAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO PLAY'
},
{
'ID': 426,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ACUERDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AGREEMENT'
},
{
'ID': 427,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VALE,DE ACUERDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ALL RIGHT'
},
{
'ID': 428,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SIEMPRE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ALWAYS'
},
{
'ID': 429,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CUANDO QUIERAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ANYTIME'
},
{
'ID': 430,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DURACIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DURATION'
},
{
'ID': 431,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SOBRE TODO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SPECIALLY'
},
{
'ID': 432,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EXACTAMENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EXACTLY'
},
{
'ID': 433,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DE VEZ EN CUANDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FROM TIME TO TIME'
},
{
'ID': 434,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MEDIA HORA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HALF AN HOUR'
},
{
'ID': 435,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CERILLA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MATCH'
},
{
'ID': 436,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NOTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NOTE'
},
{
'ID': 437,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NADA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NOTHING'
},
{
'ID': 438,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PAGO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PAYMENT'
},
{
'ID': 439,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FOTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PHOTO'
},
{
'ID': 440,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DE COLOR ROSA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PINK'
},
{
'ID': 441,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESPECIFICO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SPECIFIC'
},
{
'ID': 442,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TODAVÍA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'STILL'
},
{
'ID': 443,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EQUIPO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TEAM'
},
{
'ID': 444,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EL SOL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THE SUN'
},
{
'ID': 445,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PREGUNTAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ASK'
},
{
'ID': 446,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONDUCIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO DRIVE'
},
{
'ID': 447,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COMER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO EAT'
},
{
'ID': 448,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AYUDAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO HELP'
},
{
'ID': 449,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SABER,CONOCER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO KNOW'
},
{
'ID': 450,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MOJADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WET'
},
{
'ID': 451,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ATENCIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ATTENTION'
},
{
'ID': 452,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ANTES,ANTES DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BEFORE'
},
{
'ID': 453,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DIARIO,DIARIAMENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DAILY'
},
{
'ID': 454,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DECISIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DECISION'
},
{
'ID': 455,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MITAD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HALF'
},
{
'ID': 456,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'A FAVOR DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IN FAVOUR OF'
},
{
'ID': 457,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VAMONOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LET\'S GO'
},
{
'ID': 458,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TODAVÍA NO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NOT YET'
},
{
'ID': 459,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'A MENUDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'OFTEN'
},
{
'ID': 460,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RAZÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'REASON'
},
{
'ID': 461,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ROSA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ROSE'
},
{
'ID': 462,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SERVICIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SERVICE'
},
{
'ID': 463,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESPECTÁCULO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SHOW'
},
{
'ID': 464,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SIDE'
},
{
'ID': 465,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EL MAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THE SEA'
},
{
'ID': 466,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONTESTAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ANSWER'
},
{
'ID': 467,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COMPRAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BUY'
},
{
'ID': 468,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COSTAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO COST'
},
{
'ID': 469,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DIBUJAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO DRAW'
},
{
'ID': 470,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENCONTRAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO FIND'
},
{
'ID': 471,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'OCURRIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO HAPPEN'
},
{
'ID': 472,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'OÍR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO EAR'
},
{
'ID': 473,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VIVIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO LIVE'
},
{
'ID': 474,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MOVERSE,MUDARSE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO MOVE'
},
{
'ID': 475,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LEER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO READ'
},
{
'ID': 476,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CASI',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ALMOST'
},
{
'ID': 477,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'A LO LARGO DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ALONG'
},
{
'ID': 478,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'POR DEBAJO DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BELOW'
},
{
'ID': 479,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DENTISTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DENTIST'
},
{
'ID': 480,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TAMPOCO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EITHER'
},
{
'ID': 481,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VACÍO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EMPTY'
},
{
'ID': 482,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENORME',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ENORMOUS'
},
{
'ID': 483,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESENCIAL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ESSENTIAL'
},
{
'ID': 484,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TODO EL MUNDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EVERYBODY'
},
{
'ID': 485,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FUTURO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FUTURE'
},
{
'ID': 486,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MAS O MENOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MORE OR LESS'
},
{
'ID': 487,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CASI',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NEARLY'
},
{
'ID': 488,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NORTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NORTH'
},
{
'ID': 489,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'OFICINA DE CORREOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'POST OFFICE'
},
{
'ID': 490,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CALIDAD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'QUALITY'
},
{
'ID': 491,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CIELO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SKY'
},
{
'ID': 492,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CANCIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SONG'
},
{
'ID': 493,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SONIDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SOUND'
},
{
'ID': 494,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SUR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SOUTH'
},
{
'ID': 495,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PRIMAVERA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SPRING'
},
{
'ID': 496,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ASISTIR A',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ATTEND'
},
{
'ID': 497,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ROMPER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BREAK'
},
{
'ID': 498,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONTAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO COUNT'
},
{
'ID': 499,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DAR,ENTREGAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO GIVE'
},
{
'ID': 500,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RECIBIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO RECEIVE'
},
{
'ID': 501,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SOLO,EN SOLITARIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ALONE'
},
{
'ID': 502,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ARTÍCULO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ARTICLE'
},
{
'ID': 503,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'POR LO MENOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AT LEAST'
},
{
'ID': 504,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AL LADO DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BESIDE'
},
{
'ID': 505,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CÁMARA FOTOGRÁFICA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CAMERA'
},
{
'ID': 506,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DISCULPE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EXCUSE ME'
},
{
'ID': 507,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FINALMENTE,POR ÚLTIMO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FINALLY'
},
{
'ID': 508,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LLENO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FULL'
},
{
'ID': 509,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'UBICACIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LOCATION'
},
{
'ID': 510,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'OFICIAL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'OFFICIAL'
},
{
'ID': 511,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LLUVIA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RAIN'
},
{
'ID': 512,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SEGUNDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SECOND'
},
{
'ID': 513,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESPUÉS,ENTONCES',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THEN'
},
{
'ID': 514,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CREER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BELIEVE'
},
{
'ID': 515,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CUBRIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO COVER'
},
{
'ID': 516,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CORTAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO CUT'
},
{
'ID': 517,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SENTIR,PENSAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO FEEL'
},
{
'ID': 518,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONSEGUIR,OBTENER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO GET'
},
{
'ID': 519,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NECESITAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO NEED'
},
{
'ID': 520,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PRODUCIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO PRODUCE'
},
{
'ID': 521,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CERRAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SHUT'
},
{
'ID': 522,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GASTAR,PASAR (TIEMPO)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SPEND'
},
{
'ID': 523,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESTUDIAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO STUDY'
},
{
'ID': 524,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HABLAR,CHARLAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO TALK'
},
{
'ID': 525,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LLEVAR PUESTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO WEAR'
},
{
'ID': 526,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CUALQUIER COSA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ANYTHING'
},
{
'ID': 527,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'APARTE DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'APART FROM'
},
{
'ID': 528,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ACTITUD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ATTITUDE'
},
{
'ID': 529,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CINTURÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BELT'
},
{
'ID': 530,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LIBRERÍA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BOOKSTORE'
},
{
'ID': 531,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CASO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CASE'
},
{
'ID': 532,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'POLLO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CHICKEN'
},
{
'ID': 533,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CHINO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CHINESE'
},
{
'ID': 534,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VENGA,VAMOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'COME ON!'
},
{
'ID': 535,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MUERTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DEAD'
},
{
'ID': 536,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SUFICIENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ENOUGH'
},
{
'ID': 537,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DATE PRISA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HURRY UP!'
},
{
'ID': 538,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INCOMPLETO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'INCOMPLETE'
},
{
'ID': 539,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TAL VEZ',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MAYBE'
},
{
'ID': 540,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PROPUESTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PROPOSAL'
},
{
'ID': 541,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VENTAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SALES'
},
{
'ID': 542,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ÉXITO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SUCCESS'
},
{
'ID': 543,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AÑADIR,SUMAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ADD'
},
{
'ID': 544,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PEDIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ASK FOR'
},
{
'ID': 545,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TENER PRISA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BE IN A HURRY'
},
{
'ID': 546,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DEPENDER DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO DEPEND ON'
},
{
'ID': 547,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LLENAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO FILL'
},
{
'ID': 548,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'OFRECER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO OFFER'
},
{
'ID': 549,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PREFERIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO PREFER'
},
{
'ID': 550,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TRABAJAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO WORK'
},
{
'ID': 551,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DISCUSIÓN (ACALORADA)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ARGUMENT'
},
{
'ID': 552,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ASISTENCIA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ATTENDANCE'
},
{
'ID': 553,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'OCUPADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BUSY'
},
{
'ID': 554,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CLIMA,AMBIENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CLIMATE'
},
{
'ID': 555,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LOCO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CRAZY'
},
{
'ID': 556,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'META',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GOAL'
},
{
'ID': 557,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DE HECHO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IN FACT'
},
{
'ID': 558,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MEMORIA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MEMORY'
},
{
'ID': 559,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'JAMÁS,NUNCA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NEVER'
},
{
'ID': 560,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HORARIO,PROGRAMA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SCHEDULE'
},
{
'ID': 561,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PANTALLA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SCREEN'
},
{
'ID': 562,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EL TIEMPO (ATMOSFÉRICO)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THE WEATHER'
},
{
'ID': 563,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'A TRAVÉS DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THROUGH'
},
{
'ID': 564,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONSTRUIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BUILD'
},
{
'ID': 565,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EXIGIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO DEMAND'
},
{
'ID': 566,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENFADARSE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO GET ANGRY'
},
{
'ID': 567,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESCANSAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO REST'
},
{
'ID': 568,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CORRER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO RUN'
},
{
'ID': 569,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SONREÍR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SMILE'
},
{
'ID': 570,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PENSAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO THINK'
},
{
'ID': 571,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INTENTAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO TRY TO'
},
{
'ID': 572,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PUEBLO,CIUDAD PEQUEÑA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TOWN'
},
{
'ID': 573,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MODO,FORMA,MANERA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WAY'
},
{
'ID': 574,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FIN DE SEMANA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WEEKEND'
},
{
'ID': 575,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PALABRA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WORD'
},
{
'ID': 576,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'YA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ALREADY'
},
{
'ID': 577,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CUMPLEAÑOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BIRTHDAY'
},
{
'ID': 578,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CUIDADOSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CAREFULLY'
},
{
'ID': 579,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HUEVO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EGG'
},
{
'ID': 580,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EUROPEO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EUROPEAN'
},
{
'ID': 581,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PELÍCULA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FILM'
},
{
'ID': 582,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GRACIOSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FUNNY'
},
{
'ID': 583,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CUANTO...?',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HOW MUCH...?'
},
{
'ID': 584,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EN GENERAL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IN GENERAL'
},
{
'ID': 585,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PIERNA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LEG'
},
{
'ID': 586,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MENSAJE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MESSAGE'
},
{
'ID': 587,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PRÓXIMO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NEXT'
},
{
'ID': 588,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PROPÓSITO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PURPOSE'
},
{
'ID': 589,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TRISTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SAD'
},
{
'ID': 590,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RECTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'STRAIGHT'
},
{
'ID': 591,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EL MISMO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THE SAME'
},
{
'ID': 592,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COMENZAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BEGINNING'
},
{
'ID': 593,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONTINUAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO CONTINUE'
},
{
'ID': 594,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESCRIBIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO DESCRIBE'
},
{
'ID': 595,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESPERAR,PREVER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO EXPECT'
},
{
'ID': 596,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EXPLICAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO EXPLAIN'
},
{
'ID': 597,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PREPARAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO PREPARE'
},
{
'ID': 598,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SEE'
},
{
'ID': 599,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RESOLVER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SOLVE'
},
{
'ID': 600,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PONERSE DE PIE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO STAND UP'
},
{
'ID': 601,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CANTIDAD,IMPORTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AMOUNT'
},
{
'ID': 602,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CERCA DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CLOSE TO'
},
{
'ID': 603,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'REFERENTE A',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CONCERNING'
},
{
'ID': 604,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CORTINA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CURTAIN'
},
{
'ID': 605,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PROFUNDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DEEP'
},
{
'ID': 606,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DEPARTAMENTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DEPARTMENT'
},
{
'ID': 607,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EFICAZ',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EFFECTIVE'
},
{
'ID': 608,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TODO EL MUNDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EVERYONE'
},
{
'ID': 609,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EJERCICIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EXERCISE'
},
{
'ID': 610,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EXPERTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EXPERT'
},
{
'ID': 611,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NIETO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GRANDSON'
},
{
'ID': 612,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GRIEGO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GREECE'
},
{
'ID': 613,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CARRETERA,AUTOVIA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HIGHWAY'
},
{
'ID': 614,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESPERANZA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HOPE'
},
{
'ID': 615,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INFLACIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'INFLATION'
},
{
'ID': 616,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COMO,AL IGUAL QUE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LIKE'
},
{
'ID': 617,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PODER,POTENCIA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'POWER'
},
{
'ID': 618,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PRIORIDAD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PRIORITY'
},
{
'ID': 619,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LLEGAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ARRIVE'
},
{
'ID': 620,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'OLVIDAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO FORGET'
},
{
'ID': 621,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CRECER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO GROW'
},
{
'ID': 622,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AUMENTAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO INCREASE'
},
{
'ID': 623,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DURAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO LAST'
},
{
'ID': 624,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AMAR,QUERER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO LOVE'
},
{
'ID': 625,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EMPUJAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO PUSH'
},
{
'ID': 626,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'UNA OFERTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AN OFFER'
},
{
'ID': 627,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'OPORTUNIDAD,POSIBILIDAD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CHANCE'
},
{
'ID': 628,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DISTANCIA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DISTANCE'
},
{
'ID': 629,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GENERALMENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GENERALLY'
},
{
'ID': 630,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'REAL,AUTENTICO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'REAL'
},
{
'ID': 631,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SENCILLO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SIMPLE'
},
{
'ID': 632,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'QUEMAR,ARDER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BURN'
},
{
'ID': 633,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CAMBIAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO CHANGE'
},
{
'ID': 634,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DECIDIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO DECIDE'
},
{
'ID': 635,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DEFENDER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO DEFEND'
},
{
'ID': 636,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TERMINAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO FINISH'
},
{
'ID': 637,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VOLAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO FLY'
},
{
'ID': 638,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LLEGAR A',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO GET TO'
},
{
'ID': 639,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESPERAR (CON ILUSIÓN)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO HOPE'
},
{
'ID': 640,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MARCHARSE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO LEAVE'
},
{
'ID': 641,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PERDER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO LOSE'
},
{
'ID': 642,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PAGAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO PAY'
},
{
'ID': 643,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PROMETER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO PROMISE'
},
{
'ID': 644,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ALQUILAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO RENT'
},
{
'ID': 645,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'OLER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SMELL'
},
{
'ID': 646,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VISITAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO VISIT'
},
{
'ID': 647,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VACACIONES',
        'RESPUESTA': 'VACATIONS'
},
{
'ID': 648,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VERDURAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'VEGETABLES'
},
{
'ID': 649,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PUEBLO PEQUEÑO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'VILLAGE'
},
{
'ID': 650,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'VOCABULARY'
},
{
'ID': 651,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DE TODOS MODOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ANYWAY'
},
{
'ID': 652,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONSECUENCIAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CONSEQUENCES'
},
{
'ID': 653,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TODO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EVERYTHING'
},
{
'ID': 654,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EXCELENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EXCELLENT'
},
{
'ID': 655,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'JUSTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FAIR'
},
{
'ID': 656,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SIN EMBARGO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HOWEVER'
},
{
'ID': 657,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NADIE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NOBODY'
},
{
'ID': 658,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PROFESIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PROFESSION'
},
{
'ID': 659,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ALGÚN DIA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SOMEDAY'
},
{
'ID': 660,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ALGUIEN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SOMEONE'
},
{
'ID': 661,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TIENDA,ALMACÉN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'STORE'
},
{
'ID': 662,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SUPERMERCADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SUPERMARKET'
},
{
'ID': 663,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SEGURO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SURE'
},
{
'ID': 664,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DULCE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SWEET'
},
{
'ID': 665,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EL MUNDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THE WORLD'
},
{
'ID': 666,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ACEPTAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ACCEPT'
},
{
'ID': 667,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ATACAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ATTACK'
},
{
'ID': 668,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ATRAER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ATTRACT'
},
{
'ID': 669,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ELEGIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO CHOOSE'
},
{
'ID': 670,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COCINAR,COCER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO COOK'
},
{
'ID': 671,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SEGUIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO FOLLOW'
},
{
'ID': 672,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MEJORAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO IMPROVE'
},
{
'ID': 673,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INCLUIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO INCLUDE'
},
{
'ID': 674,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'JUBILARSE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO RETIRE'
},
{
'ID': 675,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PARAR,DETENER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO STOP'
},
{
'ID': 676,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CUALQUIERA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ANYBODY'
},
{
'ID': 677,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ADEMÁS,ADEMÁS DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BESIDES'
},
{
'ID': 678,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DEFECTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DEFECT'
},
{
'ID': 679,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CORAZÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HEART'
},
{
'ID': 680,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AGUJERO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HOLE'
},
{
'ID': 681,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONOCIMIENTOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'KNOWLEDGE'
},
{
'ID': 682,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TIERRA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LAND'
},
{
'ID': 683,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PUNTUAL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ON TIME'
},
{
'ID': 684,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'JUBILACIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RETIREMENT'
},
{
'ID': 685,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TEMPORADA,ESTACIÓN (DE AÑO)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SEASON'
},
{
'ID': 686,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DISCURSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SPEECH'
},
{
'ID': 687,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BILLETE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TICKET'
},
{
'ID': 688,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TENER SUERTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BE LUCKY'
},
{
'ID': 689,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COMPARAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO COMPARE'
},
{
'ID': 690,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MORIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO DIE'
},
{
'ID': 691,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GANAR (TRABAJANDO)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO EARN'
},
{
'ID': 692,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CAER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO FALL'
},
{
'ID': 693,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONOCER POR VEZ PRIMERA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO MEET'
},
{
'ID': 694,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TIRAR (CONTRARIO DE EMPUJAR)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO PULL'
},
{
'ID': 695,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RECOMENDAR TO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RECOMMEND'
},
{
'ID': 696,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'REVISAR,REPASAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO REVIEW'
},
{
'ID': 697,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VIAJAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO TRAVEL'
},
{
'ID': 698,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESTA NOCHE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TONIGHT'
},
{
'ID': 699,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TRAFICO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TRAFFIC'
},
{
'ID': 700,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VIAJE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TRIP'
},
{
'ID': 701,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EN CUALQUIER SITIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ANYPLACE'
},
{
'ID': 702,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PROMEDIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AVERAGE'
},
{
'ID': 703,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EQUILIBRIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BALANCE'
},
{
'ID': 704,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FACTURA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BILL'
},
{
'ID': 705,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'POTENTE,PODEROSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'POWERFUL'
},
{
'ID': 706,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'REINA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'QUEEN'
},
{
'ID': 707,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RÁPIDAMENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'QUICKLY'
},
{
'ID': 708,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SATISFECHO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SATISFIED'
},
{
'ID': 709,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESTILO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'STYLE'
},
{
'ID': 710,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESTAR DE ACUERDO CON',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO AGREE WITH'
},
{
'ID': 711,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LIMPIAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO CLEAN'
},
{
'ID': 712,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONSIDERAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO CONSIDER'
},
{
'ID': 713,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DISFRUTAR DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ENJOY'
},
{
'ID': 714,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'IR A CASA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO GO HOME'
},
{
'ID': 715,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LLOVER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO RAIN'
},
{
'ID': 716,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'REDUCIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO REDUCE'
},
{
'ID': 717,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ROBAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO STEAL'
},
{
'ID': 718,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LANZAR,ARROJAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO THROW'
},
{
'ID': 719,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENTENDER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO UNDERSTAND'
},
{
'ID': 720,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'UTILIZAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO USE'
},
{
'ID': 721,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CAMIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TRUCK'
},
{
'ID': 722,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FEO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'UGLY'
},
{
'ID': 723,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NORMALMENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'USUALLY'
},
{
'ID': 724,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VALOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'VALOR'
},
{
'ID': 725,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENTERO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WHOLE'
},
{
'ID': 726,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EN CUALQUIER SITIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ANYWHERE'
},
{
'ID': 727,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DETALLE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DETAIL'
},
{
'ID': 728,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FÁCILMENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EASILY'
},
{
'ID': 729,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ACONTECIMIENTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EVENT'
},
{
'ID': 730,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FRACASO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FAILURE'
},
{
'ID': 731,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SALUD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HEALTH'
},
{
'ID': 732,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GERENTE,DIRECTOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MANAGER'
},
{
'ID': 733,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PRESIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PRESSURE'
},
{
'ID': 734,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'REFERENTE A',
        'RESPUESTA': 'REGARDING'
},
{
'ID': 735,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SEGURIDAD (FÍSICA)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SAFETY'
},
{
'ID': 736,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DE ÉXITO,EXITOSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SUCCESSFUL'
},
{
'ID': 737,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EL MEJOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THE BEST'
},
{
'ID': 738,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PERMITIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ALLOW'
},
{
'ID': 739,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TENER MIEDO DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BE AFRAID OF'
},
{
'ID': 740,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SER ABURRIDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BE BORING'
},
{
'ID': 741,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COGER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO CATCH'
},
{
'ID': 742,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LLORAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO CRY'
},
{
'ID': 743,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VACIAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO EMPTY'
},
{
'ID': 744,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HACER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO MAKE'
},
{
'ID': 745,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PLANEAR,PLANIFICAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO PLAN'
},
{
'ID': 746,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AHORRAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SAVE'
},
{
'ID': 747,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DECIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SAY'
},
{
'ID': 748,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MOSTRAR,ENSEÑAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SHOW'
},
{
'ID': 749,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LAVAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO WASH'
},
{
'ID': 750,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'OESTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WEST'
},
{
'ID': 751,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SENTIDO COMÚN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'COMMON SENSE'
},
{
'ID': 752,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PRIMO,PRIMA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'COUSIN'
},
{
'ID': 753,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENTREGA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DELIVERY'
},
{
'ID': 754,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DEBIDO A',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DUE TO'
},
{
'ID': 755,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EXPLICACIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EXPLANATION'
},
{
'ID': 756,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AGRICULTOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FARMER'
},
{
'ID': 757,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EXTRANJERO (SUSTANTIVO)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FOREIGNER'
},
{
'ID': 758,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'IMPRESO,FORMULARIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FORM'
},
{
'ID': 759,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VAGO,PEREZOSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LAZY'
},
{
'ID': 760,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NATURALEZA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NATURE'
},
{
'ID': 761,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NADIE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NONE'
},
{
'ID': 762,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NORMALMENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NORMALLY'
},
{
'ID': 763,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RESPECTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RESPECT'
},
{
'ID': 764,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ETAPA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'STAGE'
},
{
'ID': 765,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TRAER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BRING'
},
{
'ID': 766,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CRUZAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO CROSS'
},
{
'ID': 767,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESCAPAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ESCAPE'
},
{
'ID': 768,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INVITAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO INVITE'
},
{
'ID': 769,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VENDER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SELL'
},
{
'ID': 770,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESTAR SENTADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SIT'
},
{
'ID': 771,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NEVAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SNOW'
},
{
'ID': 772,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HABLAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SPEAK'
},
{
'ID': 773,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SORPRENDER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SURPRISE'
},
{
'ID': 774,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESEAR,QUERER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO WANT'
},
{
'ID': 775,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HACIA ARRIBA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'UP'
},
{
'ID': 776,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DE CUALQUIER MODO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ANYHOW'
},
{
'ID': 777,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ASPECTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ASPECT'
},
{
'ID': 778,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NEGOCIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BUSINESS'
},
{
'ID': 779,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COMPARACIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'COMPARISON'
},
{
'ID': 780,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RETRASO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DELAY'
},
{
'ID': 781,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INCLUSO,AUN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EVEN'
},
{
'ID': 782,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VIDA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LIFE'
},
{
'ID': 783,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'POBLACIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'POPULATION'
},
{
'ID': 784,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ACTUAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ACT'
},
{
'ID': 785,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESTAR ABURRIDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BE BORED'
},
{
'ID': 786,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PERTENECER A',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BELONG TO'
},
{
'ID': 787,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PONERSE EN CONTACTO CON',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO CONTACT'
},
{
'ID': 788,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SOÑAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO DREAM'
},
{
'ID': 789,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESTABLECER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ESTABLISH'
},
{
'ID': 790,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LUCHAR,PELEAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO FIGHT'
},
{
'ID': 791,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ALCANZAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO REACH'
},
{
'ID': 792,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SERVIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SERVE'
},
{
'ID': 793,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESTAR DE PIE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO STAND'
},
{
'ID': 794,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENSEÑAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO TEACH'
},
{
'ID': 795,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DECIR,CONTAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO TELL'
},
{
'ID': 796,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ANDAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO WALK'
},
{
'ID': 797,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESCRIBIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO WRITE'
},
{
'ID': 798,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HASTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'UNTIL'
},
{
'ID': 799,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': '¿QUÉ PASA?',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WHAT\'S THE MATTER?'
},
{
'ID': 800,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MADERA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WOOD'
},
{
'ID': 801,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AL PRINCIPIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AT FIRST'
},
{
'ID': 802,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COMPARADO CON',
        'RESPUESTA': 'COMPARE TO, COMPARE WITH'
},
{
'ID': 803,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ALGO FRÍO,FRESCO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'COLD'
},
{
'ID': 804,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DURANTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DURING'
},
{
'ID': 805,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ÉNFASIS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EMPHASIS'
},
{
'ID': 806,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SOBRE (DE CORREOS)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ENVELOPE'
},
{
'ID': 807,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EN TODAS PARTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EVERYWHERE'
},
{
'ID': 808,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DIVERTIDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FUN'
},
{
'ID': 809,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NIETA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GRANDDAUGHTER'
},
{
'ID': 810,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HIELO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ICE'
},
{
'ID': 811,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ADEMÁS DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IN ADDITION TO'
},
{
'ID': 812,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PEDAZO,TROZO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PIECE'
},
{
'ID': 813,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EDUCADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'POLITE'
},
{
'ID': 814,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RIESGO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RISK'
},
{
'ID': 815,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HASTA AHORA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SO FAR'
},
{
'ID': 816,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESTABLE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'STABLE'
},
{
'ID': 817,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONVERTIRSE EN,LLEGAR A SER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BECOME'
},
{
'ID': 818,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LLEVAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO CARRY'
},
{
'ID': 819,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COPIAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO COPY'
},
{
'ID': 820,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BAILAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO DANCE'
},
{
'ID': 821,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESTAR EN DESACUERDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO DISAGREE'
},
{
'ID': 822,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LEVANTARSE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO GET UP'
},
{
'ID': 823,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ODIAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO HATE'
},
{
'ID': 824,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': '¿QUÉ QUERÍAS DECIR?',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WHAT DID YOU MEAN?'
},
{
'ID': 825,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PREOCUPADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WORRIED'
},
{
'ID': 826,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FONDO,PARTE INFERIOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BOTTOM'
},
{
'ID': 827,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CIRCUNSTANCIAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CIRCUMSTANCES'
},
{
'ID': 828,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CASUALIDAD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'COINCIDENCE'
},
{
'ID': 829,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CURSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'COURSE'
},
{
'ID': 830,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SENTIMIENTOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FEELINGS'
},
{
'ID': 831,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CIFRAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FIGURES'
},
{
'ID': 832,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EXTRANJERO (ADJETIVO)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FOREIGN'
},
{
'ID': 833,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AGRADABLE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PLEASANT'
},
{
'ID': 834,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SEGURO,LIBRE DE PELIGRO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SAFE'
},
{
'ID': 835,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DELGADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THIN'
},
{
'ID': 836,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COMPROBAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO CHECK'
},
{
'ID': 837,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONVERSAR SOBRE UN TEMA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO DISCOURSE'
},
{
'ID': 838,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DIVIDIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO DIVIDE'
},
{
'ID': 839,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NOTAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO NOTICE'
},
{
'ID': 840,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PROGRESAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO PROGRESS'
},
{
'ID': 841,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SUSTITUIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO REPLACE'
},
{
'ID': 842,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EMPEZAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO START'
},
{
'ID': 843,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'QUEDARSE,PERMANECER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO STAY'
},
{
'ID': 844,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NADAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SWIM'
},
{
'ID': 845,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESCRIBIR A MAQUINA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO TYPE'
},
{
'ID': 846,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESPERAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO WAIT'
},
{
'ID': 847,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VERDADERO,VERDAD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TRUTH'
},
{
'ID': 848,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VISTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'VIEW'
},
{
'ID': 849,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': '¿QUÉ CLASE DE...?',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WHAT KIND OF...?'
},
{
'ID': 850,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MARAVILLOSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WONDERFUL'
},
{
'ID': 851,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SEGÚN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ACCORDING TO'
},
{
'ID': 852,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ANUNCIO (EN PRENSA)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ADVERTISEMENT'
},
{
'ID': 853,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONTRA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AGAINST'
},
{
'ID': 854,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DORMIDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ASLEEP'
},
{
'ID': 855,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MEJOR QUE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BETTER THAN'
},
{
'ID': 856,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CEPILLO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BRUSH'
},
{
'ID': 857,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COCINERO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'COOK'
},
{
'ID': 858,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'POCOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FEW'
},
{
'ID': 859,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ABUELA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GRANDMOTHER'
},
{
'ID': 860,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'UVAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GRAPES'
},
{
'ID': 861,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HELADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ICE CREAM'
},
{
'ID': 862,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'IMPOSIBLE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IMPOSSIBLE'
},
{
'ID': 863,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EN VEZ DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'INSTEAD OF'
},
{
'ID': 864,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ISLA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ISLAND'
},
{
'ID': 865,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MAS QUE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MORE THAN'
},
{
'ID': 866,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CUELLO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NECK'
},
{
'ID': 867,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NINGUNO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NONE'
},
{
'ID': 868,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESTAR DE ACUERDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO AGREE'
},
{
'ID': 869,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COLGAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO HANG'
},
{
'ID': 870,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SUJETAR,SOSTENER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO HOLD'
},
{
'ID': 871,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SALTAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO JUMP'
},
{
'ID': 872,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GUARDAR,MANTENER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO KEEP'
},
{
'ID': 873,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PINTAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO PAINT'
},
{
'ID': 874,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ELEGIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO PICK'
},
{
'ID': 875,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VER,OBSERVAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO WATCH'
},
{
'ID': 876,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EQUIPAJE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BAGGAGE'
},
{
'ID': 877,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MENOS QUE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LESS THAN'
},
{
'ID': 878,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PERDEDOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LOSER'
},
{
'ID': 879,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'QUIZÁS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PERHAPS'
},
{
'ID': 880,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BASTANTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'QUITE'
},
{
'ID': 881,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LENTAMENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SLOWLY'
},
{
'ID': 882,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ASÍ QUE,POR TANTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SO'
},
{
'ID': 883,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ALGUIEN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SOMEBODY'
},
{
'ID': 884,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ALGO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SOMETHING'
},
{
'ID': 885,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'A VECES',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SOMETIMES'
},
{
'ID': 886,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SELLO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'STAMP'
},
{
'ID': 887,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PISCINA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SWIMMING POOL'
},
{
'ID': 888,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'IR DE COMPRAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO GO SHOPPING'
},
{
'ID': 889,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DARSE PRISA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO HURRY'
},
{
'ID': 890,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENVIAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SEND'
},
{
'ID': 891,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CANTAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SING'
},
{
'ID': 892,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SENTARSE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SIT DOWN'
},
{
'ID': 893,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DORMIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SLEEP'
},
{
'ID': 894,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LLEVAR,TOMAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO TAKE'
},
{
'ID': 895,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INTENTAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO TRY'
},
{
'ID': 896,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESPERTARSE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO WEAK UP'
},
{
'ID': 897,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GANAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO WIN'
},
{
'ID': 898,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CALENTITO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WARM'
},
{
'ID': 899,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DÉBIL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WEAK'
},
{
'ID': 900,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GANADOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WINNER'
},
{
'ID': 901,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ACEPTABLE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ACCEPTABLE'
},
{
'ID': 902,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ALREDEDOR DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AROUND'
},
{
'ID': 903,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESPIERTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AWAKE'
},
{
'ID': 904,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BRASILEÑO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BRAZILIAN'
},
{
'ID': 905,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AMPLIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BROAD'
},
{
'ID': 906,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CON CUIDADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CAREFULLY'
},
{
'ID': 907,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DOBLE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DOUBLE'
},
{
'ID': 908,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DURACIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DURATION'
},
{
'ID': 909,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FÁCILMENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EASILY'
},
{
'ID': 910,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ÉNFASIS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EMPHASIS'
},
{
'ID': 911,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'REGALO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GIFT'
},
{
'ID': 912,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CRECIMIENTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GROWTH'
},
{
'ID': 913,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DELANTE DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IN FRONT OF'
},
{
'ID': 914,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INCOMPLETO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'INCOMPLETE'
},
{
'ID': 915,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RUIDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NOISE'
},
{
'ID': 916,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENFERMO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SICK'
},
{
'ID': 917,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LETRERO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SIGN'
},
{
'ID': 918,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LENTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SLOW'
},
{
'ID': 919,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HASTA AHORA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SO FAR'
},
{
'ID': 920,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BLANDO,SUAVE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SOFT'
},
{
'ID': 921,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AJUSTAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ADJUST'
},
{
'ID': 922,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MOLESTAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BOTHER'
},
{
'ID': 923,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LLEVAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO CARRY'
},
{
'ID': 924,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONGELAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO FREEZE'
},
{
'ID': 925,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PERDER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO LOSE'
},
{
'ID': 926,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ACCESO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ACCESS'
},
{
'ID': 927,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VENTAJA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ADVANTAGE'
},
{
'ID': 928,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'POR DELANTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AHEAD'
},
{
'ID': 929,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TERRIBLEMENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AWFULLY'
},
{
'ID': 930,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'POR DEBAJO DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BELOW'
},
{
'ID': 931,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CUÑADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BROTHER IN LAW'
},
{
'ID': 932,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VIDA PROFESIONAL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CAREER'
},
{
'ID': 933,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EN TODAS PARTES',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EVERYWHERE'
},
{
'ID': 934,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SENTIMIENTOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FEELINGS'
},
{
'ID': 935,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PREVISIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FORECAST'
},
{
'ID': 936,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EXTRANJERO (SUSTANTIVO)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FOREIGNER'
},
{
'ID': 937,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SALUD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HEALTH'
},
{
'ID': 938,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COLINA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HILL'
},
{
'ID': 939,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'IMAGEN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IMAGE'
},
{
'ID': 940,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'IMPRESIONANTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IMPRESSIVE'
},
{
'ID': 941,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EN VEZ DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IN STEAD OF'
},
{
'ID': 942,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CORDERO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LAMB'
},
{
'ID': 943,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TAL VEZ',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MAYBE'
},
{
'ID': 944,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EDUCADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'POLITE'
},
{
'ID': 945,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CREAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO CREATE'
},
{
'ID': 946,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESTRUIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO DESTROY'
},
{
'ID': 947,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MANEJAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO HANDLE'
},
{
'ID': 948,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'IMAGINAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO IMAGINE'
},
{
'ID': 949,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'JUICIO,PROCESO JUDICIAL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TRIAL'
},
{
'ID': 950,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INJUSTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'UNFAIR'
},
{
'ID': 951,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EN EL EXTRANJERO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ABROAD'
},
{
'ID': 952,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CUENTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ACCOUNT'
},
{
'ID': 953,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PROMEDIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AVERAGE'
},
{
'ID': 954,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CASUALIDAD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'COINCIDENCE'
},
{
'ID': 955,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FORMACIÓN ACADÉMICA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EDUCATION'
},
{
'ID': 956,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PLANO,LLANO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FLAT'
},
{
'ID': 957,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BIBLIOTECA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LIBRARY'
},
{
'ID': 958,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EN CAMBIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ON THE OTHER HAND'
},
{
'ID': 959,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PUNTO DE VISTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'POINT OF VIEW'
},
{
'ID': 960,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CENTRO DE COMPRAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SHOPPING CENTRE'
},
{
'ID': 961,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ACEPTAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ACCEPT'
},
{
'ID': 962,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TENER PRISA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BE IN A HURRY'
},
{
'ID': 963,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CAUSAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO CAUSE'
},
{
'ID': 964,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LLENAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO FILL'
},
{
'ID': 965,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'REPARAR,ARREGLAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO FIX'
},
{
'ID': 966,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PERDONAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO FORGIVE'
},
{
'ID': 967,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LLEGAR A',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO GET TO'
},
{
'ID': 968,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'OÍR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO HEAR'
},
{
'ID': 969,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SUJETAR,SOSTENER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO HOLD'
},
{
'ID': 970,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MEJORAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO IMPROVE'
},
{
'ID': 971,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INCLUIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO INCLUDE'
},
{
'ID': 972,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SOSPECHAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SUSPECT'
},
{
'ID': 973,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LANZAR,ARROJAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO THROW'
},
{
'ID': 974,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENCENDER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO TURN ON'
},
{
'ID': 975,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SIN DUDA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WITHOUT OF DOUBT'
},
{
'ID': 976,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'UNA NECESIDAD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'A NEED'
},
{
'ID': 977,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ACOSTUMBRADO A',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ACCUSTOM TO'
},
{
'ID': 978,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EN VOZ ALTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ALOUD'
},
{
'ID': 979,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CITA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'APPOINTMENT'
},
{
'ID': 980,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EQUILIBRIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BALANCE'
},
{
'ID': 981,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESGLOSE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BREAKDOWN'
},
{
'ID': 982,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ROPA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CLOTHES'
},
{
'ID': 983,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CRITERIOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CRITERIA'
},
{
'ID': 984,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MESA DE TRABAJO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DESK'
},
{
'ID': 985,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MOTOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ENGINE'
},
{
'ID': 986,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INCLUSO,AUN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EVEN'
},
{
'ID': 987,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FINALMENTE,POR ÚLTIMO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FINALLY'
},
{
'ID': 988,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DIRECTRICES',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GUIDELINES'
},
{
'ID': 989,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'IDIOMA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LANGUAGE'
},
{
'ID': 990,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENFADADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MAD'
},
{
'ID': 991,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESTRECHO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NARROW'
},
{
'ID': 992,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'POLÍTICA (DE EMPRESA)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'POLICY'
},
{
'ID': 993,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RAZÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'REASON'
},
{
'ID': 994,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SATISFECHO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SATISFIED'
},
{
'ID': 995,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SIMPLEMENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SIMPLY'
},
{
'ID': 996,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PASO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'STEP'
},
{
'ID': 997,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'IMPUESTOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TAXES'
},
{
'ID': 998,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PERMITIRSE EL LUJO DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO AFFORD'
},
{
'ID': 999,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SER ABURRIDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BE BORING'
},
{
'ID': 1000,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EXISTIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO EXIST'
},
{
'ID': 1001,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HABILIDAD,PERICIA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ABILITY'
},
{
'ID': 1002,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AVANZADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ADVANCED'
},
{
'ID': 1003,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TAMBIÉN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ALSO'
},
{
'ID': 1004,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'APROBACIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'APPROVAL'
},
{
'ID': 1005,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VIAJE DE NEGOCIOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BUSINESS TRIP'
},
{
'ID': 1006,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COMPARADO CON',
        'RESPUESTA': 'COMPARE TO, COMPARE WITH'
},
{
'ID': 1007,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DIARIO,DIARIAMENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DIARY'
},
{
'ID': 1008,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DEBIDO A',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DUE TO'
},
{
'ID': 1009,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENTERO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ENTIRE'
},
{
'ID': 1010,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EXCEPTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EXCEPT'
},
{
'ID': 1011,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DE VEZ EN CUANDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FROM TIME TO TIME'
},
{
'ID': 1012,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SIN EMBARGO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HOWEVER'
},
{
'ID': 1013,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INCOMPETENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'INCOMPETENT'
},
{
'ID': 1014,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PUEDO HABLAR CON...?',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MAY I SPEAK TO...?'
},
{
'ID': 1015,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MECÁNICO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MECHANIC'
},
{
'ID': 1016,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PAGO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PAYMENT'
},
{
'ID': 1017,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SILENCIOSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'QUIET'
},
{
'ID': 1018,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MALEDUCADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RUDE'
},
{
'ID': 1019,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DE ALGUNA MANERA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SOMEHOW'
},
{
'ID': 1020,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESTABLE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'STABLE'
},
{
'ID': 1021,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SORPRESA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SURPRISE'
},
{
'ID': 1022,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EL PRINCIPIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THE BEGINNING'
},
{
'ID': 1023,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ADOPTAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ADOPT'
},
{
'ID': 1024,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESTAR ABURRIDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BE BORED'
},
{
'ID': 1025,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BAJAR,DESCENDER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO GO DOWN'
},
{
'ID': 1026,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ABSOLUTAMENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ABSOLUTELY'
},
{
'ID': 1027,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PUBLICIDAD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ADVERTISING'
},
{
'ID': 1028,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AUNQUE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ALTHOUGH'
},
{
'ID': 1029,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENTRE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AMONG'
},
{
'ID': 1030,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TAN PRONTO COMO,EN CUANTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AS SOON AS'
},
{
'ID': 1031,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AL LADO DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BESIDE'
},
{
'ID': 1032,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CAPACIDAD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CAPACITY'
},
{
'ID': 1033,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONFIADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CONFIDENT'
},
{
'ID': 1034,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DEFECTUOSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DEFECTIVE'
},
{
'ID': 1035,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'IGUAL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EQUAL'
},
{
'ID': 1036,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SOBRE TODO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SPECIALLY'
},
{
'ID': 1037,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ARCHIVO,EXPEDIENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FILE'
},
{
'ID': 1038,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SANO,SALUDABLE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HEALTHY'
},
{
'ID': 1039,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EN DETALLE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IN DETAIL'
},
{
'ID': 1040,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INFLACIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'INFLATION'
},
{
'ID': 1041,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VAMONOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LET\'S GO'
},
{
'ID': 1042,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MUSEO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MUSEUM'
},
{
'ID': 1043,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RUIDOSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NOISY'
},
{
'ID': 1044,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PROBABLEMENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PROBABLY'
},
{
'ID': 1045,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'JUBILACIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RETIREMENT'
},
{
'ID': 1046,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TAMAÑO,TALLA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SIZE'
},
{
'ID': 1047,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESCALERAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'STAIRS'
},
{
'ID': 1048,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TRAJE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SUIT'
},
{
'ID': 1049,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TITULO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TITLE'
},
{
'ID': 1050,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESCONDER,OCULTAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO HIDE'
},
{
'ID': 1051,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SEGÚN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ACCORDING TO'
},
{
'ID': 1052,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ASUNTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AFFAIR'
},
{
'ID': 1053,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ANÁLISIS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ANALYSIS'
},
{
'ID': 1054,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AYUDANTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ASSISTANT'
},
{
'ID': 1055,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CIEGO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BLIND'
},
{
'ID': 1056,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CLARO,TRANSPARENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CLEAR'
},
{
'ID': 1057,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CRÍTICA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CRITICISM'
},
{
'ID': 1058,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESVENTAJA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DISADVANTAGE'
},
{
'ID': 1059,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EXAMEN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EXAM'
},
{
'ID': 1060,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EJEMPLO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EXAMPLE'
},
{
'ID': 1061,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FRUSTRADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FRUSTRATED'
},
{
'ID': 1062,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ME TRAE SIN CUIDADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'I DON\'T CARE'
},
{
'ID': 1063,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CELOSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'JEALOUS'
},
{
'ID': 1064,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LA MAYORÍA DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MOST'
},
{
'ID': 1065,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SOBRINA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NIECE'
},
{
'ID': 1066,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'POTENTE,PODEROSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'POWERFUL'
},
{
'ID': 1067,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RECURSOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RESOURCES'
},
{
'ID': 1068,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SIMILAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SIMILAR'
},
{
'ID': 1069,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DE REPENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SUDDENLY'
},
{
'ID': 1070,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CENA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SUPPER'
},
{
'ID': 1071,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PROPINA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TIP'
},
{
'ID': 1072,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TENER MIEDO DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BE AFRAID OF'
},
{
'ID': 1073,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COMPRAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BUY'
},
{
'ID': 1074,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONVENCER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO CONVINCE'
},
{
'ID': 1075,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'POSEER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO OWN'
},
{
'ID': 1076,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'REAL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ACTUAL'
},
{
'ID': 1077,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INQUIETO,AMBICIOSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AMBITIOUS'
},
{
'ID': 1078,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'OTRO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ANOTHER'
},
{
'ID': 1079,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AMBIENTE,ATMÓSFERA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ATMOSPHERE'
},
{
'ID': 1080,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AMBOS,LOS DOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BOTH'
},
{
'ID': 1081,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COMÚN,CORRIENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'COMMON'
},
{
'ID': 1082,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PELIGROSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DANGEROUS'
},
{
'ID': 1083,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EFICAZ',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EFFECTIVE'
},
{
'ID': 1084,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'JUSTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FAIR'
},
{
'ID': 1085,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MÁS LEJOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FURTHER'
},
{
'ID': 1086,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DURO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HARD'
},
{
'ID': 1087,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'A FAVOR DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IN FAVOUR OF'
},
{
'ID': 1088,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ALTO (UN RUIDO)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LOUD'
},
{
'ID': 1089,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HOY EN DIA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NOWADAYS'
},
{
'ID': 1090,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PORCENTAJE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PERCENTAGE'
},
{
'ID': 1091,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LISTO,PREPARADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'READY'
},
{
'ID': 1092,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TEMPORADA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SEASON'
},
{
'ID': 1093,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FUERTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'STRONG'
},
{
'ID': 1094,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LLAMADA TELEFÓNICA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TELEPHONE CALL'
},
{
'ID': 1095,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GRUESO,ESPESO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THICK'
},
{
'ID': 1096,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ASISTIR A',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ATTEND'
},
{
'ID': 1097,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONSTRUIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BUILD'
},
{
'ID': 1098,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONTINUAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO CONTINUE'
},
{
'ID': 1099,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DUDAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO DOUBT'
},
{
'ID': 1100,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PARECER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SEEM'
},
{
'ID': 1101,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EN REALIDAD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ACTUALLY'
},
{
'ID': 1102,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ANUAL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ANNUAL'
},
{
'ID': 1103,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CUALQUIERA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ANYONE'
},
{
'ID': 1104,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ACTITUD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ATTITUDE'
},
{
'ID': 1105,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EDIFICIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BUILDING'
},
{
'ID': 1106,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'QUEJA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'COMPLAINT'
},
{
'ID': 1107,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DEFECTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DEFECT'
},
{
'ID': 1108,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ACONTECIMIENTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EVENT'
},
{
'ID': 1109,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SUELTO,FLUIDO (HABLANDO)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FLUENT'
},
{
'ID': 1110,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AFORTUNADAMENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FORTUNATELY'
},
{
'ID': 1111,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENORME',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HUGE'
},
{
'ID': 1112,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LLAVE,CLAVE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'KEY'
},
{
'ID': 1113,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NERVIOSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NERVOUS'
},
{
'ID': 1114,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DUEÑO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'OWNER'
},
{
'ID': 1115,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BENEFICIOS (ECONÓMICOS)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PROFITS'
},
{
'ID': 1116,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RUTINA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ROUTINE'
},
{
'ID': 1117,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TODAVÍA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'STILL'
},
{
'ID': 1118,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EL SUELO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THE GROUND'
},
{
'ID': 1119,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LO CONTRARIO DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THE OPPOSITE OF'
},
{
'ID': 1120,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PEDIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ASK FOR'
},
{
'ID': 1121,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ROMPER EL HIELO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BREAK THE ICE'
},
{
'ID': 1122,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONSULTAR CON',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO CONSULT'
},
{
'ID': 1123,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DISTRIBUIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO DISTRIBUTE'
},
{
'ID': 1124,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SEGUIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO FOLLOW'
},
{
'ID': 1125,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PREOCUPARSE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO WORRY'
},
{
'ID': 1126,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SEÑAS,DIRECCIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ADDRESS'
},
{
'ID': 1127,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HORMIGA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ANT'
},
{
'ID': 1128,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CUALQUIER COSA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ANYTHING'
},
{
'ID': 1129,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HERMOSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BEAUTIFUL'
},
{
'ID': 1130,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'POR CIERTO,A PROPÓSITO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BY THE WAY'
},
{
'ID': 1131,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONSECUENCIAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CONSEQUENCES'
},
{
'ID': 1132,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DEDICADO A',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DEVOTED TO'
},
{
'ID': 1133,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EXCEPCIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EXCEPTION'
},
{
'ID': 1134,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FRECUENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FREQUENT'
},
{
'ID': 1135,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GESTO,DETALLE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GESTURE'
},
{
'ID': 1136,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RESPONSABLE DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IN CHARGE OF'
},
{
'ID': 1137,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AFORTUNADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LUCKY'
},
{
'ID': 1138,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PÁRRAFO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PARAGRAPH'
},
{
'ID': 1139,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FASE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PHASE'
},
{
'ID': 1140,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INFORME',
        'RESPUESTA': 'REPORT'
},
{
'ID': 1141,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESDE CUANDO?',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SINCE WHEN?'
},
{
'ID': 1142,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SISTEMA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SYSTEM'
},
{
'ID': 1143,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CANSADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TIRED'
},
{
'ID': 1144,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'APARECER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO APPEAR'
},
{
'ID': 1145,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PERTENECER A',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BELONG TO'
},
{
'ID': 1146,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONFIRMAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO CONFIRM'
},
{
'ID': 1147,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESTAR EN DESACUERDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO DISAGREE'
},
{
'ID': 1148,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AVERIGUAR,ENTERARSE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO FIND OUT'
},
{
'ID': 1149,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'IDENTIFICAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO IDENTIFY'
},
{
'ID': 1150,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TORRE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TOWER'
},
{
'ID': 1151,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ADECUADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ADEQUATE'
},
{
'ID': 1152,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DE TODOS MODOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ANYWAY'
},
{
'ID': 1153,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ASPECTO,APARIENCIA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'APPEARANCE'
},
{
'ID': 1154,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DETRÁS DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BEHIND'
},
{
'ID': 1155,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TECHO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CEILING'
},
{
'ID': 1156,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MULTITUD,MUCHEDUMBRE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CROWD'
},
{
'ID': 1157,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BARATO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ECONOMICAL'
},
{
'ID': 1158,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CIFRAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FIGURES'
},
{
'ID': 1159,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FRESCO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FRESH'
},
{
'ID': 1160,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DIA FESTIVO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HOLYDAY'
},
{
'ID': 1161,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NO TIENE SENTIDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IT DOESN\'T MAKE SENSE'
},
{
'ID': 1162,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'OLVÍDALO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NEVER MIND'
},
{
'ID': 1163,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TUBO,TUBERÍA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PIPE'
},
{
'ID': 1164,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PROPÓSITO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PURPOSE'
},
{
'ID': 1165,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HORARIO,PROGRAMA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SCHEDULE'
},
{
'ID': 1166,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TEMA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SUBJECT'
},
{
'ID': 1167,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AVANZAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ADVANCE'
},
{
'ID': 1168,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PEDIR PERDÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO APOLOGIZE'
},
{
'ID': 1169,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESTAR SEGURO DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BE SURE OF'
},
{
'ID': 1170,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ACLARAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO CLEAR UP'
},
{
'ID': 1171,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESARROLLAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO DEVELOP'
},
{
'ID': 1172,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RELLENAR (IMPRESOS)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO FILL OUT'
},
{
'ID': 1173,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DARSE PRISA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO HURRY'
},
{
'ID': 1174,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ORGANIZAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ORGANIZE'
},
{
'ID': 1175,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VOZ',
        'RESPUESTA': 'VOICE'
},
{
'ID': 1176,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ANUNCIO (DE PRENSA)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ADVERTISEMENT'
},
{
'ID': 1177,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'APARTE DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'APART FROM'
},
{
'ID': 1178,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LLEGADA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ARRIVAL'
},
{
'ID': 1179,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BENEFICIOSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BENEFICIAL'
},
{
'ID': 1180,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CLIMA,AMBIENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CLIMATE'
},
{
'ID': 1181,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FECHA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DATE'
},
{
'ID': 1182,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESENCIAL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ESSENTIAL'
},
{
'ID': 1183,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LIBREMENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FREELY'
},
{
'ID': 1184,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONTENTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GLAD'
},
{
'ID': 1185,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INMEDIATAMENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IMMEDIATELY'
},
{
'ID': 1186,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'UBICACIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LOCATION'
},
{
'ID': 1187,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LLAMADA TELEFÓNICA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PHONE CALL'
},
{
'ID': 1188,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'IMPRESORA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PRINTER'
},
{
'ID': 1189,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RESPETABLE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RESPECTABLE'
},
{
'ID': 1190,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AFIRMACIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'STATEMENT'
},
{
'ID': 1191,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LA PARTE SUPERIOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THE TOP'
},
{
'ID': 1192,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EVITAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO AVOID'
},
{
'ID': 1193,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EQUILIBRAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BALANCE'
},
{
'ID': 1194,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COGER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO CATCH'
},
{
'ID': 1195,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENTREGAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO DELIVER'
},
{
'ID': 1196,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SENTIR,PENSAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO FEEL'
},
{
'ID': 1197,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PEGAR,GOLPEAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO HIT'
},
{
'ID': 1198,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'OFRECER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO OFFER'
},
{
'ID': 1199,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RECHAZAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO REJECT'
},
{
'ID': 1200,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MIENTRAS,MIENTRAS QUE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WHILE'
},
{
'ID': 1201,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'POR ENCIMA DE,SOBRE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ABOVE'
},
{
'ID': 1202,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONSEJO,ASESORAMIENTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ADVICE'
},
{
'ID': 1203,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENFOQUE,PLANTEAMIENTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'APPROACH'
},
{
'ID': 1204,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AUTOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AUTHOR'
},
{
'ID': 1205,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENTRE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BETWEEN'
},
{
'ID': 1206,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SENTIDO COMÚN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'COMMON SENSE'
},
{
'ID': 1207,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RETRASO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DELAY'
},
{
'ID': 1208,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EXACTAMENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EXACTLY'
},
{
'ID': 1209,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'META',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GOAL'
},
{
'ID': 1210,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GOBIERNO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GOVERNMENT'
},
{
'ID': 1211,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INGRESOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'INCOME'
},
{
'ID': 1212,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NATURALEZA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NATURE'
},
{
'ID': 1213,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PROHIBIDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PROHIBITED'
},
{
'ID': 1214,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CALIDAD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'QUALITY'
},
{
'ID': 1215,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FRASE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SENTENCE'
},
{
'ID': 1216,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SUPERFICIE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SURFACE'
},
{
'ID': 1217,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'APROBAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO APPROVE'
},
{
'ID': 1218,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SACAR UN TEMA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BRING UP'
},
{
'ID': 1219,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TREPAR,SUBIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO CLIMB'
},
{
'ID': 1220,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TRATAR CON',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO DEAL WITH'
},
{
'ID': 1221,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EXCLUIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO EXCLUDE'
},
{
'ID': 1222,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DIVERTIRSE,PASARLO BIEN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO HAVE A GOOD TIME'
},
{
'ID': 1223,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MEZCLAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO MIX'
},
{
'ID': 1224,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ARREPENTIRSE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO REGRET'
},
{
'ID': 1225,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FIRMAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SIGN'
},
{
'ID': 1226,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MIEDOSO,TEMEROSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AFRAID'
},
{
'ID': 1227,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'APROXIMADAMENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'APPROXIMATELY'
},
{
'ID': 1228,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HORRIBLE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AWFUL'
},
{
'ID': 1229,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FRONTERA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BORDER'
},
{
'ID': 1230,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COMPLETAMENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'COMPLETELY'
},
{
'ID': 1231,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DIFICULTAD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DIFFICULTY'
},
{
'ID': 1232,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FRACASO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FAILURE'
},
{
'ID': 1233,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HIERBA,CÉSPED',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GRASS'
},
{
'ID': 1234,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PERDIDO (SIN ESPERANZA)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HOPELESS'
},
{
'ID': 1235,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MÁS TARDE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LATER'
},
{
'ID': 1236,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'QUIZÁS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PERHAPS'
},
{
'ID': 1237,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TRIMESTRE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'QUARTER'
},
{
'ID': 1238,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RESULTADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RESULT'
},
{
'ID': 1239,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RECTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'STRAIGHT'
},
{
'ID': 1240,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'A TRAVÉS DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THROUGH'
},
{
'ID': 1241,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONVERTIRSE EN,LLEGAR A SER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BECOME'
},
{
'ID': 1242,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONSISTIR EN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO CONSIST OF'
},
{
'ID': 1243,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VACIAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO EMPTY'
},
{
'ID': 1244,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CAERSE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO FALL DOWN'
},
{
'ID': 1245,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EMPEORARSE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO GET WORSE'
},
{
'ID': 1246,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DIRIGIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO MANAGE'
},
{
'ID': 1247,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PRONUNCIAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO PRONOUNCE'
},
{
'ID': 1248,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'REDUCIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO REDUCE'
},
{
'ID': 1249,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CERRAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SHUT'
},
{
'ID': 1250,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INTENTAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO TRY TO'
},
{
'ID': 1251,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESPUÉS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AFTERWARDS'
},
{
'ID': 1252,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COMO SI',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AS IF'
},
{
'ID': 1253,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HACIA ATRÁS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BACKWARD'
},
{
'ID': 1254,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BREVE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BRIEF'
},
{
'ID': 1255,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONSTANTEMENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CONSTANTLY'
},
{
'ID': 1256,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ECONOMÍA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ECONOMY'
},
{
'ID': 1257,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'IMPRESO,FORMULARIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FORM'
},
{
'ID': 1258,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'JUDÍAS VERDES',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GREEN BEANS'
},
{
'ID': 1259,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ADEMÁS DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IN ADDITION TO'
},
{
'ID': 1260,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MÉTODO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'METHOD'
},
{
'ID': 1261,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PROPUESTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PROPOSAL'
},
{
'ID': 1262,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RECIENTEMENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RECENTLY'
},
{
'ID': 1263,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VARIOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SEVERAL'
},
{
'ID': 1264,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TRABAJO EN EQUIPO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TEAMWORK'
},
{
'ID': 1265,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ATACAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ATTACK'
},
{
'ID': 1266,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CAMBIAR DE TEMA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO CHANGE THE SUBJECT'
},
{
'ID': 1267,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MORIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO DIE'
},
{
'ID': 1268,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BORRAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ERASE'
},
{
'ID': 1269,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'APAÑARSE,SALIR DEL PASO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO GET BY'
},
{
'ID': 1270,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENTRAR EN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO GO INTO'
},
{
'ID': 1271,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LOCALIZAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO LOCATE'
},
{
'ID': 1272,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DARSE CUENTA DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO REALIZE'
},
{
'ID': 1273,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FIJAR,ESTABLECER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SET'
},
{
'ID': 1274,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONFIAR EN,FIARSE DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO TRUST'
},
{
'ID': 1275,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'URGENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'URGENT'
},
{
'ID': 1276,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COMO DE COSTUMBRE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AS USUAL'
},
{
'ID': 1277,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BANQUERO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BANKER'
},
{
'ID': 1278,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HOMBRE DE NEGOCIOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BUSINESSMAN'
},
{
'ID': 1279,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ABARROTADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CROWDED'
},
{
'ID': 1280,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EVALUACIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EVALUATION'
},
{
'ID': 1281,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GENEROSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GENEROUS'
},
{
'ID': 1282,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TIPO,INDIVIDUO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GUY'
},
{
'ID': 1283,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LA FELICIDAD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HAPPINESS'
},
{
'ID': 1284,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INTERESADO EN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'INTERESTED IN'
},
{
'ID': 1285,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'A PROPÓSITO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ON PURPOSE'
},
{
'ID': 1286,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'REQUISITOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'REQUIREMENTS'
},
{
'ID': 1287,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AFILADO,AGUDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SHARP'
},
{
'ID': 1288,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PLATA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SILVER'
},
{
'ID': 1289,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESTAR DE ACUERDO CON',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO AGREE WITH'
},
{
'ID': 1290,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ROMPER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BREAK'
},
{
'ID': 1291,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DISMINUIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO DECREASE'
},
{
'ID': 1292,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ARCHIVAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO FILE'
},
{
'ID': 1293,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DURAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO LAST'
},
{
'ID': 1294,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SIGNIFICAR,QUERER DECIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO MEAN'
},
{
'ID': 1295,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PRACTICAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO PRACTICE'
},
{
'ID': 1296,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PROGRAMAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SCHEDULE'
},
{
'ID': 1297,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TIRAR A AL BASURA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO THROW AWAY'
},
{
'ID': 1298,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'JUGUETE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TOY'
},
{
'ID': 1299,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ACTUALIZADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'UPDATE'
},
{
'ID': 1300,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RUEDA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WHEEL'
},
{
'ID': 1301,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONTRA,EN CONTRA DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AGAINST'
},
{
'ID': 1302,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LO ANTES POSIBLE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AS SOON AS POSSIBLE'
},
{
'ID': 1303,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SÓTANO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BASEMENT'
},
{
'ID': 1304,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BASE,FUNDAMENTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BASIS'
},
{
'ID': 1305,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ROTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BROKEN'
},
{
'ID': 1306,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CÓMODO,OPORTUNO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CONVENIENT'
},
{
'ID': 1307,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESFUERZO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EFFORT'
},
{
'ID': 1308,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LIBRE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FREE'
},
{
'ID': 1309,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AMA DE CASA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HOUSEWIFE'
},
{
'ID': 1310,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EN TODO CASO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IN ANY CASE'
},
{
'ID': 1311,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MIND'
},
{
'ID': 1312,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ORGULLOSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PROUD'
},
{
'ID': 1313,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TÍMIDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SHY'
},
{
'ID': 1314,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'JABÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SOAP'
},
{
'ID': 1315,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESO ES,EN EFECTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THAT\'S RIGHT'
},
{
'ID': 1316,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ATRAER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ATTRACT'
},
{
'ID': 1317,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONVERSAR (SOBRE UN TEMA)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO DISCOURSE'
},
{
'ID': 1318,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PONERSE NERVIOSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO GET NERVOUS'
},
{
'ID': 1319,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BUSCAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO LOOK FOR'
},
{
'ID': 1320,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ADELANTAR,PASAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO PASS'
},
{
'ID': 1321,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RECONOCER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO RECOGNIZE'
},
{
'ID': 1322,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GRITAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SHOUT'
},
{
'ID': 1323,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VIAJAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO TRAVEL'
},
{
'ID': 1324,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GIRAR,TORCER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO TURN'
},
{
'ID': 1325,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ÚTIL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'USEFUL'
},
{
'ID': 1326,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EDAD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AGE'
},
{
'ID': 1327,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CUANDO QUIERAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ANYTIME'
},
{
'ID': 1328,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'JUDÍAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BEANS'
},
{
'ID': 1329,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PORQUE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BECAUSE'
},
{
'ID': 1330,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TRANQUILO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CALM'
},
{
'ID': 1331,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'REFERENTE A',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CONCERNING'
},
{
'ID': 1332,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENTREGA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DELIVERY'
},
{
'ID': 1333,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TODOS LOS DÍAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EVERYDAY'
},
{
'ID': 1334,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'POR EJEMPLO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FOR EXAMPLE'
},
{
'ID': 1335,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COMO SE DICE...?',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HOW DO YOU SAY...?'
},
{
'ID': 1336,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENFERMEDAD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ILLNESS'
},
{
'ID': 1337,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DA IGUAL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IT DOESN\'T MATTER'
},
{
'ID': 1338,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MEZCLA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MIXTURE'
},
{
'ID': 1339,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PRACTICO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PRACTICAL'
},
{
'ID': 1340,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AHORA MISMO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RIGHT NOW'
},
{
'ID': 1341,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESPECIFICO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SPECIFIC'
},
{
'ID': 1342,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CUADRADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SQUARE'
},
{
'ID': 1343,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SÍMBOLO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SYMBOL'
},
{
'ID': 1344,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ANALIZAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ANALYSE'
},
{
'ID': 1345,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VALER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BE WORTH'
},
{
'ID': 1346,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ELEGIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO CHOOSE'
},
{
'ID': 1347,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DEFINIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO DEFINE'
},
{
'ID': 1348,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EVALUAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO EVALUATE'
},
{
'ID': 1349,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SUBIR,ASCENDER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO GO UP'
},
{
'ID': 1350,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HACIA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TOWARDS'
},
{
'ID': 1351,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ACUERDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AGREEMENT'
},
{
'ID': 1352,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DISCUSIÓN (ACALORADA)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ARGUMENT'
},
{
'ID': 1353,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'OSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BEAR'
},
{
'ID': 1354,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CUERPO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BODY'
},
{
'ID': 1355,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COMPARACIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'COMPARISON'
},
{
'ID': 1356,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONFIABLE, DIGNO DE CONFIANZA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DEPENDABLE'
},
{
'ID': 1357,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CARO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EXPENSIVE'
},
{
'ID': 1358,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PESADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HEAVY'
},
{
'ID': 1359,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INTERESANTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'INTERESTING'
},
{
'ID': 1360,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'IRLANDÉS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IRISH'
},
{
'ID': 1361,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TODAVÍA NO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NOT YET'
},
{
'ID': 1362,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TASA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RATE'
},
{
'ID': 1363,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FIRMA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SIGNATURE'
},
{
'ID': 1364,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TAL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SUCH'
},
{
'ID': 1365,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EQUIPO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TEAM'
},
{
'ID': 1366,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ARREGLAR,ORGANIZAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ARRANGE'
},
{
'ID': 1367,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PREGUNTAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ASK'
},
{
'ID': 1368,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LLAMAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO CALL'
},
{
'ID': 1369,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DECIDIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO DECIDE'
},
{
'ID': 1370,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EXPLICAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO EXPLAIN'
},
{
'ID': 1371,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AYUDAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO HELP'
},
{
'ID': 1372,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RECOMENDAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO RECOMMEND'
},
{
'ID': 1373,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ASUSTAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SCARE'
},
{
'ID': 1374,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SANDIA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WATERMELON'
},
{
'ID': 1375,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VALE,DE ACUERDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ALL RIGHT'
},
{
'ID': 1376,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ATENCIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ATTENTION'
},
{
'ID': 1377,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BELGA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BELGIAN'
},
{
'ID': 1378,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CIRCUNSTANCIAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CIRCUMSTANCES'
},
{
'ID': 1379,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EXIGENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DEMANDING'
},
{
'ID': 1380,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INCENDIO,FUEGO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FIRE'
},
{
'ID': 1381,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MEJORA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IMPROVEMENT'
},
{
'ID': 1382,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CUCHILLO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'KNIFE'
},
{
'ID': 1383,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CASI',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NEARLY'
},
{
'ID': 1384,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RECOMENDACIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RECOMMENDATION'
},
{
'ID': 1385,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESTRATEGIA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'STRATEGY'
},
{
'ID': 1386,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GUÍA TELEFÓNICA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TELEPHONE BOOK'
},
{
'ID': 1387,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONTESTAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ANSWER'
},
{
'ID': 1388,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VOLVER A TELEFONEAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO CALL BACK'
},
{
'ID': 1389,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DIBUJAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO DRAW'
},
{
'ID': 1390,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TERMINAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO END'
},
{
'ID': 1391,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENCONTRAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO FIND'
},
{
'ID': 1392,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENRIQUECERSE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO GET RICH'
},
{
'ID': 1393,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NOTAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO NOTICE'
},
{
'ID': 1394,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SUSTITUIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO REPLACE'
},
{
'ID': 1395,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AFIRMAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO STATE'
},
{
'ID': 1396,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'JUGUETES',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TOYS'
},
{
'ID': 1397,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MOJADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WET'
},
{
'ID': 1398,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LE IMPORTARÍA...?',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WOULD YOU MIND...?'
},
{
'ID': 1399,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESCRITOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WRITER'
},
{
'ID': 1400,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CASI',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ALMOST'
},
{
'ID': 1401,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'POR LO MENOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AT LEAST'
},
{
'ID': 1402,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BANCO (PARA SENTARSE)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BENCH'
},
{
'ID': 1403,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CAPAZ DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CAPABLE OF'
},
{
'ID': 1404,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ACTUAL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CURRENT'
},
{
'ID': 1405,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TODO EL MUNDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EVERYBODY'
},
{
'ID': 1406,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GIGANTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GIANT'
},
{
'ID': 1407,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'IMPUESTO SOBRE LA RENTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'INCOME TAX'
},
{
'ID': 1408,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NIVEL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LEVEL'
},
{
'ID': 1409,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AL CONTRARIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ON THE CONTRARY'
},
{
'ID': 1410,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'REFERENTE A',
        'RESPUESTA': 'REGARDING'
},
{
'ID': 1411,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESTADÍSTICAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'STATISTICS'
},
{
'ID': 1412,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EL CORREO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THE MAIL'
},
{
'ID': 1413,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PENSAMIENTOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THOUGHTS'
},
{
'ID': 1414,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CREER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BELIEVE'
},
{
'ID': 1415,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CUBRIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO COVER'
},
{
'ID': 1416,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AMPLIAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO EXTEND'
},
{
'ID': 1417,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HACERSE MAYOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO GROW UP'
},
{
'ID': 1418,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AUMENTAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO INCREASE'
},
{
'ID': 1419,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PRODUCIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO PRODUCE'
},
{
'ID': 1420,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PEDIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO REQUEST'
},
{
'ID': 1421,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GASTAR,PASAR (TIEMPO)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SPEND'
},
{
'ID': 1422,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LLEVAR PUESTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO WEAR'
},
{
'ID': 1423,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VALIOSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'VALUABLE'
},
{
'ID': 1424,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VIENTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WIND'
},
{
'ID': 1425,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SOLO,EN SOLITARIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ALONE'
},
{
'ID': 1426,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ADECUADO,APROPIADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'APPROPRIATED'
},
{
'ID': 1427,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BÉLGICA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BELGIUM'
},
{
'ID': 1428,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MEJOR QUE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BETTER THAN'
},
{
'ID': 1429,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VENGA,VAMOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'COME ON'
},
{
'ID': 1430,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MUERTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DEAD'
},
{
'ID': 1431,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SUFICIENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ENOUGH'
},
{
'ID': 1432,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COMIDA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FOOD'
},
{
'ID': 1433,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DATE PRISA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HURRY UP'
},
{
'ID': 1434,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ÚLTIMAMENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LATELY'
},
{
'ID': 1435,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PERDIDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LOST'
},
{
'ID': 1436,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PRINCIPAL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MAIN'
},
{
'ID': 1437,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'POR SUPUESTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'OF COURSE'
},
{
'ID': 1438,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PROPIEDAD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PROPERTY'
},
{
'ID': 1439,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BASTANTES',
        'RESPUESTA': 'QUITE A FEW'
},
{
'ID': 1440,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VENTAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SALES'
},
{
'ID': 1441,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ÉXITO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SUCCESS'
},
{
'ID': 1442,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LADRÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THIEF'
},
{
'ID': 1443,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AÑADIR,SUMAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ADD'
},
{
'ID': 1444,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SER OPTIMISTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BE OPTIMISTIC'
},
{
'ID': 1445,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COMENTAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO COMMENT ON'
},
{
'ID': 1446,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DEPENDER DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO DEPEND ON'
},
{
'ID': 1447,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TENER GANAS DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO FEEL LIKE'
},
{
'ID': 1448,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONTRATAR (A EMPLEADOS)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO HIRE'
},
{
'ID': 1449,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TOMAR UNA DECISIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO MAKE A DECISION'
},
{
'ID': 1450,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'A LO LARGO DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ALONG'
},
{
'ID': 1451,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ASISTENCIA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ATTENDANCE'
},
{
'ID': 1452,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DEBAJO DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BENEATH'
},
{
'ID': 1453,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'OCUPADO (persona)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BUSY'
},
{
'ID': 1454,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LOCO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CRAZY'
},
{
'ID': 1455,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENORME',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ENORMOUS'
},
{
'ID': 1456,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LLENO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FULL'
},
{
'ID': 1457,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DE HECHO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IN FACT'
},
{
'ID': 1458,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MEMORIA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MEMORY'
},
{
'ID': 1459,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ANTERIOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PREVIOUS'
},
{
'ID': 1460,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PANTALLA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SCREEN'
},
{
'ID': 1461,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TORMENTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'STORM'
},
{
'ID': 1462,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SOLEADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SUNNY'
},
{
'ID': 1463,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DISCUTIR (ACALORADAMENTE)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ARGUE'
},
{
'ID': 1464,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ASIGNAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ASSIGN'
},
{
'ID': 1465,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONVOCAR UNA REUNIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO CALL A MEETING'
},
{
'ID': 1466,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EXIGIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO DEMAND'
},
{
'ID': 1467,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENFADARSE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO GET ANGRY'
},
{
'ID': 1468,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CARECER DE,FALTAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO LACK'
},
{
'ID': 1469,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PROMOCIONAR,PROMOVER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO PROMOTE'
},
{
'ID': 1470,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DEPENDER DE (JERÁRQUICO)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO REPORT TO'
},
{
'ID': 1471,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SONREÍR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SMILE'
},
{
'ID': 1472,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PENSAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO THINK'
},
{
'ID': 1473,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PESARSE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO WEIGH'
},
{
'ID': 1474,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'JUNTOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TOGETHER'
},
{
'ID': 1475,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'YA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ALREADY'
},
{
'ID': 1476,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ATRACTIVO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ATTRACTIVE'
},
{
'ID': 1477,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BENEFICIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BENEFIT'
},
{
'ID': 1478,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CUIDADOSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CAREFUL'
},
{
'ID': 1479,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CRUCIAL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CRUCIAL'
},
{
'ID': 1480,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENTORNO,MEDIO AMBIENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ENVIRONMENT'
},
{
'ID': 1481,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GRACIOSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FUNNY'
},
{
'ID': 1482,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EN GENERAL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IN GENERAL'
},
{
'ID': 1483,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MENSAJE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MESSAGE'
},
{
'ID': 1484,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PRIORIDAD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PRIORITY'
},
{
'ID': 1485,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RARAMENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SELDOM'
},
{
'ID': 1486,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LA COMPETENCIA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THE COMPETITION'
},
{
'ID': 1487,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LA LUNA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THE MOON'
},
{
'ID': 1488,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AYUDAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ASSIST'
},
{
'ID': 1489,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FACTURAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BILL'
},
{
'ID': 1490,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SOPLAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BLOW'
},
{
'ID': 1491,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LLEVAR A CABO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO CARRY OUT'
},
{
'ID': 1492,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESCRIBIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO DESCRIBE'
},
{
'ID': 1493,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LLEGAR DE REGRESO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO GET BACK'
},
{
'ID': 1494,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'REÍRSE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO LAUGH'
},
{
'ID': 1495,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PROTEGER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO PROTECT'
},
{
'ID': 1496,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESCANSAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO REST'
},
{
'ID': 1497,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SELECCIONAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SELECT'
},
{
'ID': 1498,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RESOLVER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SOLVE'
},
{
'ID': 1499,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TOCAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO TOUCH'
},
{
'ID': 1500,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CANTIDAD,IMPORTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AMOUNT'
},
{
'ID': 1501,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ANTES DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BEFORE'
},
{
'ID': 1502,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HUESO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BONE'
},
{
'ID': 1503,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CERCA DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CLOSE TO'
},
{
'ID': 1504,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PROFUNDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DEEP'
},
{
'ID': 1505,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EXPERTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EXPERT'
},
{
'ID': 1506,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESPERANZA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HOPE'
},
{
'ID': 1507,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PROBABLE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LIKELY'
},
{
'ID': 1508,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VECINO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NEIGHBOUR'
},
{
'ID': 1509,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SOBRINO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NEPHEW'
},
{
'ID': 1510,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PODER,POTENCIA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'POWER'
},
{
'ID': 1511,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SUELDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SALARY'
},
{
'ID': 1512,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EL COSTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THE COST'
},
{
'ID': 1513,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESTAR DE BUEN HUMOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BE IN A GOOD MOOD'
},
{
'ID': 1514,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'QUEJARSE DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO COMPLAIN ABOUT'
},
{
'ID': 1515,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HACER HINCAPIÉ EN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO EMPHASIS'
},
{
'ID': 1516,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BAJARSE DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO GET OFF'
},
{
'ID': 1517,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SALIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO GO OUT'
},
{
'ID': 1518,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CRECER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO GROW'
},
{
'ID': 1519,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PRESTAR ATENCIÓN A',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO PAY ATTENTION TO'
},
{
'ID': 1520,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RELAJARSE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO RELAX'
},
{
'ID': 1521,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SIMPLIFICAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SIMPLIFY'
},
{
'ID': 1522,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'QUITARSE (ROPA)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO TAKE OFF'
},
{
'ID': 1523,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FEO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'UGLY'
},
{
'ID': 1524,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PESO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WEIGHT'
},
{
'ID': 1525,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'OTRA VEZ',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AGAIN'
},
{
'ID': 1526,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'UNA OFERTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AN OFFER'
},
{
'ID': 1527,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DISPONIBLE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AVAILABLE'
},
{
'ID': 1528,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BRASIL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BRAZIL'
},
{
'ID': 1529,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'OPORTUNIDAD,POSIBILIDAD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CHANCE'
},
{
'ID': 1530,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CLIENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CUSTOMER'
},
{
'ID': 1531,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TODO EL MUNDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EVERYONE'
},
{
'ID': 1532,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GENERALMENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GENERALLY'
},
{
'ID': 1533,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'A PESAR DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IN SPITE OF'
},
{
'ID': 1534,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ERROR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MISTAKE'
},
{
'ID': 1535,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DE VEZ EN CUANDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NOW AND THEN'
},
{
'ID': 1536,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CARRERA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RACE'
},
{
'ID': 1537,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SENCILLO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SIMPLE'
},
{
'ID': 1538,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EXTRAÑO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'STRANGE'
},
{
'ID': 1539,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SUGERENCIA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SUGGESTION'
},
{
'ID': 1540,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LLEGAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ARRIVE'
},
{
'ID': 1541,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'QUEMAR,ARDER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BURN'
},
{
'ID': 1542,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DEFENDER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO DEFEND'
},
{
'ID': 1543,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'OLVIDAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO FORGET'
},
{
'ID': 1544,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'QUEDAR CON,GUARDAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO KEEP'
},
{
'ID': 1545,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PROMETER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO PROMISE'
},
{
'ID': 1546,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EMPUJAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PUSH'
},
{
'ID': 1547,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ALQUILAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO RENT'
},
{
'ID': 1548,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'OLER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SMELL'
},
{
'ID': 1549,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CUIDAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO TAKE CARE OF'
},
{
'ID': 1550,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENFADADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ANGRY'
},
{
'ID': 1551,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TIMBRE,CAMPANA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BELL'
},
{
'ID': 1552,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PORTAFOLIOS,CARTERA,MALETÍN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BRIEFCASE'
},
{
'ID': 1553,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BRITÁNICO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BRITISH'
},
{
'ID': 1554,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ELECCIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CHOICE'
},
{
'ID': 1555,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FECHA TOPE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DEADLINE'
},
{
'ID': 1556,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TODO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EVERYTHING'
},
{
'ID': 1557,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AGRADECIDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GRATEFUL'
},
{
'ID': 1558,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INCAPAZ DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'INCAPABLE OF'
},
{
'ID': 1559,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AGRADABLE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NICE'
},
{
'ID': 1560,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DE VERDAD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'REALLY'
},
{
'ID': 1561,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ALGÚN DIA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SOMEDAY'
},
{
'ID': 1562,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EL OTRO DIA...',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THE OTHER DAY...'
},
{
'ID': 1563,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESTAR DE MAL HUMOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BE IN A BAD MOOD'
},
{
'ID': 1564,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CAMBIAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO CHANGE'
},
{
'ID': 1565,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COMPROBAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO CHECK'
},
{
'ID': 1566,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DEDICAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO DEVOTE'
},
{
'ID': 1567,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MEJORAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO GET BETTER'
},
{
'ID': 1568,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MARCHARSE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO LEAVE'
},
{
'ID': 1569,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DEMOSTRAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO PROVE'
},
{
'ID': 1570,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DEJAR,ABANDONAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO QUIT'
},
{
'ID': 1571,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'JUBILARSE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO RETIRE'
},
{
'ID': 1572,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESPECIFICAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SPECIFY'
},
{
'ID': 1573,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'APAGAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO TURN OFF'
},
{
'ID': 1574,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EQUIVOCADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WRONG'
},
{
'ID': 1575,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CUALQUIERA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ANYBODY'
},
{
'ID': 1576,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CINTURÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BELT'
},
{
'ID': 1577,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MOQUETA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CARPET'
},
{
'ID': 1578,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COMPROMISO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'COMMITMENT'
},
{
'ID': 1579,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DECISIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DECISION'
},
{
'ID': 1580,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EXCELENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EXCELLENT'
},
{
'ID': 1581,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CORAZÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HEART'
},
{
'ID': 1582,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONOCIMIENTOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'KNOWLEDGE'
},
{
'ID': 1583,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PUNTUAL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ON TIME'
},
{
'ID': 1584,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PAQUETE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PACKAGE'
},
{
'ID': 1585,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DOLOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PAIN'
},
{
'ID': 1586,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RAZONABLE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'REASONABLE'
},
{
'ID': 1587,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DISCURSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SPEECH'
},
{
'ID': 1588,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EL MUNDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THE WORLD'
},
{
'ID': 1589,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TENER SUERTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BE LUCKY'
},
{
'ID': 1590,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COMPARAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO COMPARE'
},
{
'ID': 1591,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GANAR (TRABAJANDO)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO EARN'
},
{
'ID': 1592,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PREPARASE PARA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO GET READY FOR'
},
{
'ID': 1593,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PRESTAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO LEND'
},
{
'ID': 1594,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TIRAR (CONTRARIO DE EMPUJAR)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO PULL'
},
{
'ID': 1595,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'REVISAR,REPASAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO REVIEW'
},
{
'ID': 1596,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SEGUIR EN CONTACTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'STAY IN TOUCH'
},
{
'ID': 1597,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ACTUALIZAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO UPDATE'
},
{
'ID': 1598,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SEMÁFORO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TRAFFIC LIGHT'
},
{
'ID': 1599,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TÍPICO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TYPICAL'
},
{
'ID': 1600,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EN CUALQUIER SITO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ANYPLACE'
},
{
'ID': 1601,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FACTURA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BILL'
},
{
'ID': 1602,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CALDERILLA,CAMBIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CHANGE'
},
{
'ID': 1603,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CIRCULO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CIRCLE'
},
{
'ID': 1604,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONFIANZA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CONFIDENCE'
},
{
'ID': 1605,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SECO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DRY'
},
{
'ID': 1606,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AMISTAD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FRIENDSHIP'
},
{
'ID': 1607,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TIERRA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LAND'
},
{
'ID': 1608,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PERSONAL DE PLANTILLA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PERSONAL'
},
{
'ID': 1609,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'POSIBILIDAD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'POSSIBILITY'
},
{
'ID': 1610,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PROCESO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PROCESS'
},
{
'ID': 1611,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TEJADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ROOF'
},
{
'ID': 1612,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESTILO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'STYLE'
},
{
'ID': 1613,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NOMBRAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO APPOINT'
},
{
'ID': 1614,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONSIDERAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO CONSIDER'
},
{
'ID': 1615,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DISFRUTAR DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ENJOY'
},
{
'ID': 1616,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GARANTIZAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO GUARANTEE'
},
{
'ID': 1617,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RECOGER (DEL SUELO)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO PICK UP'
},
{
'ID': 1618,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'QUITAR,EXTRAER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO REMOVE'
},
{
'ID': 1619,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ROBAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO STEAL'
},
{
'ID': 1620,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'APUNTAR,ANOTAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO WRITE DOWN'
},
{
'ID': 1621,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EL PARO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'UNEMPLOYMENT'
},
{
'ID': 1622,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VALOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'VALUE'
},
{
'ID': 1623,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENTERO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WHOLE'
},
{
'ID': 1624,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PEOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WORST'
},
{
'ID': 1625,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EN CUALQUIER SITIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ANYWHERE'
},
{
'ID': 1626,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ADEMÁS,ADEMÁS DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BESIDES'
},
{
'ID': 1627,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LISTO,ASTUTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CLEVER'
},
{
'ID': 1628,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NUBE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CLOUD'
},
{
'ID': 1629,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COMPAÑÍA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'COMPANY'
},
{
'ID': 1630,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DETALLE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DETAIL'
},
{
'ID': 1631,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GASTOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EXPENSES'
},
{
'ID': 1632,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ALTURA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HEIGHT'
},
{
'ID': 1633,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'IMAGINACIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IMAGINATION'
},
{
'ID': 1634,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GERENTE,DIRECTOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MANAGER'
},
{
'ID': 1635,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PRESIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PRESSURE'
},
{
'ID': 1636,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PROMESA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PROMISE'
},
{
'ID': 1637,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TRANQUILAMENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'QUIETLY'
},
{
'ID': 1638,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SEGURIDAD FÍSICA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SAFETY'
},
{
'ID': 1639,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DE ÉXITO,EXITOSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SUCCESSFUL'
},
{
'ID': 1640,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PERMITIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ALLOW'
},
{
'ID': 1641,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PEDIR PRESTADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BORROW'
},
{
'ID': 1642,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CRITICAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO CRITICIZE'
},
{
'ID': 1643,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESTIMAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ESTIMATE'
},
{
'ID': 1644,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MANTENER UNA REUNIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO HOLD A MEETING'
},
{
'ID': 1645,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MEDIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO MEASURE'
},
{
'ID': 1646,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LLEGAR A UN ACUERDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO REACH AN AGREEMENT'
},
{
'ID': 1647,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AHORRAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SAVE'
},
{
'ID': 1648,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SUGERIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SUGGEST'
},
{
'ID': 1649,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DIA DE LA SEMANA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LABORAL WEEKDAY'
},
{
'ID': 1650,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'POR LO VISTO,AL PARECER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'APPARENTLY'
},
{
'ID': 1651,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'JEFE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BOSS'
},
{
'ID': 1652,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PASE USTED',
        'RESPUESTA': 'COME IN'
},
{
'ID': 1653,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COMPETENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'COMPETENT'
},
{
'ID': 1654,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DUDA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DOUBT'
},
{
'ID': 1655,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EXPLICACIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EXPLANATION'
},
{
'ID': 1656,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AGUJERO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HOLE'
},
{
'ID': 1657,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VAGO,PEREZOSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LAZY'
},
{
'ID': 1658,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PINTURA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PAINTING'
},
{
'ID': 1659,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RECIENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RECENT'
},
{
'ID': 1660,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RESPETO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RESPECT'
},
{
'ID': 1661,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SERIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SERIOUS'
},
{
'ID': 1662,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ETAPA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'STAGE'
},
{
'ID': 1663,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EL PEOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THE WORST'
},
{
'ID': 1664,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SUPONER,ASUMIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ASSUME'
},
{
'ID': 1665,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SER PESIMISTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BE PESSIMISTIC'
},
{
'ID': 1666,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TRAER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BRING'
},
{
'ID': 1667,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CRUZAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO CROSS'
},
{
'ID': 1668,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FRACASAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO FAIL'
},
{
'ID': 1669,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INVITAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO INVITE'
},
{
'ID': 1670,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'OFENDER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO OFFEND'
},
{
'ID': 1671,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PRESIONAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO PRESSURE'
},
{
'ID': 1672,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'REFERIRSE A',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO REFER TO'
},
{
'ID': 1673,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VENDER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SELL'
},
{
'ID': 1674,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SORPRENDER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SURPRISE'
},
{
'ID': 1675,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ASPECTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ASPECT'
},
{
'ID': 1676,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NEGOCIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BUSINESS'
},
{
'ID': 1677,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COSTUMBRE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CUSTOM'
},
{
'ID': 1678,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PELIGRO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DANGER'
},
{
'ID': 1679,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DIBUJO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DRAWING'
},
{
'ID': 1680,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FLEXIBLE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FLEXIBLE'
},
{
'ID': 1681,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VIDA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LIFE'
},
{
'ID': 1682,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'POBLACIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'POPULATION'
},
{
'ID': 1683,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESDE QUE,PUESTO QUE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SINCE'
},
{
'ID': 1684,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PIEL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SKIN'
},
{
'ID': 1685,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HISTORIA,CUENTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'STORY'
},
{
'ID': 1686,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESTAR DE ACUERDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO AGREE'
},
{
'ID': 1687,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PONERSE EN CONTACTO CON',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO CONTACT'
},
{
'ID': 1688,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESTABLECER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ESTABLISH'
},
{
'ID': 1689,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DEJAR,PERMITIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO LET'
},
{
'ID': 1690,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ALCANZAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO REACH'
},
{
'ID': 1691,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SERVIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SERVE'
},
{
'ID': 1692,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESPERDICIAR,MALGASTAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO WASTE'
},
{
'ID': 1693,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TOTALMENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TOTALLY'
},
{
'ID': 1694,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TRATAMIENTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TREATMENT'
},
{
'ID': 1695,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INESPERADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'UNEXPECTED'
},
{
'ID': 1696,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HASTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'UNTIL'
},
{
'ID': 1697,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DÉBIL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WEAK'
},
{
'ID': 1698,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': '¿QUÉ PASA?',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WHAT\'S THE MATTER?'
},
{
'ID': 1699,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MADERA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WOOD'
},
{
'ID': 1700,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AL PRINCIPIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AT FIRST'
},
{
'ID': 1701,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONFIRMACIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CONFIRMATION'
},
{
'ID': 1702,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DEFINICIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DEFINITION'
},
{
'ID': 1703,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GRADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DEGREE'
},
{
'ID': 1704,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GRAN ALMACÉN (centro comercial)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DEPARTMENT STORE'
},
{
'ID': 1705,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DURANTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DURING'
},
{
'ID': 1706,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ME ALEGRO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'I\'M GLAD'
},
{
'ID': 1707,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PÉRDIDA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LOSS'
},
{
'ID': 1708,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RIESGO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RISK'
},
{
'ID': 1709,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FUERZA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'STRENGTH'
},
{
'ID': 1710,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TONTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'STUPID'
},
{
'ID': 1711,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LA ENSEÑANZA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TEACHING'
},
{
'ID': 1712,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COMENZAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BEGIN'
},
{
'ID': 1713,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COPIAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO COPY'
},
{
'ID': 1714,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONSEGUIR RESULTADOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO GET RESULTS'
},
{
'ID': 1715,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MANTENER (teoría, hipótesis)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO MAINTAIN'
},
{
'ID': 1716,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESTROPEAR (frustrar, malograr)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO RUIN'
},
{
'ID': 1717,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TENER ÉXITO,TRIUNFAR (una persona)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SUCCEED'
},
{
'ID': 1718,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DURO,DIFÍCIL (carne, examen)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TOUGH'
},
{
'ID': 1719,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PROBLEMAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TROUBLE'
},
{
'ID': 1720,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESAFORTUNADAMENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'UNFORTUNATELY'
},
{
'ID': 1721,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INÚTIL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'USELESS'
},
{
'ID': 1722,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': '¿QUE QUIERES DECIR?',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WHAT DO YOU MEAN?'
},
{
'ID': 1723,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DENTRO DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WITHIN'
},
{
'ID': 1724,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PREOCUPADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WORRIED'
},
{
'ID': 1725,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FONDO,PARTE INFERIOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BOTTOM'
},
{
'ID': 1726,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CURSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'COURSE'
},
{
'ID': 1727,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESIERTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DESERT'
},
{
'ID': 1728,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SUEÑO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DREAM'
},
{
'ID': 1729,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FAMOSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FAMOUS'
},
{
'ID': 1730,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CAMPO (ámbito)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FIELD'
},
{
'ID': 1731,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HIELO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ICE'
},
{
'ID': 1732,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AGRADABLE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PLEASANT'
},
{
'ID': 1733,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SEGURO,LIBRE DE PELIGRO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SAFE'
},
{
'ID': 1734,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LA PARTE FRONTAL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THE FRONT'
},
{
'ID': 1735,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LAS NOTICIAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THE NEWS'
},
{
'ID': 1736,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DELGADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THIN'
},
{
'ID': 1737,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BENEFICIARSE DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BENEFIT FROM'
},
{
'ID': 1738,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ELIMINAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ELIMINATE'
},
{
'ID': 1739,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DEVOLVER (cosa prestada)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO GET BACK'
},
{
'ID': 1740,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PONERSE (ROPA)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO PUT ON'
},
{
'ID': 1741,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SATISFACER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SATISFY'
},
{
'ID': 1742,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'APROVECHAR (la situación)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO TAKE ADVANTAGE OF'
},
{
'ID': 1743,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ATASCO DE TRAFICO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TRAFFIC JAM'
},
{
'ID': 1744,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VERDADERO,VERDAD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TRUE'
},
{
'ID': 1745,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'IMPROBABLE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'UNLIKELY'
},
{
'ID': 1746,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VISTA (perspectiva, panorama)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'VIEW'
},
{
'ID': 1747,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': '¿QUÉ CLASE DE...?',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WHAT KIND OF...?'
},
{
'ID': 1748,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MARAVILLOSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WONDERFUL'
},
{
'ID': 1749,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PEOR QUE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WORSE THAN'
},
{
'ID': 1750,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ASCENSOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ELEVATOR'
},
{
'ID': 1751,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENTRADA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ENTRANCE'
},
{
'ID': 1752,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EQUIPAMIENTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EQUIPMENT'
},
{
'ID': 1753,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HACIA DELANTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FORWARD'
},
{
'ID': 1754,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FRECUENTEMENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FREQUENTLY'
},
{
'ID': 1755,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ORO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GOLD'
},
{
'ID': 1756,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LA GRAMÁTICA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GRAMMAR'
},
{
'ID': 1757,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GRAN BRETAÑA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GREAT BRITAIN'
},
{
'ID': 1758,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ARMA DE FUEGO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GUN'
},
{
'ID': 1759,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GUAPO,APUESTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HANDSOME'
},
{
'ID': 1760,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'APENAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HARDLY'
},
{
'ID': 1761,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'IDÉNTICO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IDENTICAL'
},
{
'ID': 1762,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'IRLANDA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IRELAND'
},
{
'ID': 1763,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CHISTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'JOKE'
},
{
'ID': 1764,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GRANDE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LARGE'
},
{
'ID': 1765,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LECHUGA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LETTUCE'
},
{
'ID': 1766,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BAJO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LOW'
},
{
'ID': 1767,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LA COSTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THE COST'
},
{
'ID': 1768,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HACER PUBLICIDAD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ADVERTISE'
},
{
'ID': 1769,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AYUDAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO AID'
},
{
'ID': 1770,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MORDER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BITE'
},
{
'ID': 1771,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COMPLETAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO COMPLETE'
},
{
'ID': 1772,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GANAR,ADQUIRIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO GAIN'
},
{
'ID': 1773,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CASARSE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO GET MARRIED'
},
{
'ID': 1774,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INSISTIR EN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO INSIST ON'
},
{
'ID': 1775,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INGENIERO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ENGINEER'
},
{
'ID': 1776,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VUELO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FLIGHT'
},
{
'ID': 1777,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONGELADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FROZEN'
},
{
'ID': 1778,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SIGNIFICADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MEANING'
},
{
'ID': 1779,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SUEGRA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MOTHER IN LAW'
},
{
'ID': 1780,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MEDIODÍA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NOON'
},
{
'ID': 1781,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DE VEZ EN CUANDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'OCCASIONALLY'
},
{
'ID': 1782,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PROPIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'OWN'
},
{
'ID': 1783,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PASAJERO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PASSENGER'
},
{
'ID': 1784,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PASTILLAS,PÍLDORA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PILL'
},
{
'ID': 1785,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'POSIBLEMENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'POSSIBLY'
},
{
'ID': 1786,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PRODUCTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PRODUCT'
},
{
'ID': 1787,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PARIENTES',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RELATIVES'
},
{
'ID': 1788,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DUCHA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SHOWER'
},
{
'ID': 1789,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SILENCIOSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SILENT'
},
{
'ID': 1790,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EN ALGUNA PARTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SOMEONE'
},
{
'ID': 1791,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ORTOGRAFÍA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SPELLING'
},
{
'ID': 1792,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DIENTES',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TEETH'
},
{
'ID': 1793,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EXAMEN,ENSAYO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TEST'
},
{
'ID': 1794,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'OBTENER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO OBTAIN'
},
{
'ID': 1795,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SUFRIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SUFFER'
},
{
'ID': 1796,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TURISMO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TOURISM'
},
{
'ID': 1797,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TÍPICAMENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TYPICALLY'
},
{
'ID': 1798,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GUERRA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WAR'
},
{
'ID': 1799,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 2,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SIN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WITHOUT'
},
{
'ID': 1800,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'UNA CALLE DE DOBLE SENTIDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'A TWO-WAY STREET'
},
{
'ID': 1801,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ANUNCIO (EN PRENSA)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AD'
},
{
'ID': 1802,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ADVERSARIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ADVERSARY'
},
{
'ID': 1803,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BICHO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BUG'
},
{
'ID': 1804,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESCUETO,CONCISO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CONCISE'
},
{
'ID': 1805,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INGENIERÍA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ENGINEERING'
},
{
'ID': 1806,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PROHIBIDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FORBIDDEN'
},
{
'ID': 1807,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CALOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HEAT'
},
{
'ID': 1808,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESCONDIDO,OCULTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HIDDEN'
},
{
'ID': 1809,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'IMPARCIAL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IMPARTIAL'
},
{
'ID': 1810,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'IMPACIENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IMPATIENT'
},
{
'ID': 1811,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CLASE MEDIA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MIDDLE CLASS'
},
{
'ID': 1812,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MISTERIOSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MYSTERIOUS'
},
{
'ID': 1813,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PESIMISTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PESSIMISTIC'
},
{
'ID': 1814,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'IMPORTANTE,SIGNIFICATIVO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SIGNIFICANT'
},
{
'ID': 1815,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SINCERIDAD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SINCERITY'
},
{
'ID': 1816,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESTRATÉGICO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'STRATEGIC'
},
{
'ID': 1817,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AFECTAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO AFFECT'
},
{
'ID': 1818,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DICTAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO DICTATE'
},
{
'ID': 1819,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PROHIBIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO FORBID'
},
{
'ID': 1820,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'IMPRESIONAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO IMPRESS'
},
{
'ID': 1821,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COSER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SEW'
},
{
'ID': 1822,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AGRADECER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO THANK'
},
{
'ID': 1823,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DAR LA BIENVENIDA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO WELCOME'
},
{
'ID': 1824,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RARO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'UNCOMMON'
},
{
'ID': 1825,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ABUNDANTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ABUNDANT'
},
{
'ID': 1826,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CARIÑOSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AFFECTIONATE'
},
{
'ID': 1827,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ASI COMO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AS WELL AS'
},
{
'ID': 1828,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DURMIENDO,DORMIDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ASLEEP'
},
{
'ID': 1829,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'JAULA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CAGE'
},
{
'ID': 1830,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CALEFACCIÓN CENTRAL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CENTRAL HEATING'
},
{
'ID': 1831,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FRESCO (TEMPERATURA)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'COOL'
},
{
'ID': 1832,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FANÁTICO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FANATIC'
},
{
'ID': 1833,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BASURA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GARBAGE'
},
{
'ID': 1834,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MIEL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HONEY'
},
{
'ID': 1835,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'POR ADELANTADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IN ADVANCE'
},
{
'ID': 1836,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MIENTRAS TANTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IN THE MEANTIME'
},
{
'ID': 1837,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LONGITUD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LENGTH'
},
{
'ID': 1838,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MEDIANOCHE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MIDNIGHT'
},
{
'ID': 1839,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NATIVO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NATIVE'
},
{
'ID': 1840,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PSICOLÓGICO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PSYCHOLOGICAL'
},
{
'ID': 1841,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FRESAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'STRAWBERRIES'
},
{
'ID': 1842,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AGRADECIDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THANKFUL'
},
{
'ID': 1843,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LOGRAR,LLEVAR A CABO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ACCOMPLISH'
},
{
'ID': 1844,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESAPARECER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO DISAPPEAR'
},
{
'ID': 1845,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FLUIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO FLOW'
},
{
'ID': 1846,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'OBLIGAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO FORCE'
},
{
'ID': 1847,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'REPARAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO REPAIR'
},
{
'ID': 1848,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HUNDIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SINK'
},
{
'ID': 1849,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DEBAJO DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'UNDERNEATH'
},
{
'ID': 1850,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ADECUADAMENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ADEQUATELY'
},
{
'ID': 1851,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AGRESIVO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AGGRESSIVE'
},
{
'ID': 1852,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NACIMIENTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BIRTH'
},
{
'ID': 1853,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MANTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BLANKET'
},
{
'ID': 1854,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PRESUPUESTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BUDGET'
},
{
'ID': 1855,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ELEGANTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ELEGANT'
},
{
'ID': 1856,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TEMOR,MIEDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FEAR'
},
{
'ID': 1857,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FRUSTRANTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FRUSTRATING'
},
{
'ID': 1858,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LUNA DE MIEL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HONEYMOON'
},
{
'ID': 1859,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EN TEORÍA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IN THEORY'
},
{
'ID': 1860,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NATURALMENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NATURALLY'
},
{
'ID': 1861,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PREDOMINANTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PREDOMINANT'
},
{
'ID': 1862,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TRIMESTRALMENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'QUARTERLY'
},
{
'ID': 1863,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MAQUINA DE COSER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SEWING MACHINE'
},
{
'ID': 1864,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESTRICTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'STRICT'
},
{
'ID': 1865,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ASEGURAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ASSURE'
},
{
'ID': 1866,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COBRAR,CARGAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO CHARGE'
},
{
'ID': 1867,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONTENER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO CONTAIN'
},
{
'ID': 1868,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESCUBRIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO DISCOVER'
},
{
'ID': 1869,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PREVER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO FORECAST'
},
{
'ID': 1870,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MANTENER UNA REUNIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO HOLD A MEETING'
},
{
'ID': 1871,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SALTAR,OMITIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SKIP'
},
{
'ID': 1872,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SEGUIR EN CONTACTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO STAY IN TOUCH'
},
{
'ID': 1873,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ROPA INTERIOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'UNDERWEAR'
},
{
'ID': 1874,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BIENESTAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WELL-BEING'
},
{
'ID': 1875,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VENTAJOSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ADVANTAGEOUS'
},
{
'ID': 1876,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FOLLETO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BROCHURE'
},
{
'ID': 1877,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': '¡ENHORABUENA!',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CONGRATULATIONS!'
},
{
'ID': 1878,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONSIDERABLE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CONSIDERABLE'
},
{
'ID': 1879,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SALIDA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DEPARTURE'
},
{
'ID': 1880,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LIBERTAD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FREEDOM'
},
{
'ID': 1881,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AJO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GARLIC'
},
{
'ID': 1882,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'OFICINA CENTRAL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HEADQUARTERS'
},
{
'ID': 1883,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'IMPLANTACIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IMPLEMENTATION'
},
{
'ID': 1884,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'IMPRESCINDIBLE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'INDISPENSABLE'
},
{
'ID': 1885,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NECESIDAD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NECESSITY'
},
{
'ID': 1886,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PREDECIBLE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PREDICTABLE'
},
{
'ID': 1887,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PROMINENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PROMINENT'
},
{
'ID': 1888,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SENTIDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SENSE'
},
{
'ID': 1889,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESCLAVO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SLAVE'
},
{
'ID': 1890,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AUNQUE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THOUGH'
},
{
'ID': 1891,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MERECER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO DESERVE'
},
{
'ID': 1892,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EXTENDER,PRORROGAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO EXTEND'
},
{
'ID': 1893,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CUMPLIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO FULFILL'
},
{
'ID': 1894,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DECLARARSE EN HUELGA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO GO ON STRIKE'
},
{
'ID': 1895,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CAZAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO HUNT'
},
{
'ID': 1896,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HACER DAÑO,DOLER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO HURT'
},
{
'ID': 1897,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INDICAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO INDICATE'
},
{
'ID': 1898,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EN PARO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'UNEMPLOYED'
},
{
'ID': 1899,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FAMOSO,CONOCIDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WELL-KNOWN'
},
{
'ID': 1900,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'UNA PERDIDA DE TIEMPO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'A WASTE OF TIME'
},
{
'ID': 1901,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AYUDA,AUXILIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AID'
},
{
'ID': 1902,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COMPORTAMIENTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BEHAVIOR'
},
{
'ID': 1903,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MANDÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BOSSY'
},
{
'ID': 1904,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COMPARABLE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'COMPARABLE'
},
{
'ID': 1905,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HECHO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FACT'
},
{
'ID': 1906,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FORMATO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FORMAT'
},
{
'ID': 1907,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RAYO,RELÁMPAGO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LIGHTNING'
},
{
'ID': 1908,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NERVIOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NERVES'
},
{
'ID': 1909,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DOLOROSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PAINFUL'
},
{
'ID': 1910,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SOMBRA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SHADE'
},
{
'ID': 1911,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DORMIDO,CON SUEÑO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SLEEPY'
},
{
'ID': 1912,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AMENAZA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THREAT'
},
{
'ID': 1913,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LOGRAR,CONSEGUIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ACHIEVE'
},
{
'ID': 1914,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESTAR EN HUELGA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BE ON STRIKE'
},
{
'ID': 1915,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ECHAR LA CULPA A',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BLAME'
},
{
'ID': 1916,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FORMAR ACADÉMICAMENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO EDUCATE'
},
{
'ID': 1917,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LUCHAR,PELEAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO FIGHT'
},
{
'ID': 1918,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FLOTAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO FLOAT'
},
{
'ID': 1919,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DOBLAR,PLEGAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO FOLD'
},
{
'ID': 1920,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENGORDAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO GAIN WEIGHT'
},
{
'ID': 1921,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GUIAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO GUIDE'
},
{
'ID': 1922,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'IMPLANTAR,PONER EN MARCHA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO IMPLEMENT'
},
{
'ID': 1923,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESAFORTUNADAMENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'UNFORTUNATELY'
},
{
'ID': 1924,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BALLENA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WHALE'
},
{
'ID': 1925,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'UNA GRABACIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'A RECORDING'
},
{
'ID': 1926,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ÁGIL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AGILE'
},
{
'ID': 1927,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EMBAJADOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AMBASSADOR'
},
{
'ID': 1928,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESCUIDADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CARELESS'
},
{
'ID': 1929,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NUBLADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CLOUDY'
},
{
'ID': 1930,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EFICIENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EFFICIENT'
},
{
'ID': 1931,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CARA A CARA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FACE-TO-FACE'
},
{
'ID': 1932,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PLENA JORNADA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FULL TIME'
},
{
'ID': 1933,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'IDEAL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IDEAL'
},
{
'ID': 1934,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INCIDENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'INCIDENT'
},
{
'ID': 1935,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ÍNDICE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'INDEX'
},
{
'ID': 1936,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EN PRINCIPIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'INITIALLY'
},
{
'ID': 1937,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INTENSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'INTENSE'
},
{
'ID': 1938,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MANO DE OBRA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LABOR'
},
{
'ID': 1939,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COMIDA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MEAL'
},
{
'ID': 1940,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NORUEGA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NORWAY'
},
{
'ID': 1941,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'A PIE,ANDANDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ON FOOT'
},
{
'ID': 1942,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PRECEDENTE,ANTERIOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PRECEDING'
},
{
'ID': 1943,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': '¿Y QUE?',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SO WHAT?'
},
{
'ID': 1944,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'A LO LARGO Y ANCHO DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THROUGHOUT'
},
{
'ID': 1945,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RESERVAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BOOK'
},
{
'ID': 1946,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TEMER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO FEAR'
},
{
'ID': 1947,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INFLUIR EN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO INFLUENCE'
},
{
'ID': 1948,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ÚNICO EN SU GENERO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'UNIQUE'
},
{
'ID': 1949,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TRIGO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WHEAT'
},
{
'ID': 1950,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PRECISO,EXACTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ACCURATE'
},
{
'ID': 1951,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DECISIVO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DECISIVE'
},
{
'ID': 1952,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESTINO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DESTINATION'
},
{
'ID': 1953,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EMBAJADA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EMBASSY'
},
{
'ID': 1954,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VENTILADOR,ABANICO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FAN'
},
{
'ID': 1955,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'OLVIDADIZO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FORGETFUL'
},
{
'ID': 1956,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FRÁGIL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FRAGILE'
},
{
'ID': 1957,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DOLOR DE CABEZA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HEADACHE'
},
{
'ID': 1958,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'IDENTIDAD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IDENTITY'
},
{
'ID': 1959,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INCOMPETENCIA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'INCOMPETENCE'
},
{
'ID': 1960,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INICIATIVA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'INITIATIVE'
},
{
'ID': 1961,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MENTIROSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LIAR'
},
{
'ID': 1962,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ASUNTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MATTER'
},
{
'ID': 1963,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ALCALDE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MAYOR'
},
{
'ID': 1964,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NORUEGO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NORWEGIAN'
},
{
'ID': 1965,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LIGERAMENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SLIGHTLY'
},
{
'ID': 1966,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MALETA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SUITCASE'
},
{
'ID': 1967,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TRUENO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THUNDER'
},
{
'ID': 1968,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'APOSTAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BET'
},
{
'ID': 1969,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DAR DE COMER,ALIMENTAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO FEED'
},
{
'ID': 1970,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CABER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO FIT'
},
{
'ID': 1971,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MENTIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO LIE'
},
{
'ID': 1972,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AGITAR,TEMBLAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SHAKE'
},
{
'ID': 1973,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'UNIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO UNITE'
},
{
'ID': 1974,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SI',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WHETHER'
},
{
'ID': 1975,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MUCHO,UNA GRAN CANTIDAD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'A GREAT DEAL OF'
},
{
'ID': 1976,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ANTEPASADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ANCESTOR'
},
{
'ID': 1977,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BILINGÜE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BILINGUAL'
},
{
'ID': 1978,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CUEVA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CAVE'
},
{
'ID': 1979,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PROFUNDAMENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DEEPLY'
},
{
'ID': 1980,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MARCO (DE UN CUADRO)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FRAME'
},
{
'ID': 1981,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SIMPÁTICO,AMIGABLE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FRIENDLY'
},
{
'ID': 1982,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'IDIOTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IDIOT'
},
{
'ID': 1983,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TINTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'INK'
},
{
'ID': 1984,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HORAS EXTRAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'OVERTIME'
},
{
'ID': 1985,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PARCIALMENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PARTIALLY'
},
{
'ID': 1986,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PREFERIBLE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PREFERABLE'
},
{
'ID': 1987,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PREMATURO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PREMATURE'
},
{
'ID': 1988,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PRESTIGIOSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PRESTIGIOUS'
},
{
'ID': 1989,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PRETEXTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PRETEXT'
},
{
'ID': 1990,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RESISTENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RESISTANT'
},
{
'ID': 1991,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RIDICULO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RIDICULOUS'
},
{
'ID': 1992,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SERIE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SERIES'
},
{
'ID': 1993,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESBELTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SLIM'
},
{
'ID': 1994,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SUMA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SUM'
},
{
'ID': 1995,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LA TIERRA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THE EARTH'
},
{
'ID': 1996,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PENSAR HACER,PROGRAMAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO PLAN'
},
{
'ID': 1997,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ATAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO TIE'
},
{
'ID': 1998,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESCONOCIDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'UNKNOWN'
},
{
'ID': 1999,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VIUDA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WIDOW'
},
{
'ID': 2000,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'UN ATAJO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'A SHORTCUT'
},
{
'ID': 2001,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DISCIPLINA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DISCIPLINE'
},
{
'ID': 2002,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PARA SIEMPRE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FOREVER'
},
{
'ID': 2003,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PASTOR ALEMÁN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GERMAN SHEPHERD'
},
{
'ID': 2004,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CHISMORREO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GOSSIP'
},
{
'ID': 2005,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AURICULARES',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HEADPHONES'
},
{
'ID': 2006,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LÍDER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LEADER'
},
{
'ID': 2007,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CERCANO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NEARBY'
},
{
'ID': 2008,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SIMPLE,NATURAL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PLAIN'
},
{
'ID': 2009,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PRAGMÁTICO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PRAGMATIC'
},
{
'ID': 2010,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ARRIESGADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RISKY'
},
{
'ID': 2011,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESCÁNDALO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SCANDAL'
},
{
'ID': 2012,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LISTO,ELEGANTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SMART'
},
{
'ID': 2013,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RESUMEN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SUMMARY'
},
{
'ID': 2014,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'APRETADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TIGHT'
},
{
'ID': 2015,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EXPORTAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO EXPORT'
},
{
'ID': 2016,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ODIAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO HATE'
},
{
'ID': 2017,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DUDAR,VACILAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO HESITATE'
},
{
'ID': 2018,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INSPECCIONAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO INSPECT'
},
{
'ID': 2019,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LEVANTAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO LIFT'
},
{
'ID': 2020,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ECHAR DE MENOS,PERDER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO MISS'
},
{
'ID': 2021,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RECORDAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO RECALL'
},
{
'ID': 2022,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DAR LA MANO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SHAKE HANDS'
},
{
'ID': 2023,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'A NO SER QUE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'UNLESS'
},
{
'ID': 2024,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ANCHURA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WIDTH'
},
{
'ID': 2025,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CADA UNO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'APIECE'
},
{
'ID': 2026,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AVECES',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AT TIMES'
},
{
'ID': 2027,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NIÑEZ',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CHILDHOOD'
},
{
'ID': 2028,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CREATIVO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CREATIVE'
},
{
'ID': 2029,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DERROTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DEFEAT'
},
{
'ID': 2030,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESACUERDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DISAGREEMENT'
},
{
'ID': 2031,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EMPLEADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EMPLOYEE'
},
{
'ID': 2032,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BOSQUE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FOREST'
},
{
'ID': 2033,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EN CONTACTO CON',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IN CONTACT WITH'
},
{
'ID': 2034,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EN REALIDAD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IN REALITY'
},
{
'ID': 2035,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INTROVERTIDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'INTROVERTED'
},
{
'ID': 2036,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MAQUILLAJE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MAKEUP'
},
{
'ID': 2037,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FILOSÓFICO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PHILOSOPHICAL'
},
{
'ID': 2038,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'POTENCIAL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'POTENTIAL'
},
{
'ID': 2039,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PRÁCTICAMENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PRACTICALLY'
},
{
'ID': 2040,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AHORROS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SAVINGS'
},
{
'ID': 2041,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'POCO PROFUNDO,SOMERO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SHALLOW'
},
{
'ID': 2042,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'OLOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SMELL'
},
{
'ID': 2043,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SUPERFICIAL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SUPERFICIAL'
},
{
'ID': 2044,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENCENDER (CIGARRO,FUEGO)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO LIGHT'
},
{
'ID': 2045,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RELACIONAR EN UNA LISTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO LIST'
},
{
'ID': 2046,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LLEGAR A DOMINAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO MASTER'
},
{
'ID': 2047,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HACER LAS MALETAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO PACK'
},
{
'ID': 2048,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESCARGAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO UNLOAD'
},
{
'ID': 2049,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SALVAJE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WILD'
},
{
'ID': 2050,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'IRA,RABIA,ENFADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ANGER'
},
{
'ID': 2051,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'QUE YO SEPA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AS FAR AS I KNOW'
},
{
'ID': 2052,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EN CUALQUIER CASO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AT ANY RATE'
},
{
'ID': 2053,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AMARGO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BITTER'
},
{
'ID': 2054,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AVERIA,DESGLOSE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BREAKDOWN'
},
{
'ID': 2055,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BREVEMENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BRIEFLY'
},
{
'ID': 2056,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EMOCIONANTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EXCITING'
},
{
'ID': 2057,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FORTUNA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FORTUNE'
},
{
'ID': 2058,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FUNCIONAL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FUNCTIONAL'
},
{
'ID': 2059,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GITANO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GYPSY'
},
{
'ID': 2060,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INMEDIATO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IMMEDIATE'
},
{
'ID': 2061,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EQUIPAJE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LUGGAGE'
},
{
'ID': 2062,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EVIDENTE,OBVIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'OBVIOUS'
},
{
'ID': 2063,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'POBREZA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'POVERTY'
},
{
'ID': 2064,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PRACTICA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PRACTICE'
},
{
'ID': 2065,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BILLETE DE VUELTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RETURN TICKET'
},
{
'ID': 2066,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SONRISA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SMILE'
},
{
'ID': 2067,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SUMINISTRO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SUPPLY'
},
{
'ID': 2068,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SOLICITAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO APPLY FOR'
},
{
'ID': 2069,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESPERAR,PREVER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO EXPECT'
},
{
'ID': 2070,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INVENTAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO INVENT'
},
{
'ID': 2071,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CARGAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO LOAD'
},
{
'ID': 2072,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CUIDAR (DE ALGUIEN)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO LOOK AFTER'
},
{
'ID': 2073,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PARTICIPAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO PARTICIPATE'
},
{
'ID': 2074,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PERIODO DE PRUEBA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TRIAL PERIOD'
},
{
'ID': 2075,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ATRACTIVO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'APPEAL'
},
{
'ID': 2076,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MARCA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BRAND'
},
{
'ID': 2077,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PREOCUPADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CONCERNED'
},
{
'ID': 2078,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DAÑADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DAMAGED'
},
{
'ID': 2079,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ECONÓMICO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ECONOMIC'
},
{
'ID': 2080,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENVIDIOSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ENVIOUS'
},
{
'ID': 2081,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EMOCIONADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EXCITED'
},
{
'ID': 2082,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EXTRANJERO (ADJETIVO)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FOREIGN'
},
{
'ID': 2083,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ANFITRIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HOST'
},
{
'ID': 2084,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CAZADOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HUNTER'
},
{
'ID': 2085,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INMIGRANTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IMMIGRANT'
},
{
'ID': 2086,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INVENTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'INVENTION'
},
{
'ID': 2087,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MAQUINARIA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MACHINERY'
},
{
'ID': 2088,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PRINCIPALMENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MAINLY'
},
{
'ID': 2089,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MANTENIMIENTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MAINTENANCE'
},
{
'ID': 2090,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MEZCLA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MIXTURE'
},
{
'ID': 2091,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'POR TELEFONO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ON THE PHONE'
},
{
'ID': 2092,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PACIENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PATIENT'
},
{
'ID': 2093,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PRODUCTIVIDAD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PRODUCTIVITY'
},
{
'ID': 2094,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PROFESIONALIDAD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PROFESSIONALISM'
},
{
'ID': 2095,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FORMA,CONFIGURACIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SHAPE'
},
{
'ID': 2096,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DISCUTIR (ACALORADAMENTE)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ARGUE'
},
{
'ID': 2097,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESTIMAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ESTIMATE'
},
{
'ID': 2098,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SALUDAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO GREET'
},
{
'ID': 2099,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DEBER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO OWE'
},
{
'ID': 2100,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VALLA PUBLICITARIA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BILLBOARD'
},
{
'ID': 2101,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CAMPAÑA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CAMPAIGN'
},
{
'ID': 2102,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CAJERO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CASHIER'
},
{
'ID': 2103,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EXCUSA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EXCUSE'
},
{
'ID': 2104,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AUTENTICO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GENUINE'
},
{
'ID': 2105,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'IMPACTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IMPACT'
},
{
'ID': 2106,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INCOMPETENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'INCOMPETENT'
},
{
'ID': 2107,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MÍNIMO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MINIMUM'
},
{
'ID': 2108,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PERMANENTEMENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PERMANENTLY'
},
{
'ID': 2109,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PERTINENTE,CORRESPONDIENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PERTINENT'
},
{
'ID': 2110,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'APLAZAMIENTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'POSTPONEMENT'
},
{
'ID': 2111,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PARA QUE...',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SO THAT...'
},
{
'ID': 2112,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'APOYO,RESPALDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SUPPORT'
},
{
'ID': 2113,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'APLICAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO APPLY'
},
{
'ID': 2114,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COBRAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO COLLECT'
},
{
'ID': 2115,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ADJUNTAR (A UNA CARTA)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ENCLOSE'
},
{
'ID': 2116,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EXAMINAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO EXAMINE'
},
{
'ID': 2117,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ADIVINAR,SUPONER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO GUESS'
},
{
'ID': 2118,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INFORMAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO INFORM'
},
{
'ID': 2119,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INVESTIGAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO INVESTIGATE'
},
{
'ID': 2120,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PROGRESAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO PROGRESS'
},
{
'ID': 2121,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COMPARTIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SHARE'
},
{
'ID': 2122,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DEJAR PROPINA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO TIP'
},
{
'ID': 2123,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESAGRADABLE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'UNPLEASANT'
},
{
'ID': 2124,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FUERZA DE VOLUNTAD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WILLPOWER'
},
{
'ID': 2125,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ETCÉTERA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AND SO ON'
},
{
'ID': 2126,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TASA DE NATALIDAD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BIRTH RATE'
},
{
'ID': 2127,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DEPRIMIDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DEPRESSED'
},
{
'ID': 2128,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NIEBLA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FOG'
},
{
'ID': 2129,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PLENAMENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FULLY'
},
{
'ID': 2130,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FANTASMA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GHOST'
},
{
'ID': 2131,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SUPERMERCADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GROCERY STORE'
},
{
'ID': 2132,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INVITACIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'INVITATION'
},
{
'ID': 2133,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'POR SI ACASO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'JUST IN CASE'
},
{
'ID': 2134,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FLOJO,SUELTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LOOSE'
},
{
'ID': 2135,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MADURO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MATURE'
},
{
'ID': 2136,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PERMISO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PERMISSION'
},
{
'ID': 2137,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LA POLÍTICA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'POLITICS'
},
{
'ID': 2138,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PROCEDIMIENTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PROCEDURE'
},
{
'ID': 2139,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ACCIONISTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SHAREHOLDER'
},
{
'ID': 2140,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HUELGA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'STRIKE'
},
{
'ID': 2141,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HACER EJERCICIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO EXERCISE'
},
{
'ID': 2142,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TENER INTENCIÓN DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO INTEND'
},
{
'ID': 2143,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INCORPORARSE A,UNIRSE A',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO JOIN'
},
{
'ID': 2144,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DEJAR UNA PROPINA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO LEAVE A TIP'
},
{
'ID': 2145,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PROHIBIR,IMPEDIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO PROHIBIT'
},
{
'ID': 2146,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PROPONER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO PROPOSE'
},
{
'ID': 2147,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'APOYAR,MANTENER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SUPPORT'
},
{
'ID': 2148,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'IMPOPULAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'UNPOPULAR'
},
{
'ID': 2149,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VENTOSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WINDY'
},
{
'ID': 2150,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COMO SI',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AS THOUGH'
},
{
'ID': 2151,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PRIMA,INCENTIVO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BONUS'
},
{
'ID': 2152,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DIBUJOS ANIMADOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CARTOONS'
},
{
'ID': 2153,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESDE LUEGO,POR SUPUESTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CERTAINLY'
},
{
'ID': 2154,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONSERVADOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CONSERVATIVE'
},
{
'ID': 2155,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DISEÑO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DESIGN'
},
{
'ID': 2156,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SALIDA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EXIT'
},
{
'ID': 2157,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'UÑA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FINGERNAIL'
},
{
'ID': 2158,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MOSCA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FLY'
},
{
'ID': 2159,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PERIODISTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'JOURNALIST'
},
{
'ID': 2160,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'REINO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'KINGDOM'
},
{
'ID': 2161,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LÓGICAMENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LOGICALLY'
},
{
'ID': 2162,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NINGUNA PARTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NOWHERE'
},
{
'ID': 2163,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FUERA DE CONTROL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'OUT OF CONTROL'
},
{
'ID': 2164,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PORTÁTIL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PORTABLE'
},
{
'ID': 2165,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PRECAUCIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PRECAUTION'
},
{
'ID': 2166,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CUALIFICADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'QUALIFIED'
},
{
'ID': 2167,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NEUMÁTICO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TIRE'
},
{
'ID': 2168,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INVOLUCRAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO INVOLVE'
},
{
'ID': 2169,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BAJAR,HACER DESCENDER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO LOWER'
},
{
'ID': 2170,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'POSPONER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO POSTPONE'
},
{
'ID': 2171,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PROCEDER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO PROCEED'
},
{
'ID': 2172,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SUPONER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SUPPOSE'
},
{
'ID': 2173,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RARO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'UNUSUAL'
},
{
'ID': 2174,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ALA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WING'
},
{
'ID': 2175,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GANGA,CHOLLO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BARGAIN'
},
{
'ID': 2176,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENVIDIA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ENVY'
},
{
'ID': 2177,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CON SOLTURA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FLUENTLY'
},
{
'ID': 2178,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PEGAMENTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GLUE'
},
{
'ID': 2179,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'A MITAD DE CAMINO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HALFWAY'
},
{
'ID': 2180,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INFARTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HEART ATTACK'
},
{
'ID': 2181,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MAL EDUCADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IMPOLITE'
},
{
'ID': 2182,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EN CONTEXTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IN CONTEXT'
},
{
'ID': 2183,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'JUGO,ZUMO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'JUICE'
},
{
'ID': 2184,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INFERIOR,MAS BAJO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LOWER'
},
{
'ID': 2185,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MILAGRO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MIRACLE'
},
{
'ID': 2186,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PERSUASIVO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PERSUASIVE'
},
{
'ID': 2187,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FILOSOFÍA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PHILOSOPHY'
},
{
'ID': 2188,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PRECISO,EXACTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PRECISE'
},
{
'ID': 2189,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LA PRENSA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THE PRESS'
},
{
'ID': 2190,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EXPLORAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO EXPLORE'
},
{
'ID': 2191,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VESTIRSE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO GET DRESSED'
},
{
'ID': 2192,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'REUNIRSE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO GET TOGETHER'
},
{
'ID': 2193,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'IMPORTAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO IMPORT'
},
{
'ID': 2194,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BROMEAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO JOKE'
},
{
'ID': 2195,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'JUZGAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO JUDGE'
},
{
'ID': 2196,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FINGIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO PRETEND'
},
{
'ID': 2197,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BENEFICIARSE DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO PROFIT FROM'
},
{
'ID': 2198,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INACEPTABLE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'UNACCEPTABLE'
},
{
'ID': 2199,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GANADOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WINNER'
},
{
'ID': 2200,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HERMOSURA,BELLEZA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BEAUTY'
},
{
'ID': 2201,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CIUDADANO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CITIZEN'
},
{
'ID': 2202,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CAJÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DRAWER'
},
{
'ID': 2203,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EXPORTACIONES',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EXPORTS'
},
{
'ID': 2204,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SOLTURA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FLUENCY'
},
{
'ID': 2205,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ULTRAMARINOS,COMESTIBLES',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GROCERIES'
},
{
'ID': 2206,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PEINADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HAIRSTYLE'
},
{
'ID': 2207,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AUDICIÓN,CAPACIDAD AUDITIVA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HEARING'
},
{
'ID': 2208,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'POCO A POCO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LITTLE BY LITTLE'
},
{
'ID': 2209,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SUERTE,FORTUNA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LUCK'
},
{
'ID': 2210,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESPEJO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MIRROR'
},
{
'ID': 2211,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BARRIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NEIGHBORHOOD'
},
{
'ID': 2212,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PÁRRAFO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PARAGRAPH'
},
{
'ID': 2213,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PRECISAMENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PRECISELY'
},
{
'ID': 2214,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RECESIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RECESSION'
},
{
'ID': 2215,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EGOÍSTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SELFISH'
},
{
'ID': 2216,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SOLDADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SOLDIER'
},
{
'ID': 2217,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LA LEY',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THE LAW'
},
{
'ID': 2218,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PREDECIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO PREDICT'
},
{
'ID': 2219,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PULSAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO PRESS'
},
{
'ID': 2220,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PREVENIR,EVITAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO PREVENT'
},
{
'ID': 2221,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SOBREVIVIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SURVIVE'
},
{
'ID': 2222,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HERRAMIENTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TOOL'
},
{
'ID': 2223,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VARIEDAD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'VARIETY'
},
{
'ID': 2224,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ALAMBRE,CABLE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WIRE'
},
{
'ID': 2225,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MAS ALLÁ DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BEYOND'
},
{
'ID': 2226,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CEREBRO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BRAIN'
},
{
'ID': 2227,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DISCUSIÓN (NO ACALORADA)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DISCUSSION'
},
{
'ID': 2228,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DE MODA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IN FASHION'
},
{
'ID': 2229,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INVISIBLE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'INVISIBLE'
},
{
'ID': 2230,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MEDIDAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MEASUREMENTS'
},
{
'ID': 2231,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MALENTENDIDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MISUNDERSTANDING'
},
{
'ID': 2232,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': '¡DIOS MIO!',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MY GOD!'
},
{
'ID': 2233,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENCIMA DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ON TOP OF'
},
{
'ID': 2234,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MONTÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PILE'
},
{
'ID': 2235,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONTENTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PLEASED'
},
{
'ID': 2236,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SACERDOTE,CURA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PRIEST'
},
{
'ID': 2237,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PERFIL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PROFILE'
},
{
'ID': 2238,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PERSPECTIVAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PROSPECTS'
},
{
'ID': 2239,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'REFERENCIA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'REFERENCE'
},
{
'ID': 2240,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MARISCOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SHELLFISH'
},
{
'ID': 2241,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LEVE,LIGERO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SLIGHT'
},
{
'ID': 2242,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SOLIDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SOLID'
},
{
'ID': 2243,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SUPERVIVIENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SURVIVOR'
},
{
'ID': 2244,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EL COSTE DE LA VIDA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THE COST OF LIVING'
},
{
'ID': 2245,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PERMITIRSE EL LUJO DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO AFFORD'
},
{
'ID': 2246,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EXPRESAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO EXPRESS'
},
{
'ID': 2247,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONCEDER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO GRANT'
},
{
'ID': 2248,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VARIAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO VARY'
},
{
'ID': 2249,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INTELIGENTE,SABIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WISE'
},
{
'ID': 2250,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'UN REQUISITO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'A REQUIREMENT'
},
{
'ID': 2251,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FRENOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BRAKES'
},
{
'ID': 2252,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'POR CASUALIDAD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BY CHANCE'
},
{
'ID': 2253,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PAPEL CARTÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CARDBOARD'
},
{
'ID': 2254,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONSECUTIVO,SEGUIDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CONSECUTIVE'
},
{
'ID': 2255,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DEUDA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DEBT'
},
{
'ID': 2256,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESCUENTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DISCOUNT'
},
{
'ID': 2257,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EXPRESIVO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EXPRESSIVE'
},
{
'ID': 2258,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PLANO,LLANO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FLAT'
},
{
'ID': 2259,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PARA SIEMPRE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FOR GOOD'
},
{
'ID': 2260,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TRABAJADOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HARD-WORKING'
},
{
'ID': 2261,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'JOYA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'JEWEL'
},
{
'ID': 2262,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LEGAL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LEGAL'
},
{
'ID': 2263,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PARA NADA,EN ABSOLUTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NOT AT ALL'
},
{
'ID': 2264,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DE SOBRA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PLENTY OF'
},
{
'ID': 2265,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PRIVADO,INTIMO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PRIVATE'
},
{
'ID': 2266,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CORRECTAMENTE,ADECUADAMENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PROPERLY'
},
{
'ID': 2267,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PROSPERIDAD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PROSPERITY'
},
{
'ID': 2268,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MATERIA,COSA,SUSTANCIA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'STUFF'
},
{
'ID': 2269,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HACER UN ESFUERZO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO MAKE AN EFFORT'
},
{
'ID': 2270,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SEÑALAR,RESALTAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO POINT OUT'
},
{
'ID': 2271,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TRAGAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SWALLOW'
},
{
'ID': 2272,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESEAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO WISH'
},
{
'ID': 2273,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TEMA (DE CONVERSACIÓN)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TOPIC'
},
{
'ID': 2274,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VEHÍCULO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'VEHICLE'
},
{
'ID': 2275,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ALOJAMIENTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ACCOMMODATION'
},
{
'ID': 2276,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CAMPAÑA PUBLICITARIA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ADVERTISING CAMPAIGN'
},
{
'ID': 2277,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SUCURSAL,RAMA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BRANCH'
},
{
'ID': 2278,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VALIENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BRAVE'
},
{
'ID': 2279,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CANCELACIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CANCELLATION'
},
{
'ID': 2280,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DECENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DECENT'
},
{
'ID': 2281,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EXTRAORDINARIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EXTRAORDINARY'
},
{
'ID': 2282,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FABULOSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FABULOUS'
},
{
'ID': 2283,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FALSA ALARMA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FALSE ALARM'
},
{
'ID': 2284,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PRECIOSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GORGEOUS'
},
{
'ID': 2285,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ÚTIL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HANDY'
},
{
'ID': 2286,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'IMPERSONAL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IMPERSONAL'
},
{
'ID': 2287,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'JUDIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'JEW'
},
{
'ID': 2288,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LIMITE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LIMIT'
},
{
'ID': 2289,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NI...NI',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NEITHER...NOR'
},
{
'ID': 2290,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PAZ',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PEACE'
},
{
'ID': 2291,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PECULIAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PECULIAR'
},
{
'ID': 2292,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'POLÍTICO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'POLITICIAN'
},
{
'ID': 2293,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PREDICCIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PREDICTION'
},
{
'ID': 2294,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RENTABILIDAD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PROFITABILITY'
},
{
'ID': 2295,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PROVISIONAL,TEMPORAL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PROVISIONAL'
},
{
'ID': 2296,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'REALISTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'REALISTIC'
},
{
'ID': 2297,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SEÑALAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO POINT'
},
{
'ID': 2298,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PREGUNTARSE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO WONDER'
},
{
'ID': 2299,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VICEVERSA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'VICEVERSA'
},
{
'ID': 2300,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ACEPTACIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ACCEPTANCE'
},
{
'ID': 2301,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONTABLE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ACCOUNTANT'
},
{
'ID': 2302,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EXTROVERTIDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EXTROVERTED'
},
{
'ID': 2303,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BANDERA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FLAG'
},
{
'ID': 2304,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FRACCIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FRACTION'
},
{
'ID': 2305,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PATATAS FRITAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FRENCH FRIES'
},
{
'ID': 2306,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INFLEXIBLE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'INFLEXIBLE'
},
{
'ID': 2307,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INESTABILIDAD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'INSTABILITY'
},
{
'ID': 2308,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RENTABLE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PROFITABLE'
},
{
'ID': 2309,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LECTURA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'READING'
},
{
'ID': 2310,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RECIBO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RECEIPT'
},
{
'ID': 2311,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENVÍO (DE MERCANCÍAS)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SHIPMENT'
},
{
'ID': 2312,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FUENTE,ORIGEN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SOURCE'
},
{
'ID': 2313,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SORPRENDENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SURPRISING'
},
{
'ID': 2314,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INTERRUPTOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SWITCH'
},
{
'ID': 2315,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LAS RAMAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THE BRANCHES'
},
{
'ID': 2316,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LA DIRECCIÓN (EMPRESARIAL)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THE MANAGEMENT'
},
{
'ID': 2317,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GOBERNAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO GOVERN'
},
{
'ID': 2318,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ECHAR AL CORREO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO MAIL'
},
{
'ID': 2319,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PROPORCIONAR,SUMINISTRAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO PROVIDE'
},
{
'ID': 2320,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PROVOCAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO PROVOKE'
},
{
'ID': 2321,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COMERCIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TRADE'
},
{
'ID': 2322,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESAFORTUNADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'UNLUCKY'
},
{
'ID': 2323,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VICTIMA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'VICTIM'
},
{
'ID': 2324,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TALLER MECÁNICO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WORKSHOP'
},
{
'ID': 2325,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CATEGORÍA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CATEGORY'
},
{
'ID': 2326,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COMPETITIVO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'COMPETITIVE'
},
{
'ID': 2327,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONSIDERADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CONSIDERATE'
},
{
'ID': 2328,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ABARROTADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CROWDED'
},
{
'ID': 2329,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ECONOMISTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ECONOMIST'
},
{
'ID': 2330,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ARCHIVADOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FILING CABINET'
},
{
'ID': 2331,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SABOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FLAVOR'
},
{
'ID': 2332,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INCENDIO FORESTAL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FOREST FIRE'
},
{
'ID': 2333,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LUNA LLENA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FULL MOON'
},
{
'ID': 2334,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GOBERNADOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GOVERNOR'
},
{
'ID': 2335,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EN VISTA DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IN VIEW OF'
},
{
'ID': 2336,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INDIFERENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'INDIFFERENT'
},
{
'ID': 2337,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ZURDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LEFT-HANDED'
},
{
'ID': 2338,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PARANOICO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PARANOID'
},
{
'ID': 2339,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PRESTIGIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PRESTIGE'
},
{
'ID': 2340,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DEMOSTRACIÓN,PRUEBA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PROOF'
},
{
'ID': 2341,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DUDOSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'QUESTIONABLE'
},
{
'ID': 2342,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PESCADO Y MARISCO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SEAFOOD'
},
{
'ID': 2343,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESPECIALISTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SPECIALIST'
},
{
'ID': 2344,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VALER LA PENA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BE WORTH IT'
},
{
'ID': 2345,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'REALIZAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO PERFORM'
},
{
'ID': 2346,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PUBLICAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO PUBLISH'
},
{
'ID': 2347,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CAMBIAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SWITCH'
},
{
'ID': 2348,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TRADUCIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO TRANSLATE'
},
{
'ID': 2349,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DISPUESTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WILLING'
},
{
'ID': 2350,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LOGRO,CONSECUCIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ACCOMPLISHMENT'
},
{
'ID': 2351,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ACONSEJABLE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ADVISABLE'
},
{
'ID': 2352,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'APETITO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'APPETITE'
},
{
'ID': 2353,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BALA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BULLET'
},
{
'ID': 2354,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONFIDENCIAL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CONFIDENTIAL'
},
{
'ID': 2355,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ACTUAL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CURRENT'
},
{
'ID': 2356,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'REGLA DE ORO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GOLDEN RULE'
},
{
'ID': 2357,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INDEFINIDAMENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'INDEFINITELY'
},
{
'ID': 2358,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ALTAVOZ',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LOUDSPEAKER'
},
{
'ID': 2359,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PARADÓJICO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PARADOXICAL'
},
{
'ID': 2360,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FONTANERO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PLUMBER'
},
{
'ID': 2361,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ANTERIORMENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PREVIOUSLY'
},
{
'ID': 2362,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ADECUADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PROPER'
},
{
'ID': 2363,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BASTANTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'QUITE'
},
{
'ID': 2364,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BÚSQUEDA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SEARCH'
},
{
'ID': 2365,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LISO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SMOOTH'
},
{
'ID': 2366,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PROPINA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TIP'
},
{
'ID': 2367,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VALER LA PENA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BE WORTHWHILE'
},
{
'ID': 2368,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ATERRIZAR,TOMAR TIERRA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO LAND'
},
{
'ID': 2369,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MEMORIZAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO MEMORIZE'
},
{
'ID': 2370,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CUESTIONAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO QUESTION'
},
{
'ID': 2371,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESPECIALIZARSE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SPECIALIZE'
},
{
'ID': 2372,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENCENDER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SWITCH ON'
},
{
'ID': 2373,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BANDEJA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TRAY'
},
{
'ID': 2374,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VOLUMEN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'VOLUME'
},
{
'ID': 2375,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONSCIENTE DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AWARE OF'
},
{
'ID': 2376,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CIEGO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BLIND'
},
{
'ID': 2377,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SANGRE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BLOOD'
},
{
'ID': 2378,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AVERGONZADO,VIOLENTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EMBARRASSED'
},
{
'ID': 2379,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EL OTOÑO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FALL'
},
{
'ID': 2380,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DIRECTRICES',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GUIDELINES'
},
{
'ID': 2381,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENCABEZAMIENTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HEADING'
},
{
'ID': 2382,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NIÑOS,HIJOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'KIDS'
},
{
'ID': 2383,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PREFERIBLEMENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PREFERABLY'
},
{
'ID': 2384,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PROMETEDOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PROMISING'
},
{
'ID': 2385,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CUOTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'QUOTA'
},
{
'ID': 2386,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'REACCIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'REACTION'
},
{
'ID': 2387,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESPECÍFICAMENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SPECIFICALLY'
},
{
'ID': 2388,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EL CANAL DE LA MANCHA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THE ENGLISH CHANNEL'
},
{
'ID': 2389,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GRADUARSE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO GRADUATE'
},
{
'ID': 2390,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CERRAR CON LLAVE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO LOCK'
},
{
'ID': 2391,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MENCIONAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO MENTION'
},
{
'ID': 2392,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'IMPRIMIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO PRINT'
},
{
'ID': 2393,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BUSCAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SEARCH FOR'
},
{
'ID': 2394,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PROPORCIONAR,SUMINISTRAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SUPPLY'
},
{
'ID': 2395,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'APAGAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SWITCH OFF'
},
{
'ID': 2396,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TRIPLICAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO TRIPLE'
},
{
'ID': 2397,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENVOLVER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO WRAP'
},
{
'ID': 2398,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TESORO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TREASURE'
},
{
'ID': 2399,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CINTURA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WAIST'
},
{
'ID': 2400,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'A TODA VELOCIDAD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AT FULL SPEED'
},
{
'ID': 2401,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AUTENTICO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AUTHENTIC'
},
{
'ID': 2402,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BASADO EN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BASED ON'
},
{
'ID': 2403,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CAPITULO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CHAPTER'
},
{
'ID': 2404,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CHICLE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CHEWING GUM'
},
{
'ID': 2405,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HARINA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FLOUR'
},
{
'ID': 2406,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GRATITUD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GRATITUDE'
},
{
'ID': 2407,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GRIEGO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GREEK'
},
{
'ID': 2408,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': '¡ESPERA!',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HOLD ON!'
},
{
'ID': 2409,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ANFITRIONA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HOSTESS'
},
{
'ID': 2410,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'POR ESCRITO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IN WRITING'
},
{
'ID': 2411,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INVERSIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'INVESTMENT'
},
{
'ID': 2412,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PRÉSTAMO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LOAN'
},
{
'ID': 2413,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MINA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MINE'
},
{
'ID': 2414,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EMBARAZADA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PREGNANT'
},
{
'ID': 2415,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ASCENSO,PROMOCIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PROMOTION'
},
{
'ID': 2416,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EMISORA DE RADIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RADIO STATION'
},
{
'ID': 2417,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CIENCIA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SCIENCE'
},
{
'ID': 2418,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VELOCIDAD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SPEED'
},
{
'ID': 2419,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SISTEMÁTICO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SYSTEMATIC'
},
{
'ID': 2420,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DIMINUTO,MUY PEQUEÑO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TINY'
},
{
'ID': 2421,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESTAR FAMILIARIZADO CON',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BE FAMILIAR WITH'
},
{
'ID': 2422,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DISPARA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SHOOT'
},
{
'ID': 2423,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TRATAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO TREAT'
},
{
'ID': 2424,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CARTERA,BILLETERO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WALLET'
},
{
'ID': 2425,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'UNA PETICIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'A REQUEST'
},
{
'ID': 2426,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PUENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BRIDGE'
},
{
'ID': 2427,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CARÁCTER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CHARACTER'
},
{
'ID': 2428,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ELOCUENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ELOQUENT'
},
{
'ID': 2429,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TARIFA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FARE'
},
{
'ID': 2430,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LA FRENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FOREHEAD'
},
{
'ID': 2431,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GRECIA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GREECE'
},
{
'ID': 2432,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GARANTÍA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GUARANTEE'
},
{
'ID': 2433,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SEMANA SANTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HOLY WEEK'
},
{
'ID': 2434,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'IMPULSIVO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IMPULSIVE'
},
{
'ID': 2435,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EN COMÚN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IN COMMON'
},
{
'ID': 2436,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MINORÍA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MINORITY'
},
{
'ID': 2437,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ORGANIZADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ORGANIZED'
},
{
'ID': 2438,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PUERTO (DE MAR)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PORT'
},
{
'ID': 2439,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INMEDIATO,RÁPIDO,PRONTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PROMPT'
},
{
'ID': 2440,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FERROCARRIL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RAILROAD'
},
{
'ID': 2441,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESPÍRITU',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SPIRIT'
},
{
'ID': 2442,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TALENTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TALENT'
},
{
'ID': 2443,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LO SIGUIENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THE FOLLOWING'
},
{
'ID': 2444,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DUPLICAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO DOUBLE'
},
{
'ID': 2445,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SUBIR,ELEVAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO RAISE'
},
{
'ID': 2446,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ADVERTIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO WARN'
},
{
'ID': 2447,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TENDENCIA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TREND'
},
{
'ID': 2448,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INNECESARIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'UNNECESSARY'
},
{
'ID': 2449,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESCRITO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WRITTEN'
},
{
'ID': 2450,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONTABILIDAD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ACCOUNTING'
},
{
'ID': 2451,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DINERO EN METÁLICO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CASH'
},
{
'ID': 2452,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONEXIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CONNECTION'
},
{
'ID': 2453,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PRESA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DAM'
},
{
'ID': 2454,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DECADA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DECADE'
},
{
'ID': 2455,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'POLVO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DUST'
},
{
'ID': 2456,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EFICIENCIA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EFFICIENCY'
},
{
'ID': 2457,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AGRICULTURA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FARMING'
},
{
'ID': 2458,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FAVORABLE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FAVORABLE'
},
{
'ID': 2459,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GUARDA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GUARD'
},
{
'ID': 2460,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TRABAJO DOMESTICO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HOUSEWORK'
},
{
'ID': 2461,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LESIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'INJURY'
},
{
'ID': 2462,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VESTÍBULO (DE HOTEL)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LOBBY'
},
{
'ID': 2463,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MODESTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MODEST'
},
{
'ID': 2464,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LLUVIOSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RAINY'
},
{
'ID': 2465,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GAMA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RANGE'
},
{
'ID': 2466,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VALORACIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RATING'
},
{
'ID': 2467,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ORILLA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SHORE'
},
{
'ID': 2468,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DEPOSITO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TANK'
},
{
'ID': 2469,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EL CONTENIDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THE CONTENTS'
},
{
'ID': 2470,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESTAR DISPUESTO A',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BE WILLING TO'
},
{
'ID': 2471,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DIVIDIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SPLIT'
},
{
'ID': 2472,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TRUCO,TRAMPA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TRICK'
},
{
'ID': 2473,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ADVERTENCIA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WARNING'
},
{
'ID': 2474,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ANUALMENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'YEARLY'
},
{
'ID': 2475,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VIVO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ALIVE'
},
{
'ID': 2476,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TABLÓN DE ANUNCIOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BULLETIN BOARD'
},
{
'ID': 2477,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COMPLICADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'COMPLICATED'
},
{
'ID': 2478,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONCESIONARIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DEALER'
},
{
'ID': 2479,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LA MUERTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DEATH'
},
{
'ID': 2480,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BORRACHO,BEBIDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DRUNK'
},
{
'ID': 2481,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'UN DÍA SI Y OTRO NO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EVERY OTHER DAY'
},
{
'ID': 2482,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CULPA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FAULT'
},
{
'ID': 2483,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PREVISIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FORECAST'
},
{
'ID': 2484,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PUNTO FINAL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FULL STOP'
},
{
'ID': 2485,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FONDOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FUNDS'
},
{
'ID': 2486,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INVITADO,HUÉSPED',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GUEST'
},
{
'ID': 2487,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'IMPRESIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IMPRESSION'
},
{
'ID': 2488,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INCOMPATIBLE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'INCOMPATIBLE'
},
{
'ID': 2489,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PENDIENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PENDING'
},
{
'ID': 2490,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SALADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SALTY'
},
{
'ID': 2491,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SERIAMENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SERIOUSLY'
},
{
'ID': 2492,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'A CORTO PLAZO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SHORT-TERM'
},
{
'ID': 2493,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESPONTANEO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SPONTANEOUS'
},
{
'ID': 2494,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PASO A PASO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'STEP BY STEP'
},
{
'ID': 2495,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BLANCO,OBJETIVO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TARGET'
},
{
'ID': 2496,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESTAR METIDO EN UN LIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BE IN TROUBLE'
},
{
'ID': 2497,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MODIFICAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO MODIFY'
},
{
'ID': 2498,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PAPELERA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WASTE BASKET'
},
{
'ID': 2499,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'JUVENTUD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'YOUTH'
},
{
'ID': 2500,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ASOMBROSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AMAZING'
},
{
'ID': 2501,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CORRIDA DE TOROS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BULLFIGHT'
},
{
'ID': 2502,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PRESIDENTE DEL CONSEJO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CHAIRMAN'
},
{
'ID': 2503,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COMPATIBLE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'COMPATIBLE'
},
{
'ID': 2504,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONTAGIOSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CONTAGIOUS'
},
{
'ID': 2505,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TRIBUNAL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'COURT'
},
{
'ID': 2506,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'POSTRE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DESSERT'
},
{
'ID': 2507,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HEMBRA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FEMALE'
},
{
'ID': 2508,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GUIA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GUIDE'
},
{
'ID': 2509,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'IMPROBABLE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IMPROBABLE'
},
{
'ID': 2510,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LABIOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LIPS'
},
{
'ID': 2511,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'UBICADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LOCATED'
},
{
'ID': 2512,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MATRIMONIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MARRIAGE'
},
{
'ID': 2513,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'OPERACIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'OPERATION'
},
{
'ID': 2514,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PLACER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PLEASURE'
},
{
'ID': 2515,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RESPONSABLE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RESPONSIBLE'
},
{
'ID': 2516,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SEGURO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SECURE'
},
{
'ID': 2517,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESPONTÁNEAMENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SPONTANEOUSLY'
},
{
'ID': 2518,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TAREA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TASK'
},
{
'ID': 2519,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'A TRAVÉS DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THROUGH'
},
{
'ID': 2520,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LLEVARSE BIEN CON',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO GET ALONG WITH'
},
{
'ID': 2521,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RAZONAR CON',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO REASON WITH'
},
{
'ID': 2522,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONFIANZA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TRUST'
},
{
'ID': 2523,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'OLA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WAVE'
},
{
'ID': 2524,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'iQUE LIO!',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WHAT A MESS!'
},
{
'ID': 2525,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'UNA CALLE DE SENTIDO ÚNICO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'A ONE-WAY STREET'
},
{
'ID': 2526,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LA HISTORIA ANTIGUA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ANCIENT HISTORY'
},
{
'ID': 2527,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ATENAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ATHENS'
},
{
'ID': 2528,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENCANTADOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CHARMING'
},
{
'ID': 2529,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COMPLEJO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'COMPLEX'
},
{
'ID': 2530,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TASA DE MORTALIDAD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DEATH RATE'
},
{
'ID': 2531,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DECLIVE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DECLINE'
},
{
'ID': 2532,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VALLA,CERCA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FENCE'
},
{
'ID': 2533,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': '¡ADELANTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'I GO AHEAD!'
},
{
'ID': 2534,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GRÁFICO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GRAPH'
},
{
'ID': 2535,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CULPABLE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GUILTY'
},
{
'ID': 2536,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INSPECCIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'INSPECTION'
},
{
'ID': 2537,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MONSTRUO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MONSTER'
},
{
'ID': 2538,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'QUIOSCO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NEWSSTAND'
},
{
'ID': 2539,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RAZONABLEMENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'REASONABLY'
},
{
'ID': 2540,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SEMINARIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SEMINAR'
},
{
'ID': 2541,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESTANTERÍA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SHELF'
},
{
'ID': 2542,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'A CORTO PLAZO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SHORT-RANGE'
},
{
'ID': 2543,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SEGURIDAD SOCIAL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SOCIAL SECURITY'
},
{
'ID': 2544,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MANCHA,PUNTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SPOT'
},
{
'ID': 2545,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TÉCNICA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TECHNIQUE'
},
{
'ID': 2546,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LA MARINA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THE NAVY'
},
{
'ID': 2547,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LA VERDAD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THE TRUTH'
},
{
'ID': 2548,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NEUMÁTICOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TIRES'
},
{
'ID': 2549,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CERA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WAX'
},
{
'ID': 2550,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AMBIGUO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AMBIGUOUS'
},
{
'ID': 2551,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VELA (DE CERA)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CANDLE'
},
{
'ID': 2552,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TAPA,CUBIERTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'COVER'
},
{
'ID': 2553,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CLIENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CUSTOMER'
},
{
'ID': 2554,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENTUSIASTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ENTHUSIASTIC'
},
{
'ID': 2555,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FIEBRE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FEVER'
},
{
'ID': 2556,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PASILLO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HALLWAY'
},
{
'ID': 2557,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TITULARES',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HEADLINES'
},
{
'ID': 2558,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'IGNORANTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IGNORANT'
},
{
'ID': 2559,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'JUEZ',
        'RESPUESTA': 'JUDGE'
},
{
'ID': 2560,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CUERO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LEATHER'
},
{
'ID': 2561,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESORDENADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MESSY'
},
{
'ID': 2562,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TIBURÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SHARK'
},
{
'ID': 2563,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DISPARO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SHOT'
},
{
'ID': 2564,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GAMBAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SHRIMP'
},
{
'ID': 2565,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ALGO ASI COMO...',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SOMETHING LIKE...'
},
{
'ID': 2566,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESPÍA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SPY'
},
{
'ID': 2567,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TECNOLOGÍA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TECHNOLOGY'
},
{
'ID': 2568,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MOTIVAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO MOTIVATE'
},
{
'ID': 2569,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AGRADAR,COMPLACER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO PLEASE'
},
{
'ID': 2570,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SEPARAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SEPARATE'
},
{
'ID': 2571,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENVIAR (MERCANCÍAS)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SHIP'
},
{
'ID': 2572,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PROBLEMAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TROUBLE'
},
{
'ID': 2573,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MELODÍA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TUNE'
},
{
'ID': 2574,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RIQUEZA,PATRIMONIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WEALTH'
},
{
'ID': 2575,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RETO,DESAFIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CHALLENGE'
},
{
'ID': 2576,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CAMPEÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CHAMPION'
},
{
'ID': 2577,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CRISIS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CRISIS'
},
{
'ID': 2578,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MULTITUD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CROWD'
},
{
'ID': 2579,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EXIGENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DEMANDING'
},
{
'ID': 2580,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BASTANTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FAIRLY'
},
{
'ID': 2581,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MODA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FASHION'
},
{
'ID': 2582,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PELEA,LUCHA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FIGHT'
},
{
'ID': 2583,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COMBUSTIBLE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FUEL'
},
{
'ID': 2584,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GRADUALMENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GRADUALLY'
},
{
'ID': 2585,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HECHO A MANO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HAND-MADE'
},
{
'ID': 2586,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'IMPORTADOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IMPORTER'
},
{
'ID': 2587,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INCENTIVO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'INCENTIVE'
},
{
'ID': 2588,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LÓGICO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LOGICAL'
},
{
'ID': 2589,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MOTIVADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MOTIVATED'
},
{
'ID': 2590,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PERSONALMENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PERSONALLY'
},
{
'ID': 2591,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LA SOCIEDAD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SOCIETY'
},
{
'ID': 2592,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESTABILIDAD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'STABILITY'
},
{
'ID': 2593,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'JOVEN DE 13 A 19 AÑOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TEENAGER'
},
{
'ID': 2594,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RECONOCER,ADMITIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ADMIT'
},
{
'ID': 2595,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HACER TURISMO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO GO SIGHTSEEING'
},
{
'ID': 2596,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NOMBRAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO NAME'
},
{
'ID': 2597,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'REFLEXIONAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO REFLECT'
},
{
'ID': 2598,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TÚNEL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TUNNEL'
},
{
'ID': 2599,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ADINERADO ',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WEALTHY'
},
{
'ID': 2600,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESPISTADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ABSENT-MINDED'
},
{
'ID': 2601,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TELÓN DE FONDO,HISTORIAL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BACKGROUND'
},
{
'ID': 2602,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BARBA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BEARD'
},
{
'ID': 2603,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DE MEMORIA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BY HEART'
},
{
'ID': 2604,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FECHADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DATED'
},
{
'ID': 2605,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DEFICIENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DEFICIENT'
},
{
'ID': 2606,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ADJUNTO (EN UNA CARTA)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ENCLOSED'
},
{
'ID': 2607,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AGRICULTOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FARMER'
},
{
'ID': 2608,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FINANCIERO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FINANCIAL'
},
{
'ID': 2609,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESPERANZA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HOPE'
},
{
'ID': 2610,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CÁRCEL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'JAIL'
},
{
'ID': 2611,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MERMELADA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'JAM'
},
{
'ID': 2612,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MERCANCÍAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MERCHANDISE'
},
{
'ID': 2613,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ASESINATO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MURDER'
},
{
'ID': 2614,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PACIENCIA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PATIENCE'
},
{
'ID': 2615,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PREVALENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PREVALENT'
},
{
'ID': 2616,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PRIVILEGIADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PRIVILEGED'
},
{
'ID': 2617,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SEÑAL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SIGNAL'
},
{
'ID': 2618,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TEMPERAMENTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TEMPER'
},
{
'ID': 2619,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ACONSEJAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ADVISE'
},
{
'ID': 2620,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RESULTAR ÚTIL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO COME IN HANDY'
},
{
'ID': 2621,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SELLAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO STAMP'
},
{
'ID': 2622,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GEMELOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TWINS'
},
{
'ID': 2623,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ARMA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WEAPON'
},
{
'ID': 2624,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': '¿QUE CLASE DE...?',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WHAT SORT OF...?'
},
{
'ID': 2625,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LOGRO,CONSECUCIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ACHIEVEMENT'
},
{
'ID': 2626,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PREMIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AWARD'
},
{
'ID': 2627,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COMPACTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'COMPACT'
},
{
'ID': 2628,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONFUNDIDO,CONFUSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CONFUSED'
},
{
'ID': 2629,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PRIMO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'COUSIN'
},
{
'ID': 2630,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DAÑO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DAMAGE'
},
{
'ID': 2631,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DELICIOSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DELICIOUS'
},
{
'ID': 2632,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESVENTAJA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DISADVANTAGE'
},
{
'ID': 2633,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FURIOSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FURIOUS'
},
{
'ID': 2634,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GUAPO,DE BUEN VER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GOOD-LOOKING'
},
{
'ID': 2635,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ILEGAL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ILLEGAL'
},
{
'ID': 2636,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MENSUAL,MENSUALMENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MONTHLY'
},
{
'ID': 2637,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONCHA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SHELL'
},
{
'ID': 2638,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SEDA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SILK'
},
{
'ID': 2639,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VAPOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'STEAM'
},
{
'ID': 2640,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TENDENCIA (PERSONAL)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TENDENCY'
},
{
'ID': 2641,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESO ES,EN EFECTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THAT\'S RIGHT'
},
{
'ID': 2642,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EL HOMBRE DEL TIEMPO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THE WEATHERMAN'
},
{
'ID': 2643,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SOÑAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO DREAM'
},
{
'ID': 2644,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'APAÑARSE,SALIR DEL PASO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO GET BY'
},
{
'ID': 2645,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COLGAR (EL TELEFONO)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO HANG UP'
},
{
'ID': 2646,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ASESINAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO MURDER'
},
{
'ID': 2647,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'REACCIONAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO REACT'
},
{
'ID': 2648,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESTABLECER,FIJAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SET UP'
},
{
'ID': 2649,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SUDAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SWEAT'
},
{
'ID': 2650,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GRACIOSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AMUSING'
},
{
'ID': 2651,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ARREGLO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ARRANGEMENT'
},
{
'ID': 2652,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENSEGUIDA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AT ONCE'
},
{
'ID': 2653,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EN ESTOS MOMENTOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AT PRESENT'
},
{
'ID': 2654,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CATEDRAL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CATHEDRAL'
},
{
'ID': 2655,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CEMENTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CEMENT'
},
{
'ID': 2656,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DIAMANTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DIAMOND'
},
{
'ID': 2657,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EFICACIA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EFFECTIVENESS'
},
{
'ID': 2658,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENTIDAD O PERSONA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EMPLEADORA EMPLOYER'
},
{
'ID': 2659,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GRADUAL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GRADUAL'
},
{
'ID': 2660,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PUERTO (DE MAR)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HARBOR'
},
{
'ID': 2661,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PUNTO DE ENCUENTRO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MEETING PLACE'
},
{
'ID': 2662,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MINISTERIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MINISTRY'
},
{
'ID': 2663,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MÚSICO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MUSICIAN'
},
{
'ID': 2664,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PREVENCIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PREVENTION'
},
{
'ID': 2665,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CIENTÍFICO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SCIENTIST'
},
{
'ID': 2666,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SOMBRA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SHADOW'
},
{
'ID': 2667,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SIMULTANEO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SIMULTANEOUS'
},
{
'ID': 2668,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ACERO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'STEEL'
},
{
'ID': 2669,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FABULOSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TERRIFIC'
},
{
'ID': 2670,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EL DIABLO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THE DEVIL'
},
{
'ID': 2671,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ABANDONAR,DARSE POR VENCIDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO GIVE UP'
},
{
'ID': 2672,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RESOLVER,LIQUIDAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SETTLE'
},
{
'ID': 2673,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INCREÍBLE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'UNBELIEVABLE'
},
{
'ID': 2674,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BODA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WEDDING'
},
{
'ID': 2675,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DE REPENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ALL OF A SUDDEN'
},
{
'ID': 2676,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AGRADECIMIENTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'APPRECIATION'
},
{
'ID': 2677,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SIGLO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CENTURY'
},
{
'ID': 2678,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESORGANIZADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DISORGANIZED'
},
{
'ID': 2679,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EXTREMADAMENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EXTREMELY'
},
{
'ID': 2680,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INSTALACIONES',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FACILITES'
},
{
'ID': 2681,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LA PESCA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FISHING'
},
{
'ID': 2682,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LLAMA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FLAME'
},
{
'ID': 2683,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AFORTUNADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FORTUNATE'
},
{
'ID': 2684,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HUEVO DURO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HARD-BOILED EGG'
},
{
'ID': 2685,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INDIVIDUO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'INDIVIDUAL'
},
{
'ID': 2686,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MONO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MONKEY'
},
{
'ID': 2687,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MISTERIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MYSTERY'
},
{
'ID': 2688,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FÍSICO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PHYSICAL'
},
{
'ID': 2689,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SEVERO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SEVERE'
},
{
'ID': 2690,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SINCERO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SINCERE'
},
{
'ID': 2691,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EL LEJANO ORIENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THE FAR EAST'
},
{
'ID': 2692,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PROGRAMA,HORARIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TIMETABLE'
},
{
'ID': 2693,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESTAR EN CONTACTO CON',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BE IN TOUCH WITH'
},
{
'ID': 2694,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TENER PUESTO (ROPA)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO HAVE ON'
},
{
'ID': 2695,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HACER COMPRAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SHOP'
},
{
'ID': 2696,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ALMACENAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO STORE'
},
{
'ID': 2697,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENSAYAR,PONER A PRUEBA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO TEST'
},
{
'ID': 2698,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INCOMODO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'UNCOMFORTABLE'
},
{
'ID': 2699,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 3,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SEMANAL,SEMANALMENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WEEKLY'
},
{
'ID': 2700,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FLECHA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ARROW'
},
{
'ID': 2701,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'POR CIERTO,A PROPOSITO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BY THE WAY'
},
{
'ID': 2702,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PAÑUELO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HANDKERCHIEF'
},
{
'ID': 2703,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SIN EMBARGO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HOWEVER'
},
{
'ID': 2704,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PROBABILIDAD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LIKELIHOOD'
},
{
'ID': 2705,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'IMÁN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MAGNET'
},
{
'ID': 2706,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TORTILLA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'OMELET'
},
{
'ID': 2707,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'REEMBOLSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'REFUND'
},
{
'ID': 2708,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RELACIONADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RELATED'
},
{
'ID': 2709,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESCASO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SCARCE'
},
{
'ID': 2710,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SENSIBLE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SENSITIVE'
},
{
'ID': 2711,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ARAÑA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SPIDER'
},
{
'ID': 2712,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PROVISIONAL,TEMPORAL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TENTATIVE'
},
{
'ID': 2713,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TERRITORIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TERRITORY'
},
{
'ID': 2714,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESTAR DE BUEN HUMOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BE IN A GOOD MOOD'
},
{
'ID': 2715,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SOPORTAR,AGUANTAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BEAR'
},
{
'ID': 2716,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESCANSAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO REST'
},
{
'ID': 2717,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'JUBILARSE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO RETIRE'
},
{
'ID': 2718,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RASCAR,ARAÑAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SCRATCH'
},
{
'ID': 2719,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FIRMAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SIGN'
},
{
'ID': 2720,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESTIRAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO STRETCH'
},
{
'ID': 2721,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FORMAR,ENTRENAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO TRAIN'
},
{
'ID': 2722,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SILBAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO WHISTLE'
},
{
'ID': 2723,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TOALLA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TOWEL'
},
{
'ID': 2724,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DISGUSTADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'UPSET'
},
{
'ID': 2725,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'UN DICHO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'A SAYING'
},
{
'ID': 2726,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ASOMBROSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AMAZING'
},
{
'ID': 2727,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'POR LO VISTO,AL PARECER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'APPARENTLY'
},
{
'ID': 2728,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CALVO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BALD'
},
{
'ID': 2729,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': '¿COMO SE DICE...?',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HOW DO YOU SAY...?'
},
{
'ID': 2730,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESORDENADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MESSY'
},
{
'ID': 2731,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NO OBSTANTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NEVERTHELESS'
},
{
'ID': 2732,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EN REBAJAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ON SALE'
},
{
'ID': 2733,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CAMINO DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ON THE WAY TO'
},
{
'ID': 2734,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PERSEVERANCIA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PERSEVERANCE'
},
{
'ID': 2735,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ANTES DE,ANTERIOR A',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PRIOR TO'
},
{
'ID': 2736,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AHORA MISMO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RIGHT NOW'
},
{
'ID': 2737,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GAFAS DE SOL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SUNGLASSES'
},
{
'ID': 2738,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PUESTA DEL SOL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SUNSET'
},
{
'ID': 2739,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ANTICIPAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ANTICIPATE'
},
{
'ID': 2740,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TRANSMITIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO CONVEY'
},
{
'ID': 2741,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ARCHIVAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO FILE'
},
{
'ID': 2742,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'JUNTAR,INGRESAR EN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO JOIN'
},
{
'ID': 2743,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'JUZGAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO JUDGE'
},
{
'ID': 2744,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LLEGAR A FIN DE MES',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO MAKE ENDS MEET'
},
{
'ID': 2745,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LLEGAR A DOMINAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO MASTER'
},
{
'ID': 2746,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'REFERIRSE A',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO REFER TO'
},
{
'ID': 2747,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONSIDERAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO REGARD'
},
{
'ID': 2748,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GRITAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SHOUT'
},
{
'ID': 2749,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VIUDA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WIDOW'
},
{
'ID': 2750,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EFICAZ',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EFFECTIVE'
},
{
'ID': 2751,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LESIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'INJURY'
},
{
'ID': 2752,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DA IGUAL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IT DOESN\'T MATTER'
},
{
'ID': 2753,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NO VALE LA PENA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IT\'S NOT WORTH IT'
},
{
'ID': 2754,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'POR SI ACASO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'JUST IN CASE'
},
{
'ID': 2755,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AVERIA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BREAKDOWN,MALFUNCTION'
},
{
'ID': 2756,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EN GENERAL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ON THE WHOLE'
},
{
'ID': 2757,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PERSEVERANTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PERSEVERING'
},
{
'ID': 2758,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'OBRA DE TEATRO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PLAY'
},
{
'ID': 2759,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INDEPENDIENTEMENTE DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'REGARDLESS OF'
},
{
'ID': 2760,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COMENTARIO (CON CRITICA)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'REMARK'
},
{
'ID': 2761,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COMPAÑERO DE HABITACIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ROOMMATE'
},
{
'ID': 2762,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SARCASMO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SARCASM'
},
{
'ID': 2763,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CULEBRA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SNAKE'
},
{
'ID': 2764,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ETAPA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'STAGE'
},
{
'ID': 2765,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LOS AÑOS CINCUENTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THE FIFTIES'
},
{
'ID': 2766,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COOPERAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO COOPERATE'
},
{
'ID': 2767,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FINANCIAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO FINANCE'
},
{
'ID': 2768,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INFLUIR EN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO INFLUENCE'
},
{
'ID': 2769,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RECONOCER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO RECOGNIZE'
},
{
'ID': 2770,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DAR LA MANO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SHAKE HANDS'
},
{
'ID': 2771,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESACELERAR,IR MAS DESPACIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SLOW DOWN'
},
{
'ID': 2772,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TRADUCIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO TRANSLATE'
},
{
'ID': 2773,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONFIAR EN,FIARSE DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO TRUST'
},
{
'ID': 2774,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VOLUNTAD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WILL'
},
{
'ID': 2775,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VENTAJOSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ADVANTAGEOUS'
},
{
'ID': 2776,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RESPONSABLE DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IN CHARGE OF'
},
{
'ID': 2777,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'UBICACIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LOCATION'
},
{
'ID': 2778,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FLOJO,SUELTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LOOSE'
},
{
'ID': 2779,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LA HUMANIDAD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MANKIND'
},
{
'ID': 2780,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MADURO (PERSONAS)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MATURE'
},
{
'ID': 2781,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'QUIOSCO DE PRENSA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NEWSSTAND'
},
{
'ID': 2782,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CEBOLLA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ONION'
},
{
'ID': 2783,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PESIMISTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PESSIMISTIC'
},
{
'ID': 2784,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RENOVACIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RENEWAL'
},
{
'ID': 2785,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RECURSOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RESOURCES'
},
{
'ID': 2786,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ASUSTADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SCARED'
},
{
'ID': 2787,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TORMENTA DE NIEVE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SNOWSTORM'
},
{
'ID': 2788,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LOS AÑOS CUARENTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THE FORTIES'
},
{
'ID': 2789,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MUY PEQUEÑO,DIMINUTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TINY'
},
{
'ID': 2790,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ACERCARSE A',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO APPROACH'
},
{
'ID': 2791,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'APROBAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO APPROVE'
},
{
'ID': 2792,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'REFORZAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO REINFORCE'
},
{
'ID': 2793,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ACELERAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SPEED UP'
},
{
'ID': 2794,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AFIRMAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO STATE'
},
{
'ID': 2795,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PERDER TIEMPO (MALGASTAR)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO WASTE TIME'
},
{
'ID': 2796,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PERIODO DE PRUEBA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TRIAL PERIOD'
},
{
'ID': 2797,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INEVITABLE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'UNAVOIDABLE'
},
{
'ID': 2798,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PUNTO DÉBIL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WEAK POINT'
},
{
'ID': 2799,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': '¡VAYA FOLLÓN!',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WHAT A MESS!'
},
{
'ID': 2800,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AGRADECIMIENTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'APPRECIATION'
},
{
'ID': 2801,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CUESTA ABAJO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DOWNHILL'
},
{
'ID': 2802,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DE VEZ EN CUANDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EVERY ONCE IN A WHILE'
},
{
'ID': 2803,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NO TIENE SENTIDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IT DOESNT MAKE SENSE'
},
{
'ID': 2804,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PROBABLE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LIKELY'
},
{
'ID': 2805,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FUERZA LABORAL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MANPOWER'
},
{
'ID': 2806,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MÁXIMO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MAXIMUM'
},
{
'ID': 2807,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PESADILLA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NIGHTMARE'
},
{
'ID': 2808,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'OPTIMISTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'OPTIMISTIC'
},
{
'ID': 2809,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PASTILLA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PILL'
},
{
'ID': 2810,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PERFIL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PROFILE'
},
{
'ID': 2811,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RELACIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RELATIONSHIP'
},
{
'ID': 2812,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ASEO (EN LUGARES PÚBLICOS)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RESTROOM'
},
{
'ID': 2813,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENCUESTA,SONDEO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SURVEY'
},
{
'ID': 2814,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EL POLO NORTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THE NORTH POLE'
},
{
'ID': 2815,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EL POLO SUR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THE SOUTH POLE'
},
{
'ID': 2816,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NOMBRAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO APPOINT'
},
{
'ID': 2817,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VALORAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ASSESS'
},
{
'ID': 2818,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CARECER DE,FALTAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO LACK'
},
{
'ID': 2819,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LOCALIZAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO LOCATE'
},
{
'ID': 2820,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESPERAR CON ILUSIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO LOOK FORWARD TO'
},
{
'ID': 2821,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MEDIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO MEASURE'
},
{
'ID': 2822,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INTRODUCIR EN FASES',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO PHASE IN'
},
{
'ID': 2823,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LUCHAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO STRUGGLE'
},
{
'ID': 2824,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SOBREVIVIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SURVIVE'
},
{
'ID': 2825,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PUBLICIDAD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ADVERTISING'
},
{
'ID': 2826,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COMO DE COSTUMBRE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AS USUAL'
},
{
'ID': 2827,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VIDA PROFESIONAL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CAREER'
},
{
'ID': 2828,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FABRICANTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MANUFACTURER'
},
{
'ID': 2829,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MEDIOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MEANS'
},
{
'ID': 2830,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': '¡DE NINGUNA MANERA!,¡PARA NADA!',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NO WAY!'
},
{
'ID': 2831,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FUERA DE CONTEXTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'OUT OF CONTEXT'
},
{
'ID': 2832,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FASE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PHASE'
},
{
'ID': 2833,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RENTABILIDAD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PROFITABILITY'
},
{
'ID': 2834,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RELEVANTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RELEVANT'
},
{
'ID': 2835,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CURRICULUM VITAE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RESUME,CV'
},
{
'ID': 2836,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EGOÍSTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SELFISH'
},
{
'ID': 2837,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': '¡CÁLLATE!',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SHUT UP!'
},
{
'ID': 2838,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DE REPENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SUDDENLY'
},
{
'ID': 2839,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LA GOTA QUE COLMO EL VASO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THE LAST STRAW'
},
{
'ID': 2840,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LAS PAGINAS AMARILLAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THE YELLOW PAGES'
},
{
'ID': 2841,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INTENTAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ATTEMPT'
},
{
'ID': 2842,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ATREVERSE A',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO DARE'
},
{
'ID': 2843,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DEDICAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO DEVOTE'
},
{
'ID': 2844,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESPEDIR,ECHAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO FIRE'
},
{
'ID': 2845,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ELIMINAR EN FASES',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO PHASE OUT'
},
{
'ID': 2846,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PROGRAMAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SCHEDULE'
},
{
'ID': 2847,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HUNDIRSE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SINK'
},
{
'ID': 2848,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SUPERAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SURPASS'
},
{
'ID': 2849,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': '¿LE IMPORTARÍA...?',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WOULD YOU MIND...?'
},
{
'ID': 2850,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BENEFICIOSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BENEFICIAL'
},
{
'ID': 2851,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COMPARACIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'COMPARISON'
},
{
'ID': 2852,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SABOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FLAVOR'
},
{
'ID': 2853,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'IMPRESIONANTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IMPRESSIVE'
},
{
'ID': 2854,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FABRICACIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MANUFACTURING'
},
{
'ID': 2855,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MEDIDA,MEDICIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MEASUREMENT'
},
{
'ID': 2856,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FUERA DE CONTROL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'OUT OF CONTROL'
},
{
'ID': 2857,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MEDICO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PHYSICIAN'
},
{
'ID': 2858,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BENEFICIO Y PERDIDA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PROFIT AND LOSS'
},
{
'ID': 2859,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RECIBO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RECEIPT'
},
{
'ID': 2860,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FIABILIDAD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RELIABILITY'
},
{
'ID': 2861,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INGRESOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'REVENUE'
},
{
'ID': 2862,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RECTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'STRAIGHT'
},
{
'ID': 2863,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FUERZA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'STRENGTH'
},
{
'ID': 2864,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TEÓRICO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THEORETICAL'
},
{
'ID': 2865,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AUTORIZAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO AUTHORIZE'
},
{
'ID': 2866,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SER CONSCIENTE DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BE AWARE OF'
},
{
'ID': 2867,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SER OPTIMISTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BE OPTIMISTIC'
},
{
'ID': 2868,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENGAÑAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO DECEIVE'
},
{
'ID': 2869,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EVOLUCIONAR,DESARROLLAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO EVOLVE'
},
{
'ID': 2870,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CABER,AJUSTARSE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO FIT'
},
{
'ID': 2871,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VOLVERSE LOCO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO GO CRAZY'
},
{
'ID': 2872,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PASAR POR ALTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO OVERLOOK'
},
{
'ID': 2873,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ECHAR LA SIESTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO TAKE A NAP'
},
{
'ID': 2874,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ACOSTUMBRADO A',
        'RESPUESTA': 'USED TO'
},
{
'ID': 2875,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DECEPCIONADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DISAPPOINTED'
},
{
'ID': 2876,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MARMOL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MARBLE'
},
{
'ID': 2877,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CASI',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NEARLY'
},
{
'ID': 2878,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FISGÓN,COTILLA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NOSY'
},
{
'ID': 2879,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PASADO DE MODA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'OUT OF FASHION'
},
{
'ID': 2880,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'QUISQUILLOSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PICKY'
},
{
'ID': 2881,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DEMOSTRACIÓN,PRUEBA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PROOF'
},
{
'ID': 2882,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RETICENTE,REACIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RELUCTANT'
},
{
'ID': 2883,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COSTILLAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RIBS'
},
{
'ID': 2884,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SANO Y SALVO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SAFE AND SOUND'
},
{
'ID': 2885,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HASTA AHORA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SO FAR'
},
{
'ID': 2886,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LOS MEDIOS DE COMUNICACIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THE MEDIA'
},
{
'ID': 2887,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TORMENTA (ELÉCTRICA)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THUNDER STORM'
},
{
'ID': 2888,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EVITAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO AVOID'
},
{
'ID': 2889,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SALIR POR LA CULATA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BACKFIRE'
},
{
'ID': 2890,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DERROTAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO DEFEAT'
},
{
'ID': 2891,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FRACASAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO FAIL'
},
{
'ID': 2892,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DECEPCIONAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO LET DOWN'
},
{
'ID': 2893,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RECALCAR,SEÑALAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO POINT OUT'
},
{
'ID': 2894,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COMPRAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO PURCHASE'
},
{
'ID': 2895,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'REVISAR,REPASAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO REVIEW'
},
{
'ID': 2896,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DEJAR UNA PROPINA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO TIP'
},
{
'ID': 2897,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SUBRAYAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO UNDERLINE'
},
{
'ID': 2898,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CUESTA ARRIBA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'UPHILL'
},
{
'ID': 2899,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DEBILIDAD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WEAKNESS'
},
{
'ID': 2900,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CITA,COMPROMISO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'APPOINTMENT'
},
{
'ID': 2901,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENORME',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HUGE'
},
{
'ID': 2902,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MASACRE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MASSACRE'
},
{
'ID': 2903,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MEDIOCRE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MEDIOCRE'
},
{
'ID': 2904,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EN ABSOLUTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NOT AT ALL'
},
{
'ID': 2905,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AGOTADO (NO EN EXISTENCIA)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'OUT OF STOCK'
},
{
'ID': 2906,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MONTÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PILE'
},
{
'ID': 2907,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PROMETEDOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PROMISING'
},
{
'ID': 2908,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ADECUADO,APROPIADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PROPER'
},
{
'ID': 2909,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PROPUESTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PROPOSAL'
},
{
'ID': 2910,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ARROZ',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RICE'
},
{
'ID': 2911,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SATISFECHO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SATISFIED'
},
{
'ID': 2912,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HOMBRO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SHOULDER'
},
{
'ID': 2913,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AMENAZA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THREAT'
},
{
'ID': 2914,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'POR LO TANTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THUS'
},
{
'ID': 2915,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ACONSEJAR,ASESORAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ADVISE'
},
{
'ID': 2916,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BENEFICIARSE DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BENEFIT FROM'
},
{
'ID': 2917,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RETRASAR,DEMORAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO DELAY'
},
{
'ID': 2918,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PREVER,HACER UNA PREVISIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO FORECAST'
},
{
'ID': 2919,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LLEVARSE BIEN CON',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO GET ALONG WITH'
},
{
'ID': 2920,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RECOGER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO PICK UP'
},
{
'ID': 2921,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DEPENDER DE,CONFIAR EN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO RELY ON'
},
{
'ID': 2922,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AFEITARSE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SHAVE'
},
{
'ID': 2923,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TRAMPA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TRAP'
},
{
'ID': 2924,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TESTIGO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WITNESS'
},
{
'ID': 2925,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TODO EL TIEMPO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ALL THE TIME'
},
{
'ID': 2926,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RETO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CHALLENGE'
},
{
'ID': 2927,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'OBRA MAESTRA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MASTERPIECE'
},
{
'ID': 2928,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LIO,FOLLÓN,DESORDEN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MESS'
},
{
'ID': 2929,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NOCHE VIEJA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NEW YEAR\'S EVE'
},
{
'ID': 2930,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EN NOMBRE DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ON BEHALF OF'
},
{
'ID': 2931,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PRODUCCIÓN,RENDIMIENTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'OUTPUT'
},
{
'ID': 2932,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SACERDOTE,CURA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PRIEST'
},
{
'ID': 2933,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RENTABLE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PROFITABLE'
},
{
'ID': 2934,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RIESGO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RISK'
},
{
'ID': 2935,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BATA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ROBE'
},
{
'ID': 2936,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CUERDA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'STRING'
},
{
'ID': 2937,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TRABAJO EN EQUIPO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TEAMWORK'
},
{
'ID': 2938,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PEDIR PERDÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO APOLOGIZE'
},
{
'ID': 2939,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESTAR DISPUESTO A',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BE WILLING TO'
},
{
'ID': 2940,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ABURRIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BORE'
},
{
'ID': 2941,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESMORALIZAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO DEMORALIZE'
},
{
'ID': 2942,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NOTIFICAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO NOTIFY'
},
{
'ID': 2943,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LOCALIZAR,DETERMINAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO PINPOINT'
},
{
'ID': 2944,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PROMOCIONAR,PROMOVER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO PROMOTE'
},
{
'ID': 2945,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PROPONER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO PROPOSE'
},
{
'ID': 2946,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RECUPERARSE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO RECOVER'
},
{
'ID': 2947,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NEGARSE A',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO REFUSE'
},
{
'ID': 2948,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CHILLAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SCREAM'
},
{
'ID': 2949,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BASURA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TRASH, RUBBISH'
},
{
'ID': 2950,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'UNA AMPLIA GAMA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AWIDE RANGE'
},
{
'ID': 2951,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CLIENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CUSTOMER'
},
{
'ID': 2952,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EXIGENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DEMANDING'
},
{
'ID': 2953,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AGOTADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EXHAUSTED'
},
{
'ID': 2954,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EN TODO CASO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IN ANY CASE'
},
{
'ID': 2955,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GANADO (VACUNO, LANAR, ETC.)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LIVESTOCK'
},
{
'ID': 2956,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DOMINIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MASTERY'
},
{
'ID': 2957,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HORNO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'OVEN'
},
{
'ID': 2958,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BENEFICIOS (ECONÓMICOS)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PROFITS'
},
{
'ID': 2959,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PERSPECTIVAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PROSPECTS'
},
{
'ID': 2960,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PAPEL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ROLE'
},
{
'ID': 2961,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RUGOSO,ÁSPERO,TURBULENTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ROUGH'
},
{
'ID': 2962,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MARINO,MARINERO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SAILOR'
},
{
'ID': 2963,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LA EDAD MEDIA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THE MIDDLE AGES'
},
{
'ID': 2964,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ANALIZAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ANALYZE'
},
{
'ID': 2965,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SOLICITAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO APPLY FOR'
},
{
'ID': 2966,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ASEGURAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ASSURE'
},
{
'ID': 2967,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COMPORTARSE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BEHAVE'
},
{
'ID': 2968,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COLABORAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO COLLABORATE'
},
{
'ID': 2969,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ASUSTAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO FRIGHTEN'
},
{
'ID': 2970,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PASÁRSELO BIEN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO HAVE A GOOD TIME'
},
{
'ID': 2971,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TOMAR UNA DECISIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO MAKE A DECISION'
},
{
'ID': 2972,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COLOCAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO PLACE'
},
{
'ID': 2973,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PRESIONAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO PRESSURE'
},
{
'ID': 2974,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INCONSCIENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'UNCONSCIOUS'
},
{
'ID': 2975,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SEGÚN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ACCORDING TO'
},
{
'ID': 2976,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENFOQUE,PLANTEAMIENTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'APPROACH'
},
{
'ID': 2977,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'REFERENTE A',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CONCERNING'
},
{
'ID': 2978,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INCOMODO,INOPORTUNO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'UNCOMFORTABLE'
},
{
'ID': 2979,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'A LARGO PLAZO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LONG-RANGE'
},
{
'ID': 2980,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SIGNIFICATIVO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MEANINGFUL'
},
{
'ID': 2981,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MONJA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NUN'
},
{
'ID': 2982,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'OBVIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'OBVIOUS'
},
{
'ID': 2983,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GABARDINA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'OVERCOAT'
},
{
'ID': 2984,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'JUBILACIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RETIREMENT'
},
{
'ID': 2985,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TEJADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ROOF'
},
{
'ID': 2986,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HASTA AHORA TODO BIEN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SO FAR SO GOOD'
},
{
'ID': 2987,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ORIENTE MEDIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THE MIDDLE EAST'
},
{
'ID': 2988,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TRUENO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THUNDER'
},
{
'ID': 2989,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONFUNDIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO CONFUSE'
},
{
'ID': 2990,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NEGAR,DESMENTIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO DENY'
},
{
'ID': 2991,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DISEÑAR,IDEAR,CONCEBIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO DEVISE'
},
{
'ID': 2992,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HACER HINCAPIÉ EN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO EMPHASIZE'
},
{
'ID': 2993,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PROPORCIONAR,AMUEBLAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO FURNISH'
},
{
'ID': 2994,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CASTIGAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO PUNISH'
},
{
'ID': 2995,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RECHAZAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO REJECT'
},
{
'ID': 2996,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RESPONDER,CONTESTAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO REPLY'
},
{
'ID': 2997,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SALTAR,OMITIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SKIP'
},
{
'ID': 2998,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LANZAR,ARROJAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO THROW'
},
{
'ID': 2999,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ILIMITADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'UNLIMITED'
},
{
'ID': 3000,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'QUE YO SEPA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AS FAR AS I KNOW'
},
{
'ID': 3001,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FECHA TOPE,PLAZO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DEADLINE'
},
{
'ID': 3002,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'A LARGO PLAZO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LONG-TERM'
},
{
'ID': 3003,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SIN IMPORTANCIA,INSIGNIFICATIVO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MEANINGLESS'
},
{
'ID': 3004,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EN ULTRAMAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'OVERSEAS'
},
{
'ID': 3005,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DOLOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PAIN'
},
{
'ID': 3006,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'REPUTACIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'REPUTATION'
},
{
'ID': 3007,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RAÍZ',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ROOT'
},
{
'ID': 3008,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESCEPTICO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SKEPTICAL'
},
{
'ID': 3009,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ÉXITO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SUCCESS'
},
{
'ID': 3010,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BLANCO,DIANA,OBJETIVO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TARGET'
},
{
'ID': 3011,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EL COSTE DE LA VIDA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THE COST OF LIVING'
},
{
'ID': 3012,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SUMAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ADD UP'
},
{
'ID': 3013,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CULPAR,ECHAR LA CULPA A',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BLAME'
},
{
'ID': 3014,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONTRIBUIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO CONTRIBUTE'
},
{
'ID': 3015,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESANIMAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO DISCOURAGE'
},
{
'ID': 3016,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ANIMAR,ALENTAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ENCOURAGE'
},
{
'ID': 3017,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MATAR TIEMPO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO KILL TIME'
},
{
'ID': 3018,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RECORDAR (RECORDARLE A OTRO)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO REMIND'
},
{
'ID': 3019,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SOSPECHAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SUSPECT'
},
{
'ID': 3020,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ACTUALIZAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO UPDATE'
},
{
'ID': 3021,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DIGNO DE CONFIANZA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TRUSTWORTHY'
},
{
'ID': 3022,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INSATISFACTORIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'UNSATISFACTORY'
},
{
'ID': 3023,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TRIGO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WHEAT'
},
{
'ID': 3024,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DISPUESTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WILLING'
},
{
'ID': 3025,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'APROBACIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'APPROVAL'
},
{
'ID': 3026,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CAPAZ DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CAPABLE OF'
},
{
'ID': 3027,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DUDOSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DOUBTFUL'
},
{
'ID': 3028,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PEGAMENTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GLUE'
},
{
'ID': 3029,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MIENTRAS TANTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IN THE MEANTIME'
},
{
'ID': 3030,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'UNA IDEA GENERAL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AN OVERVIEW'
},
{
'ID': 3031,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TRIMESTRAL,TRIMESTRALMENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'QUARTERLY'
},
{
'ID': 3032,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PETICIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'REQUEST'
},
{
'ID': 3033,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HABITACIÓN Y PENSIÓN COMPLETA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ROOM AND BOARD'
},
{
'ID': 3034,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CUERDA,SOGA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ROPE'
},
{
'ID': 3035,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AGUDO,AFILADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SHARP'
},
{
'ID': 3036,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GRUESO,ESPESO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THICK'
},
{
'ID': 3037,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AGRADECER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO APPRECIATE'
},
{
'ID': 3038,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SACAR (UN TEMA)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BRING UP'
},
{
'ID': 3039,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COORDINAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO COORDINATE'
},
{
'ID': 3040,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESMANTELAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO DISMANTLE'
},
{
'ID': 3041,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TENER EN CUENTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO KEEP IN MIND'
},
{
'ID': 3042,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LEVANTAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO LIFT'
},
{
'ID': 3043,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CUIDAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO LOOK AFTER'
},
{
'ID': 3044,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ASEGURARSE DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO MAKE SURE'
},
{
'ID': 3045,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RESOLVER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SOLVE'
},
{
'ID': 3046,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'APRETAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO TIGHTEN'
},
{
'ID': 3047,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INESTABLE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'UNSTABLE'
},
{
'ID': 3048,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EXTRAÑO,RARO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'UNUSUAL'
},
{
'ID': 3049,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MODO DE VIVIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WAY OF LIFE'
},
{
'ID': 3050,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONFIANZA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CONFIDENCE'
},
{
'ID': 3051,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INSTALACIONES',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FACILITES'
},
{
'ID': 3052,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INVERSIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'INVESTMENT'
},
{
'ID': 3053,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HIERRO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IRON'
},
{
'ID': 3054,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FUSIÓN (DE EMPRESAS)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MERGER'
},
{
'ID': 3055,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DE MENTE ABIERTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'OPEN-MINDED'
},
{
'ID': 3056,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CLIP',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PAPER CLIP'
},
{
'ID': 3057,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONTENTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PLEASED'
},
{
'ID': 3058,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'POTENTE,PODEROSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'POWERFUL'
},
{
'ID': 3059,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'OCURRENTE,LISTO,PERSPICAZ',
        'RESPUESTA': 'QUICK-WITTED'
},
{
'ID': 3060,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FIABLE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RELIABLE'
},
{
'ID': 3061,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VIAJE DE IDA Y VUELTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ROUND TRIP'
},
{
'ID': 3062,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TENER EN CUENTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BEAR IN MIND'
},
{
'ID': 3063,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RESERVAR (MESA, HOTEL, ETC.)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BOOK'
},
{
'ID': 3064,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CANCELAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO CALL OFF'
},
{
'ID': 3065,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LLEVAR A CABO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO CARRY OUT'
},
{
'ID': 3066,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'APLASTAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO CRUSH'
},
{
'ID': 3067,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PONERSE NERVIOSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO GET NERVOUS'
},
{
'ID': 3068,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'REVISAR,REPASAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO LOOK OVER'
},
{
'ID': 3069,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NOTAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO NOTICE'
},
{
'ID': 3070,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PARECERSE A',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO RESEMBLE'
},
{
'ID': 3071,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DAR POR SENTADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO TAKE FOR GRANTED'
},
{
'ID': 3072,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INJUSTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'UNFAIR'
},
{
'ID': 3073,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ALTIBAJOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'UPS AND DOWNS'
},
{
'ID': 3074,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CERA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WAX'
},
{
'ID': 3075,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ALENTADOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ENCOURAGING'
},
{
'ID': 3076,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CRECIMIENTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GROWTH'
},
{
'ID': 3077,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'METICULOSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'METICULOUS'
},
{
'ID': 3078,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MILAGRO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MIRACLE'
},
{
'ID': 3079,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'POR SUPUESTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'OF COURSE'
},
{
'ID': 3080,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'APARCAMIENTO (EXTERIOR)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PARKING LOT'
},
{
'ID': 3081,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LA POLÍTICA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'POLITICS'
},
{
'ID': 3082,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ARCO IRIS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RAINBOW'
},
{
'ID': 3083,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PARIENTES,FAMILIARES',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RELATIVES'
},
{
'ID': 3084,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ALIVIADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RELIEVED'
},
{
'ID': 3085,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FILA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ROW'
},
{
'ID': 3086,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TOMA LAS COSAS CON FILOSOFÍA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TAKE IT EASY'
},
{
'ID': 3087,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TITULARES DE PRENSA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HEADLINES'
},
{
'ID': 3088,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'JACTARSE,PRESUMIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TOBRAG'
},
{
'ID': 3089,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PONERSE EN CONTACTO CON',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO CONTACT'
},
{
'ID': 3090,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TRATAR CON',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO DEAL WITH'
},
{
'ID': 3091,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DEMOSTRAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO DEMONSTRATE'
},
{
'ID': 3092,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PARECERSE A',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO LOOK LIKE'
},
{
'ID': 3093,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DIMITIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO RESIGN'
},
{
'ID': 3094,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AGUANTAR EL RITMO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO STAND THE PACE'
},
{
'ID': 3095,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HACER PUENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO TAKE A LONG WEEKEND'
},
{
'ID': 3096,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ADVERTIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO WARN'
},
{
'ID': 3097,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'IMPROBABLE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'UNLIKELY'
},
{
'ID': 3098,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TERCIOPELO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'VELVET'
},
{
'ID': 3099,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': '¿QUIEN SABE?',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WHO KNOWS?'
},
{
'ID': 3100,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DISPONIBLE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AVAILABLE'
},
{
'ID': 3101,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'JUSTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FAIR'
},
{
'ID': 3102,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PERDIDA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LOSS'
},
{
'ID': 3103,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SUAVE,TEMPLADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MILD'
},
{
'ID': 3104,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ATAQUE NERVIOSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NERVOUS BREAKDOWN'
},
{
'ID': 3105,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'A TIEMPO PARCIAL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PART TIME'
},
{
'ID': 3106,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LLUVIOSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RAINY'
},
{
'ID': 3107,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DIMISIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RESIGNATION'
},
{
'ID': 3108,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GOMA,CAUCHO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RUBBER'
},
{
'ID': 3109,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TÍMIDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SHY'
},
{
'ID': 3110,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PAPEL CELO,CINTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TAPE'
},
{
'ID': 3111,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AZULEJOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TILE'
},
{
'ID': 3112,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LOGRAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ACHIEVE'
},
{
'ID': 3113,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CLARIFICAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO CLARIFY'
},
{
'ID': 3114,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONTAR CON',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO COUNT ON'
},
{
'ID': 3115,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DISEÑAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO DESIGN'
},
{
'ID': 3116,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ELABORAR,CONFECCIONAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO DRAW UP'
},
{
'ID': 3117,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PARECERSE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO LOOKALIKE'
},
{
'ID': 3118,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COMETER FALTAS DE ORTOGRAFÍA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO MISSPELL'
},
{
'ID': 3119,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ALIVIAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO RELIEVE'
},
{
'ID': 3120,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VARIAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO VARY'
},
{
'ID': 3121,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PESAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO WEIGH'
},
{
'ID': 3122,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VALIOSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'VALUABLE'
},
{
'ID': 3123,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PUNTO DE VISTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'VIEWPOINT'
},
{
'ID': 3124,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SIN DUDA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WITHOUT A DOUBT'
},
{
'ID': 3125,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'A LA LARGA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IN THE LONG RUN'
},
{
'ID': 3126,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MALA INTERPRETACIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MISINTERPRETATION'
},
{
'ID': 3127,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EQUIVOCADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MISTAKEN'
},
{
'ID': 3128,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PAUTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PATTERN'
},
{
'ID': 3129,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PERSONAL (DE PLANTILLA)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PERSONNEL'
},
{
'ID': 3130,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PORTÁTIL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PORTABLE'
},
{
'ID': 3131,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RELACIÓN,COMPENETRACIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RAPPORT'
},
{
'ID': 3132,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DEPENDIENTE DE TIENDA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SALES CLERK'
},
{
'ID': 3133,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HABILIDAD,PERICIA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SKILL'
},
{
'ID': 3134,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ADOLESCENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TEENAGER'
},
{
'ID': 3135,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VALER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BE WORTH'
},
{
'ID': 3136,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RESPIRAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BREATHE'
},
{
'ID': 3137,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CRITICAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO CRITICIZE'
},
{
'ID': 3138,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EXIGIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO DEMAND'
},
{
'ID': 3139,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DETERMINAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO DETERMINE'
},
{
'ID': 3140,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ADIVINAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO GUESS'
},
{
'ID': 3141,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INVERTIR (DINERO, TIEMPO)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO INVEST'
},
{
'ID': 3142,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INVESTIGAR (UN ASUNTO)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO LOOK INTO'
},
{
'ID': 3143,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RECURRIRÁ',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO RESORT TO'
},
{
'ID': 3144,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COMPARTIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SHARE'
},
{
'ID': 3145,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESPERDICIAR,MALGASTAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO WASTE'
},
{
'ID': 3146,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TRUCO,TRAMPA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TRICK'
},
{
'ID': 3147,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INCONSTANTE,DE POCA CONFIANZA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'UNRELIABLE'
},
{
'ID': 3148,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VIRTUD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'VIRTUE'
},
{
'ID': 3149,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CABLE,ALAMBRE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WIRE'
},
{
'ID': 3150,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EN VOZ ALTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ALOUD'
},
{
'ID': 3151,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BASADO EN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BASED ON'
},
{
'ID': 3152,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DINERO EN METÁLICO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CASH'
},
{
'ID': 3153,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'O SEA,EN OTRAS PALABRAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IN OTHER WORDS'
},
{
'ID': 3154,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MODESTIA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MODESTY'
},
{
'ID': 3155,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NOMINA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PAYROLL'
},
{
'ID': 3156,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INGENIOSO,QUE TIENE RECURSOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RESOURCEFUL'
},
{
'ID': 3157,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VENDEDOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SALESPERSON'
},
{
'ID': 3158,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DOLOR DE GARGANTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SORE THROAT'
},
{
'ID': 3159,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SER ABURRIDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BE BORING'
},
{
'ID': 3160,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONVENCER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO CONVINCE'
},
{
'ID': 3161,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MERECER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO DESERVE'
},
{
'ID': 3162,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESTAR EN DESACUERDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO DISAGREE'
},
{
'ID': 3163,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESPEDIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO DISMISS'
},
{
'ID': 3164,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PERMITIR,POSIBILITAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ENABLE'
},
{
'ID': 3165,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONTRATAR (A EMPLEADOS)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO HIRE'
},
{
'ID': 3166,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MALTRATAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO MISTREAT'
},
{
'ID': 3167,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'POSPONER,APLAZAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO POSTPONE'
},
{
'ID': 3168,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DEMOSTRAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO PROVE'
},
{
'ID': 3169,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CLASIFICAR,VALORAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO RATE'
},
{
'ID': 3170,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ARREPENTIRSE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO REGRET'
},
{
'ID': 3171,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SATISFACER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SATISFY'
},
{
'ID': 3172,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RIZAR EL RIZO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SPLIT HAIRS'
},
{
'ID': 3173,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ATAR CABOS SUELTOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO TIE LOOSE ENDS'
},
{
'ID': 3174,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ALIANZA DE BODAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WEDDING RING'
},
{
'ID': 3175,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESCUIDADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CARELESS'
},
{
'ID': 3176,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AJEDREZ',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CHESS'
},
{
'ID': 3177,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SENTIDO COMÚN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'COMMON SENSE'
},
{
'ID': 3178,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CIFRAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FIGURES'
},
{
'ID': 3179,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PREVISIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FORECAST'
},
{
'ID': 3180,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LA MORAL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MORALE'
},
{
'ID': 3181,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AL CONTRARIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ON THE CONTRARY'
},
{
'ID': 3182,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PACIFICO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PEACEFUL'
},
{
'ID': 3183,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VENENO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'POISON'
},
{
'ID': 3184,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'APLAZAMIENTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'POSTPONEMENT'
},
{
'ID': 3185,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PROCEDIMIENTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PROCEDURE'
},
{
'ID': 3186,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ALGO,UN TANTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SOMEWHAT'
},
{
'ID': 3187,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'REFERENTE A',
        'RESPUESTA': 'REGARDING'
},
{
'ID': 3188,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INQUIETO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RESTLESS'
},
{
'ID': 3189,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SALADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SALTY'
},
{
'ID': 3190,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DOMINAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO DOMINATE'
},
{
'ID': 3191,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HACER CUMPLIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ENFORCE'
},
{
'ID': 3192,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RELLENAR (IMPRESOS)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO FILL OUT'
},
{
'ID': 3193,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'APAÑARSE,SALIR DEL PASO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO GET BY'
},
{
'ID': 3194,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DUDAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO HESITATE'
},
{
'ID': 3195,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AFLOJAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO LOOSEN'
},
{
'ID': 3196,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MALENTENDER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO MISUNDERSTAND'
},
{
'ID': 3197,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TIRAR (A LA BASURA)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO THROW AWAY'
},
{
'ID': 3198,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TEMA (DE CONVERSACIÓN)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TOPIC'
},
{
'ID': 3199,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BIEN HECHO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WELL-DONE'
},
{
'ID': 3200,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PAYASO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CLOWN'
},
{
'ID': 3201,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COMPROMISO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'COMMITMENT'
},
{
'ID': 3202,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PERICIA,HABILIDAD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EXPERTISE'
},
{
'ID': 3203,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HIPOTECA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MORTGAGE'
},
{
'ID': 3204,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HOY EN DÍA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NOWADAYS'
},
{
'ID': 3205,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DE OTRO MODO,SI NO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'OTHERWISE'
},
{
'ID': 3206,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CACAHUETES',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PEANUTS'
},
{
'ID': 3207,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MUESTRA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SAMPLE'
},
{
'ID': 3208,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HASTA CIERTO PUNTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO A CERTAIN EXTENT'
},
{
'ID': 3209,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'APOSTAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BET'
},
{
'ID': 3210,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DUDAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO DOUBT'
},
{
'ID': 3211,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ARRASTRAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO DRAG'
},
{
'ID': 3212,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'REALZAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ENHANCE'
},
{
'ID': 3213,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PERDONAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO FORGIVE'
},
{
'ID': 3214,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LIARSE,CONFUNDIRSE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO GET MIXED UP'
},
{
'ID': 3215,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'REUNIRSE (INFORMALMENTE)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO GET TOGETHER'
},
{
'ID': 3216,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HACER DAÑO,PERJUDICAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO HURT'
},
{
'ID': 3217,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RESTRINGIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO RESTRICT'
},
{
'ID': 3218,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ASUSTAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SCARE'
},
{
'ID': 3219,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SUGERIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SUGGEST'
},
{
'ID': 3220,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RETIRAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO WITHDRAW'
},
{
'ID': 3221,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ADVERTENCIA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WARNING'
},
{
'ID': 3222,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ADINERADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WEALTHY'
},
{
'ID': 3223,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PESO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WEIGHT'
},
{
'ID': 3224,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BIEN INFORMADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WELL-INFORMED'
},
{
'ID': 3225,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MONEDA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'COIN'
},
{
'ID': 3226,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'QUEJA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'COMPLAINT'
},
{
'ID': 3227,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ME ALEGRO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'I\'M GLAD'
},
{
'ID': 3228,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESTADO DE ANIMO,HUMOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MOOD'
},
{
'ID': 3229,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CHAMPIÑONES',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MUSHROOMS'
},
{
'ID': 3230,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EXTROVERTIDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'OUTGOING'
},
{
'ID': 3231,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GUISANTES',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PEAS'
},
{
'ID': 3232,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ELOGIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PRAISE'
},
{
'ID': 3233,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PRESIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PRESSURE'
},
{
'ID': 3234,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MATERIAS PRIMAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RAW MATERIALS'
},
{
'ID': 3235,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SALSA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SAUCE'
},
{
'ID': 3236,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LISO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SMOOTH'
},
{
'ID': 3237,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FABULOSO,GENIAL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TERRIFIC'
},
{
'ID': 3238,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GARGANTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THROAT'
},
{
'ID': 3239,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESTAR DE ACUERDO CON',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO AGREE WITH'
},
{
'ID': 3240,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ASEGURAR VERIFICANDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO CHECK ON'
},
{
'ID': 3241,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EXAGERAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO EXAGGERATE'
},
{
'ID': 3242,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ABANDONAR,TIRAR LA TOALLA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO GIVE UP'
},
{
'ID': 3243,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'OCULTAR,ESCONDER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO HIDE'
},
{
'ID': 3244,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NO HACER CASO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO IGNORE'
},
{
'ID': 3245,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PASAR LA PELOTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO PASS THE BUCK'
},
{
'ID': 3246,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'REANUDAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO RESUME'
},
{
'ID': 3247,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EXTENDERSE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SPREAD'
},
{
'ID': 3248,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'APRECIADO POR TODOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WELL-LIKED'
},
{
'ID': 3249,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SALVAJE,SILVESTRE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WILD'
},
{
'ID': 3250,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CRITERIOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CRITERIA'
},
{
'ID': 3251,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EN VEZ DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'INSTEAD OF'
},
{
'ID': 3252,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VOLUBLE,CAMBIA MUCHO DE HUMOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MOODY'
},
{
'ID': 3253,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MEJILLONES',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MUSSELS'
},
{
'ID': 3254,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': '¡NO ME EXTRAÑA QUE...!',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NO WONDER ...!'
},
{
'ID': 3255,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EN LAS AFUERAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ON THE OUTSKIRTS'
},
{
'ID': 3256,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PERSUASIVO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PERSUASIVE'
},
{
'ID': 3257,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ORGULLOSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PROUD'
},
{
'ID': 3258,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'I+D (INVESTIGACIÓN Y DESARROLLO)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'R&D'
},
{
'ID': 3259,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VENGANZA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'REVENGE'
},
{
'ID': 3260,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CUENTA DE AHORRO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SAVINGS ACCOUNT'
},
{
'ID': 3261,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CENTRO COMERCIAL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SHOPPING CENTER'
},
{
'ID': 3262,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SUPONER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ASSUME'
},
{
'ID': 3263,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ASEGURAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ENSURE'
},
{
'ID': 3264,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FACILITAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO FACILITATE'
},
{
'ID': 3265,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENTORPECER,PONER TRABAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO HINDER'
},
{
'ID': 3266,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'IMPRESIONAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO IMPRESS'
},
{
'ID': 3267,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INVOLUCRAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO INVOLVE'
},
{
'ID': 3268,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HACER BAJAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO LOWER'
},
{
'ID': 3269,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ELOGIAR,ALABAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO PRAISE'
},
{
'ID': 3270,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'REACCIONAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO REACT'
},
{
'ID': 3271,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DIRIGIR (COMPAÑÍA O DPTO.)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO RUN'
},
{
'ID': 3272,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AHORRAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SAVE'
},
{
'ID': 3273,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'OLAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WAVES'
},
{
'ID': 3274,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BIEN HECHO (UN OBJETO)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WELL-MADE'
},
{
'ID': 3275,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'UNA REUNIÓN AMISTOSA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'A GET-TOGETHER'
},
{
'ID': 3276,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AVERIA,DESGLOSE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BREAKDOWN'
},
{
'ID': 3277,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DEBIDO A',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DUE TO'
},
{
'ID': 3278,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RELÁMPAGO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LIGHTNING'
},
{
'ID': 3279,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MUTUO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MUTUAL'
},
{
'ID': 3280,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FARMACÉUTICO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PHARMACIST'
},
{
'ID': 3281,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'UN POLÍTICO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'A POLITICIAN'
},
{
'ID': 3282,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'UNA POSTAL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'A POSTCARD'
},
{
'ID': 3283,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DIGNO DE ELOGIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PRAISEWORTHY'
},
{
'ID': 3284,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INMOBILIARIA,BIENES RAICES',
        'RESPUESTA': 'REAL ESTATE'
},
{
'ID': 3285,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RECOMPENSA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'REWARD'
},
{
'ID': 3286,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SUGERENCIA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SUGGESTION'
},
{
'ID': 3287,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LOS MOROS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THE MOORS'
},
{
'ID': 3288,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'POR LO TANTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THEREFORE'
},
{
'ID': 3289,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LOGRAR,CONSEGUIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ACCOMPLISH'
},
{
'ID': 3290,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ADJUNTAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ENCLOSE'
},
{
'ID': 3291,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EXPULSAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO EXPEL'
},
{
'ID': 3292,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INUNDAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO FLOOD'
},
{
'ID': 3293,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MANEJAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO HANDLE'
},
{
'ID': 3294,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ASEGURARSE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO MAKE CERTAIN'
},
{
'ID': 3295,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SUPERAR,SOBREPONERSE A',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO OVERCOME'
},
{
'ID': 3296,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DAR EJEMPLO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SET AN EXAMPLE'
},
{
'ID': 3297,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESCARGAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO UNLOAD'
},
{
'ID': 3298,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ACOMODADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WELL-OFF'
},
{
'ID': 3299,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': '¿QUE PASA?',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WHAT\'S THE MATTER?'
},
{
'ID': 3300,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ELECCIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CHOICE'
},
{
'ID': 3301,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CIERVO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DEER'
},
{
'ID': 3302,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESVENTAJA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DISADVANTAGE'
},
{
'ID': 3303,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FRACASO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FAILURE'
},
{
'ID': 3304,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ES UNA PERDIDA DE TIEMPO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IT\'S POINTLESS'
},
{
'ID': 3305,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PRINCIPALMENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MAINLY'
},
{
'ID': 3306,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MUTUAMENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MUTUALLY'
},
{
'ID': 3307,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GLOBAL,TOTAL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'OVERALL'
},
{
'ID': 3308,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RITMO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PACE'
},
{
'ID': 3309,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'REALISTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'REALISTIC'
},
{
'ID': 3310,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESCASEZ',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SCARCITY'
},
{
'ID': 3311,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONFIANZA EN UNO MISMO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SELF-CONFIDENCE'
},
{
'ID': 3312,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RASCACIELOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SKYSCRAPER'
},
{
'ID': 3313,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RETAR,DESAFIAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO CHALLENGE'
},
{
'ID': 3314,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENTREGAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO DELIVER'
},
{
'ID': 3315,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CADUCAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO EXPIRE'
},
{
'ID': 3316,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DOBLAR,PLEGAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO FOLD'
},
{
'ID': 3317,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DAR UN PASEO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO GO FOR A WALK'
},
{
'ID': 3318,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SUJETAR,SOSTENER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO HOLD'
},
{
'ID': 3319,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COMPLACER,AGRADAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO PLEASE'
},
{
'ID': 3320,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PRECEDER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO PRECEDE'
},
{
'ID': 3321,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PROPORCIONAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO PROVIDE'
},
{
'ID': 3322,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SUDAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SWEAT'
},
{
'ID': 3323,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INÚTIL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'USELESS'
},
{
'ID': 3324,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BIEN PLANIFICADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WELL-PLANNED'
},
{
'ID': 3325,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONSEJO,ASESORAMIENTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ADVICE'
},
{
'ID': 3326,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CÓMODO,OPORTUNO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CONVENIENT'
},
{
'ID': 3327,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESANIMADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DISCOURAGED'
},
{
'ID': 3328,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'UN DÍA SI Y OTRO NO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EVERY OTHER DAY'
},
{
'ID': 3329,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'IMPUESTO SOBRE LA RENTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'INCOME TAX'
},
{
'ID': 3330,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': '!MENOS MAL!',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IT\'S A GOOD THING!'
},
{
'ID': 3331,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CLAVO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NAIL'
},
{
'ID': 3332,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'A CAUSA DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ON ACCOUNT OF'
},
{
'ID': 3333,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EN CAMBIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ON THE OTHER HAND'
},
{
'ID': 3334,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HORAS EXTRAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'OVERTIME'
},
{
'ID': 3335,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VENENOSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'POISONOUS'
},
{
'ID': 3336,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ANTERIOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PRECEDING'
},
{
'ID': 3337,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MANO DERECHA (PERSONA)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RIGHT-HAND MAN'
},
{
'ID': 3338,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TORNILLO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SCREW'
},
{
'ID': 3339,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'APROPIADO,IDÓNEO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SUITABLE'
},
{
'ID': 3340,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESTAR DE MAL HUMOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BE IN A BAD MOOD'
},
{
'ID': 3341,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COBRAR,CARGAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO CHARGE'
},
{
'ID': 3342,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PROLONGAR,EXTENDER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO EXTEND'
},
{
'ID': 3343,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PREVER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO FORESEE'
},
{
'ID': 3344,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SER GOLOSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO HAVE A SWEET TOOTH'
},
{
'ID': 3345,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'IMPLANTAR,PONER EN PRACTICA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO IMPLEMENT'
},
{
'ID': 3346,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RAZONAR CON',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO REASON WITH'
},
{
'ID': 3347,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESTROPEAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO RUIN'
},
{
'ID': 3348,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DÉBIL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WEAK'
},
{
'ID': 3349,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BIEN TRATADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WELL-TREATED'
},
{
'ID': 3350,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESALENTADOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DISCOURAGING'
},
{
'ID': 3351,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SUPONGO QUE SI',
        'RESPUESTA': 'I GUESS SO'
},
{
'ID': 3352,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'A PESAR DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IN SPITE OF'
},
{
'ID': 3353,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CRUCE (DE CALLES)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'INTERSECTION'
},
{
'ID': 3354,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SIESTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NAP'
},
{
'ID': 3355,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INGENUO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NAIVE'
},
{
'ID': 3356,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'A PROPOSITO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ON PURPOSE'
},
{
'ID': 3357,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DOLOROSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PAINFUL'
},
{
'ID': 3358,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RETRATO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PORTRAIT'
},
{
'ID': 3359,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TASA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RATE'
},
{
'ID': 3360,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SEGURO DE SI MISMO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SELF-CONFIDENT'
},
{
'ID': 3361,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'APRETADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TIGHT'
},
{
'ID': 3362,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DISCUTIR (ACALORADAMENTE)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ARGUE'
},
{
'ID': 3363,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'REPARAR,ARREGLAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO FIX'
},
{
'ID': 3364,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PERDERSE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO GET LOST'
},
{
'ID': 3365,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DAR UN PASEO (EN COCHE)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO GO FOR A DRIVE'
},
{
'ID': 3366,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DAR A ENTENDER,IMPLICAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO IMPLY'
},
{
'ID': 3367,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PREDECIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO PREDICT'
},
{
'ID': 3368,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TRANQUILIZAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO REASSURE'
},
{
'ID': 3369,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RESUMIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SUMMARIZE'
},
{
'ID': 3370,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'APROVECHAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO TAKE ADVANTAGE OF'
},
{
'ID': 3371,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'APUNTAR (ESCRIBIENDO)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO WRITE DOWN'
},
{
'ID': 3372,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TENDENCIA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TREND'
},
{
'ID': 3373,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BIENESTAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WELFARE'
},
{
'ID': 3374,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SILLA DE RUEDAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WHEELCHAIR'
},
{
'ID': 3375,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INGRESOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'INCOME'
},
{
'ID': 3376,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SERVILLETA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NAPKIN'
},
{
'ID': 3377,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AGUJA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NEEDLE'
},
{
'ID': 3378,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PALMERA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PALM TREE'
},
{
'ID': 3379,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ORACIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PRAYER'
},
{
'ID': 3380,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EMBARAZADA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PREGNANT'
},
{
'ID': 3381,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BASTANTES',
        'RESPUESTA': 'QUITE A FEW'
},
{
'ID': 3382,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AUTODISCIPLINA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SELF-DISCIPLINE'
},
{
'ID': 3383,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NIVEL DE VIDA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'STANDARD OF LIVING'
},
{
'ID': 3384,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PROVISIONES',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SUPPLIES'
},
{
'ID': 3385,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LA PRENSA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THE PRESS'
},
{
'ID': 3386,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ADQUIRIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ACQUIRE'
},
{
'ID': 3387,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PERMITIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ALLOW'
},
{
'ID': 3388,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HACER TRAMPA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO CHEAT'
},
{
'ID': 3389,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ELEGIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO CHOOSE'
},
{
'ID': 3390,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ILUSTRAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ILLUSTRATE'
},
{
'ID': 3391,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'IMPROVISAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO IMPROVISE'
},
{
'ID': 3392,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PRESTAR ATENCIÓN A',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO PAY ATTENTION TO'
},
{
'ID': 3393,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ACORDARSE DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO RECALL'
},
{
'ID': 3394,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RENOVAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO RENEW'
},
{
'ID': 3395,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DEPENDER DE (JERÁRQUICAMENTE)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO REPORT TO'
},
{
'ID': 3396,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SIMPLIFICAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SIMPLIFY'
},
{
'ID': 3397,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENVOLVER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO WRAP'
},
{
'ID': 3398,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BODEGA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WINE CELLAR'
},
{
'ID': 3399,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PRUDENTE,JUICIOSO,SABIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WISE'
},
{
'ID': 3400,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AVERGONZADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ASHAMED'
},
{
'ID': 3401,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DIRECTRICES',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GUIDELINES'
},
{
'ID': 3402,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DE MENTE ESTRECHA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NARROW-MINDED'
},
{
'ID': 3403,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NEGLIGENCIA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NEGLIGENCE'
},
{
'ID': 3404,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'POBREZA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'POVERTY'
},
{
'ID': 3405,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RECETA (MEDICA)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PRESCRIPTION'
},
{
'ID': 3406,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CRUDO,NO COCINADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RAW'
},
{
'ID': 3407,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'REQUISITOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'REQUIREMENTS'
},
{
'ID': 3408,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'APROXIMADAMENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ROUGHLY'
},
{
'ID': 3409,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MAL EDUCADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RUDE'
},
{
'ID': 3410,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PAISAJE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SCENERY'
},
{
'ID': 3411,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AUTÓNOMO (TRABAJADOR)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SELF-EMPLOYED'
},
{
'ID': 3412,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESDE CUANDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SINCE WHEN'
},
{
'ID': 3413,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESTAR ABURRIDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BE BORED'
},
{
'ID': 3414,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TENER GANAS DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO FEEL LIKE'
},
{
'ID': 3415,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HEREDAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO INHERIT'
},
{
'ID': 3416,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INSTALAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO INSTALL'
},
{
'ID': 3417,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DEBER (DINERO, UN FAVOR, ETC.)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO OWE'
},
{
'ID': 3418,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AMENAZAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO THREATEN'
},
{
'ID': 3419,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESAGRADABLE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'UNPLEASANT'
},
{
'ID': 3420,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'IMPOPULAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'UNPOPULAR'
},
{
'ID': 3421,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VOLUMEN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'VOLUME'
},
{
'ID': 3422,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BODA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WEDDING'
},
{
'ID': 3423,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CAPRICHO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WHIM'
},
{
'ID': 3424,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SABIDURÍA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WISDOM'
},
{
'ID': 3425,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESPIERTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AWAKE'
},
{
'ID': 3426,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ME TRAE SIN CUIDADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'I DON\'T CARE'
},
{
'ID': 3427,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MIENTRAS TANTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MEANWHILE'
},
{
'ID': 3428,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LA NATURALEZA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NATURE'
},
{
'ID': 3429,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NEGOCIABLE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NEGOTIABLE'
},
{
'ID': 3430,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INTIMIDAD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PRIVACY'
},
{
'ID': 3431,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONTRATACIÓN DE PERSONAL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RECRUITMENT'
},
{
'ID': 3432,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TARDE O TEMPRANO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SOONER OR LATER'
},
{
'ID': 3433,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TERCO,TESTARUDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'STUBBORN'
},
{
'ID': 3434,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DE ÉXITO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SUCCESSFUL'
},
{
'ID': 3435,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'IMPUESTOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TAXES'
},
{
'ID': 3436,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MOLESTAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BOTHER'
},
{
'ID': 3437,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RESULTAR ÚTIL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO COME IN HANDY'
},
{
'ID': 3438,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MEJORAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO IMPROVE'
},
{
'ID': 3439,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LESIONAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO INJURE'
},
{
'ID': 3440,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'JUSTIFICAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO JUSTIFY'
},
{
'ID': 3441,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DURAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO LAST'
},
{
'ID': 3442,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PULSAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO PRESS'
},
{
'ID': 3443,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESCARTAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO RULE OUT'
},
{
'ID': 3444,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DURO,DIFÍCIL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TOUGH'
},
{
'ID': 3445,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TRADUCCIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TRANSLATION'
},
{
'ID': 3446,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TESORO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TREASURE'
},
{
'ID': 3447,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PROBLEMAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TROUBLE'
},
{
'ID': 3448,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SIEMPRE QUE...',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WHENEVER...'
},
{
'ID': 3449,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BRUJA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WITCH'
},
{
'ID': 3450,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ÁGUILA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EAGLE'
},
{
'ID': 3451,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ÉNFASIS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EMPHASIS'
},
{
'ID': 3452,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': '¡DATE PRISA!',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HURRY UP!'
},
{
'ID': 3453,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': '!YA ERA HORA!',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IT\'S ABOUT TIME!'
},
{
'ID': 3454,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ÚLTIMAMENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LATELY'
},
{
'ID': 3455,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NIDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NEST'
},
{
'ID': 3456,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SENDA,SENDERO,VEREDA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PATH'
},
{
'ID': 3457,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EDUCADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'POLITE'
},
{
'ID': 3458,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PRESTIGIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PRESTIGE'
},
{
'ID': 3459,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PRIVILEGIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PRIVILEGE'
},
{
'ID': 3460,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ALMA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SOUL'
},
{
'ID': 3461,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COMPASIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SYMPATHY'
},
{
'ID': 3462,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'IMPROVISAR (HABLANDO)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO AD-LIB'
},
{
'ID': 3463,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PERMITIRSE EL LUJO DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO AFFORD'
},
{
'ID': 3464,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'QUEJARSE DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO COMPLAIN ABOUT'
},
{
'ID': 3465,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DECEPCIONAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO DISAPPOINT'
},
{
'ID': 3466,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TOMAR UNA COPA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO HAVE A DRINK'
},
{
'ID': 3467,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENLAZAR,UNIR,ACOPLAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO LINK'
},
{
'ID': 3468,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DIRIGIR,APAÑARSE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO MANAGE'
},
{
'ID': 3469,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SUSTITUIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO REPLACE'
},
{
'ID': 3470,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'QUITAR,EXTRAER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO REMOVE'
},
{
'ID': 3471,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CORRER RIESGOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO RUN RISKS'
},
{
'ID': 3472,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONVERTIRSE EN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO TURN INTO'
},
{
'ID': 3473,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ÚNICO EN SU GENERO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'UNIQUE'
},
{
'ID': 3474,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TENER ÉXITO,TRIUNFAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SUCCEED'
},
{
'ID': 3475,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ADEMAS (DE)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BESIDES'
},
{
'ID': 3476,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONFIADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CONFIDENT'
},
{
'ID': 3477,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EN UN ABRIR Y CERRAR DE OJOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IN NO TIME'
},
{
'ID': 3478,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MALENTENDIDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MISUNDERSTANDING'
},
{
'ID': 3479,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CERCANO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NEARBY'
},
{
'ID': 3480,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SIN DUDA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NO DOUBT'
},
{
'ID': 3481,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PENDIENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PENDING'
},
{
'ID': 3482,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'POLÍTICA (DE ACTUACIÓN)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'POLICY'
},
{
'ID': 3483,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PRESTIGIOSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PRESTIGIOUS'
},
{
'ID': 3484,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENSEGUIDA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PROMPTLY'
},
{
'ID': 3485,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GRAPA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'STAPLE'
},
{
'ID': 3486,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LA DIRECCIÓN (EMPRESARIAL)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THE MANAGEMENT'
},
{
'ID': 3487,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CUANTO ANTES MEJOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THE SOONER THE BETTER'
},
{
'ID': 3488,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AGRAVAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO AGGRAVATE'
},
{
'ID': 3489,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TENER PRISA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BE IN A HURRY'
},
{
'ID': 3490,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PEDIR PRESTADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BORROW'
},
{
'ID': 3491,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COMPETIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO COMPETE'
},
{
'ID': 3492,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONTRADECIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO CONTRADICT'
},
{
'ID': 3493,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HACER UN SEGUIMIENTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO FOLLOW UP'
},
{
'ID': 3494,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TENER INTENCIÓN DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO INTEND'
},
{
'ID': 3495,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CERRAR CON LLAVE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO LOCK'
},
{
'ID': 3496,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PEGÁRSELE LAS SABANAS A UNO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO OVERSLEEP'
},
{
'ID': 3497,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TROPEZAR CON,ENCONTRARSE CON',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO RUN INTO'
},
{
'ID': 3498,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EL PARO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'UNEMPLOYMENT'
},
{
'ID': 3499,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VARIEDAD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'VARIETY'
},
{
'ID': 3500,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AUNQUE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ALTHOUGH'
},
{
'ID': 3501,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MAS VALE TARDE QUE NUNCA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BETTER LATE THAN NEVER'
},
{
'ID': 3502,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SEMANA SANTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EASTER'
},
{
'ID': 3503,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'OBLIGATORIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MANDATORY'
},
{
'ID': 3504,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MIOPE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NEARSIGHTED'
},
{
'ID': 3505,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NOVELA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NOVEL'
},
{
'ID': 3506,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PORCENTAJE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PERCENTAGE'
},
{
'ID': 3507,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PROXIMIDAD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PROXIMITY'
},
{
'ID': 3508,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PAPELEO BUROCRÁTICO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RED TAPE'
},
{
'ID': 3509,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GRAPADORA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'STAPLER'
},
{
'ID': 3510,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'APUNTAR (CON ARMA)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO AIM'
},
{
'ID': 3511,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ACLARAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO CLEAR UP'
},
{
'ID': 3512,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TEMER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO FEAR'
},
{
'ID': 3513,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AVERIGUAR,DESCUBRIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO FIND OUT'
},
{
'ID': 3514,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PUBLICAR,EMITIR,LANZAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ISSUE'
},
{
'ID': 3515,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BUSCAR (COMO CONSULTA)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO LOOK UP'
},
{
'ID': 3516,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ECHAR DE MENOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO MISS'
},
{
'ID': 3517,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FINGIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO PRETEND'
},
{
'ID': 3518,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DARSE CUENTA DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO REALIZE'
},
{
'ID': 3519,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ARRIESGAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO RISK'
},
{
'ID': 3520,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ATROPELLAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO RUN OVER'
},
{
'ID': 3521,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SEGUIR EN CONTACTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO STAY IN TOUCH'
},
{
'ID': 3522,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INESPERADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'UNEXPECTED'
},
{
'ID': 3523,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AL REVÉS (POSICIÓN INVERTIDA)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'UPSIDE DOWN'
},
{
'ID': 3524,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ÚTIL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'USEFUL'
},
{
'ID': 3525,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VIVO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ALIVE'
},
{
'ID': 3526,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'POR AHORA,DE MOMENTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FOR THE TIME BEING'
},
{
'ID': 3527,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MATRIMONIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MARRIAGE'
},
{
'ID': 3528,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NECESIDADES',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NEEDS'
},
{
'ID': 3529,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NOVEDAD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NOVELTY'
},
{
'ID': 3530,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PAGO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PAYMENT'
},
{
'ID': 3531,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DE SOBRA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PLENTY OF'
},
{
'ID': 3532,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PSICOLÓGICO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PSYCHOLOGICAL'
},
{
'ID': 3533,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ARRIESGADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RISKY'
},
{
'ID': 3534,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AHORROS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SAVINGS'
},
{
'ID': 3535,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PUNTO DE PARTIDA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'STARTING POINT'
},
{
'ID': 3536,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MOLESTAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ANNOY'
},
{
'ID': 3537,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONTENER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO CONTAIN'
},
{
'ID': 3538,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'QUEDARSE DORMIDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO FALL ASLEEP'
},
{
'ID': 3539,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DAR DE COMER,ALIMENTAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO FEED'
},
{
'ID': 3540,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONCEDER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO GRANT'
},
{
'ID': 3541,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GARANTIZAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO GUARANTEE'
},
{
'ID': 3542,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PONER EN PELIGRO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO JEOPARDIZE'
},
{
'ID': 3543,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TENER SENTIDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO MAKE SENSE'
},
{
'ID': 3544,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'REALIZAR,EJECUTAR,RENDIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO PERFORM'
},
{
'ID': 3545,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PREVENIR,EVITAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO PREVENT'
},
{
'ID': 3546,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ASCENDER,SUBIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO RISE'
},
{
'ID': 3547,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'APRESURARSE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO RUSH'
},
{
'ID': 3548,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MANTENER,APOYAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SUPPORT'
},
{
'ID': 3549,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CUIDAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO TAKE CARE OF'
},
{
'ID': 3550,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PREOCUPADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CONCERNED'
},
{
'ID': 3551,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COMERCIO INTERNACIONAL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FOREIGN TRADE'
},
{
'ID': 3552,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NOVATO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NOVICE'
},
{
'ID': 3553,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENFERMERA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NURSE'
},
{
'ID': 3554,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'OBSTÁCULO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'OBSTACLE'
},
{
'ID': 3555,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PASADO DE MODA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'OLD-FASHIONED'
},
{
'ID': 3556,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ACTUACIÓN,RENDIMIENTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PERFORMANCE'
},
{
'ID': 3557,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CASTIGO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PUNISHMENT'
},
{
'ID': 3558,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PROPOSITO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PURPOSE'
},
{
'ID': 3559,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TRANQUILIZADOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'REASSURING'
},
{
'ID': 3560,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RECUPERACIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RECOVERY'
},
{
'ID': 3561,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'REPENTINO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SUDDEN'
},
{
'ID': 3562,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SUPERVIVENCIA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SURVIVAL'
},
{
'ID': 3563,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HABLADOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TALKATIVE'
},
{
'ID': 3564,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENTERRAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BURY'
},
{
'ID': 3565,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AMPLIAR (FÍSICAMENTE)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ENLARGE'
},
{
'ID': 3566,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HACER FRENTE A',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO FACE'
},
{
'ID': 3567,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BURLARSE DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO MAKE FUN OF'
},
{
'ID': 3568,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FABRICAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO MANUFACTURE'
},
{
'ID': 3569,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESEMPEÑAR UN PAPEL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO PLAY A ROLE'
},
{
'ID': 3570,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BUSCAR Y CONTRATAR A PERSONAL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO RECRUIT'
},
{
'ID': 3571,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ALQUILAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO RENT'
},
{
'ID': 3572,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SEGUIR EN CONTACTO CON',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO STAY IN CONTACT WITH'
},
{
'ID': 3573,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SUMINISTRAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SUPPLY'
},
{
'ID': 3574,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'A DIFERENCIA DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'UNLIKE'
},
{
'ID': 3575,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DE VEZ EN CUANDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EVERY NOW AND THEN'
},
{
'ID': 3576,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'OLVÍDALO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NEVER MIND'
},
{
'ID': 3577,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NUMEROSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NUMEROUS'
},
{
'ID': 3578,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'OBSOLETO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'OBSOLETE'
},
{
'ID': 3579,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ACEITE,PETRÓLEO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'OIL'
},
{
'ID': 3580,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ACEITUNA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'OLIVE'
},
{
'ID': 3581,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SOCIO (CON OTRO U OTROS)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PARTNER'
},
{
'ID': 3582,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ORGULLO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PRIDE'
},
{
'ID': 3583,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ORDEN DE COMPRA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PURCHASE ORDER'
},
{
'ID': 3584,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CUESTIONARIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'QUESTIONNAIRE'
},
{
'ID': 3585,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RECETA (DE COCINA)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RECIPE'
},
{
'ID': 3586,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RECONOCIMIENTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RECOGNITION'
},
{
'ID': 3587,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PELIRROJO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RED-HEADED'
},
{
'ID': 3588,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'REFRESCANTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'REFRESHING'
},
{
'ID': 3589,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LAS HORAS PUNTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THE RUSH HOUR'
},
{
'ID': 3590,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LUZ SOLAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SUNLIGHT'
},
{
'ID': 3591,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CON TALENTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TALENTED'
},
{
'ID': 3592,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COMPAÑERO DE EQUIPO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TEAMMATE'
},
{
'ID': 3593,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESO ES,EN EFECTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THAT\'S RIGHT'
},
{
'ID': 3594,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LA BOLSA (DE VALORES)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THE STOCK MARKET'
},
{
'ID': 3595,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NEGOCIAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO NEGOTIATE'
},
{
'ID': 3596,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RECONSIDERAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO RECONSIDER'
},
{
'ID': 3597,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENSAYAR (UN EVENTO)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO REHEARSE'
},
{
'ID': 3598,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PEDIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO REQUEST'
},
{
'ID': 3599,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 4,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ATAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO TIE'
},
{
'ID': 3600,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'UN GRAN AVANCE CIENTÍFICO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'A BREAKTHROUGH'
},
{
'ID': 3601,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ANSIOSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ANXIOUS'
},
{
'ID': 3602,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BIOLOGÍA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BIOLOGY'
},
{
'ID': 3603,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'QUEJA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'COMPLAINT'
},
{
'ID': 3604,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CURRICULUM VITAE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CV'
},
{
'ID': 3605,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENANO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DWARF'
},
{
'ID': 3606,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EL DESTINO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FATE'
},
{
'ID': 3607,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COSECHA,RECOLECCIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HARVEST'
},
{
'ID': 3608,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'A CÁMARA LENTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IN SLOW MOTION'
},
{
'ID': 3609,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DOTES DE MANDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LEADERSHIP'
},
{
'ID': 3610,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LA NATURALEZA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NATURE'
},
{
'ID': 3611,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GRUPO DE PRESIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PRESSURE GROUP'
},
{
'ID': 3612,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LA JUBILACIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RETIREMENT'
},
{
'ID': 3613,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DOMINIO DE SI MISMO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SELF-RESTRAINT'
},
{
'ID': 3614,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RESBALADIZO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SLIPPERY'
},
{
'ID': 3615,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FUERZA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'STRENGTH'
},
{
'ID': 3616,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EL PADRE NUESTRO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THE LORD\'S PRAYER'
},
{
'ID': 3617,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NOMBRAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO APPOINT'
},
{
'ID': 3618,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RESULTAR ÚTIL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO COME IN HANDY'
},
{
'ID': 3619,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'APAÑARSE,SALIR DEL PASO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO GET BY'
},
{
'ID': 3620,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'REMATAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO NAIL DOWN'
},
{
'ID': 3621,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TROPEZAR CON,ENCONTRARSE CON',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO RUN INTO'
},
{
'ID': 3622,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TARTAMUDEAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO STUTTER'
},
{
'ID': 3623,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SOMETERSE A',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO UNDERGO'
},
{
'ID': 3624,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INOLVIDABLE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'UNFORGETTABLE'
},
{
'ID': 3625,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'UN INCONVENIENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'A DRAWBACK'
},
{
'ID': 3626,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DISCULPA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'APOLOGY'
},
{
'ID': 3627,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CHANTAJE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BLACKMAIL'
},
{
'ID': 3628,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CUMPLIMIENTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'COMPLIANCE'
},
{
'ID': 3629,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CÍNICO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CYNICAL'
},
{
'ID': 3630,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'JUBILACIÓN ANTICIPADA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EARLY RETIREMENT'
},
{
'ID': 3631,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PLUMA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FEATHER'
},
{
'ID': 3632,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MAITRE HEAD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WAITER'
},
{
'ID': 3633,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MIENTRAS TANTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IN THE MEANTIME'
},
{
'ID': 3634,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'OCIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LEISURE'
},
{
'ID': 3635,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESATENCIÓN,ABANDONO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NEGLECT'
},
{
'ID': 3636,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PROCEDIMIENTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PROCEDURE'
},
{
'ID': 3637,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INGRESOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'REVENUE'
},
{
'ID': 3638,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AUTO-SUFICIENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SELF-SUFFICIENT'
},
{
'ID': 3639,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CHAPUCERO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SLOPPY'
},
{
'ID': 3640,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CARGADO (EL AMBIENTE)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'STUFFY'
},
{
'ID': 3641,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LA LETRA (DE UNA CANCIÓN)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THE LYRICS'
},
{
'ID': 3642,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VALORAR,TASAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO APPRAISE'
},
{
'ID': 3643,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SUICIDARSE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO COMMIT SUICIDE'
},
{
'ID': 3644,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LIARSE,CONFUNDIRSE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO GET MIXED UP'
},
{
'ID': 3645,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESATENDER,NO CUMPLIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO NEGLECT'
},
{
'ID': 3646,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DIRIGIR EL COTARRO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO RUN THE SHOW'
},
{
'ID': 3647,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SUBVENCIONAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SUBSIDIZE'
},
{
'ID': 3648,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MINAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO UNDERMINE'
},
{
'ID': 3649,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'IMPROBABLE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'UNLIKELY'
},
{
'ID': 3650,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'UN BOCAZAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ALOUDMOUTH'
},
{
'ID': 3651,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'POR LO VISTO,AL PARECER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'APPARENTLY'
},
{
'ID': 3652,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MEZCLA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BLEND'
},
{
'ID': 3653,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CUMPLIDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'COMPLIMENT'
},
{
'ID': 3654,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DANÉS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DANISH'
},
{
'ID': 3655,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TERREMOTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EARTHQUAKE'
},
{
'ID': 3656,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CARACTERÍSTICAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FEATURES'
},
{
'ID': 3657,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENCABEZAMIENTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HEADING'
},
{
'ID': 3658,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EN MEDIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IN THE WAY'
},
{
'ID': 3659,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PERMISIVO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LENIENT'
},
{
'ID': 3660,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NO OBSTANTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NEVERTHELESS'
},
{
'ID': 3661,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PERFIL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PROFILE'
},
{
'ID': 3662,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MARCHA ATRÁS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'REVERSE'
},
{
'ID': 3663,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EGOÍSTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SELFISH'
},
{
'ID': 3664,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RANURA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SLOT'
},
{
'ID': 3665,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SUBVENCIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SUBSIDY'
},
{
'ID': 3666,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LA VIA LÁCTEA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THE MILKY WAY'
},
{
'ID': 3667,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AGRADECER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO APPRECIATE'
},
{
'ID': 3668,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CUMPLIR CON',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO COMPLY WITH'
},
{
'ID': 3669,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESHACERSE DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO GET RID OF'
},
{
'ID': 3670,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ORIENTAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ORIENT'
},
{
'ID': 3671,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'OXIDARSE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO RUST'
},
{
'ID': 3672,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TENER ÉXITO,TRIUNFAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SUCCEED'
},
{
'ID': 3673,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SUBVALORAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO UNDERRATE'
},
{
'ID': 3674,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VENIDERO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'UPCOMING'
},
{
'ID': 3675,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'UN ALIVIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'A RELIEF'
},
{
'ID': 3676,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'APERITIVO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'APPETIZER'
},
{
'ID': 3677,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BENDICIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BLESSING'
},
{
'ID': 3678,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONSUMO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CONSUMPTION'
},
{
'ID': 3679,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PROCESO DE DATOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DATA PROCESSING'
},
{
'ID': 3680,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TRANQUILO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EASY-GOING'
},
{
'ID': 3681,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HONORARIOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FEE'
},
{
'ID': 3682,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LUCES (DEL COCHE)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HEADLIGHTS'
},
{
'ID': 3683,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PARIENTES POLÍTICOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IN-LAWS'
},
{
'ID': 3684,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PALANCA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LEVER'
},
{
'ID': 3685,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'QUIOSCO DE PRENSA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NEWSSTAND'
},
{
'ID': 3686,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BENEFICIO Y PERDIDA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PROFIT AND LOSS'
},
{
'ID': 3687,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GRATIFICANTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'REWARDING'
},
{
'ID': 3688,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PUNTO Y COMA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SEMICOLON'
},
{
'ID': 3689,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MAQUINA TRAGAPERRAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SLOT MACHINE'
},
{
'ID': 3690,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DE ÉXITO,EXITOSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SUCCESSFUL'
},
{
'ID': 3691,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LA MORALEJA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THE MORAL'
},
{
'ID': 3692,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DISCUTIR (ACALORADAMENTE)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ARGUE'
},
{
'ID': 3693,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DAR LA ENHORABUENA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO CONGRATULATE'
},
{
'ID': 3694,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESVESTIRSE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO GET UNDRESSED'
},
{
'ID': 3695,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SOBREVIVIR A (UNA PERSONA)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO OUTLIVE'
},
{
'ID': 3696,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BUSCAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SEEK'
},
{
'ID': 3697,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DEMANDAR,PEDIR PLEITO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SUE'
},
{
'ID': 3698,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EMPRENDER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO UNDERTAKE'
},
{
'ID': 3699,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LA CLASE ALTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'UPPER CLASS'
},
{
'ID': 3700,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'UN RECORDATORIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'A REMINDER'
},
{
'ID': 3701,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CANDIDATO,SOLICITANTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'APPLICANT'
},
{
'ID': 3702,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TENSIÓN SANGUÍNEA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BLOOD PRESSURE'
},
{
'ID': 3703,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PREOCUPADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CONCERNED'
},
{
'ID': 3704,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GUARDERÍA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DAYCARE CENTER'
},
{
'ID': 3705,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ECONÓMICAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ECONOMICS'
},
{
'ID': 3706,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PROMETIDO/A',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FIANCE'
},
{
'ID': 3707,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ARDOR (DE ESTOMAGO)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HEART BURN'
},
{
'ID': 3708,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INPRECISO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'INACCURATE'
},
{
'ID': 3709,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESPERANZA DE VIDA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LIFE EXPECTANCY'
},
{
'ID': 3710,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VIDA NOCTURNA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NIGHT LIFE'
},
{
'ID': 3711,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RENTABILIDAD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PROFITABILITY'
},
{
'ID': 3712,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ACERTIJO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RIDDLE'
},
{
'ID': 3713,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ANTIGÜEDAD (EN UNA EMPRESA)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SENIORITY'
},
{
'ID': 3714,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CARACOL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SNAIL'
},
{
'ID': 3715,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BRONCEADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SUNTAN'
},
{
'ID': 3716,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LOS JUEGOS OLÍMPICOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THE OLYMPIC GAMES'
},
{
'ID': 3717,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EVALUAR,VALORAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ASSESS'
},
{
'ID': 3718,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TOSER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO COUGH'
},
{
'ID': 3719,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'REGALAR (POR NO QUERER)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TOGIVEAWAY'
},
{
'ID': 3720,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SUPERAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO OVERCOME'
},
{
'ID': 3721,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DAR EJEMPLO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SET AN EXAMPLE'
},
{
'ID': 3722,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RESUMIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SUM UP'
},
{
'ID': 3723,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESATAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO UNTIE'
},
{
'ID': 3724,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ASPIRADORA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'VACUUM CLEANER'
},
{
'ID': 3725,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'UN TIMO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'A RIP-OFF'
},
{
'ID': 3726,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VALORACIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'APPRAISAL'
},
{
'ID': 3727,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GUARDA ESPALDAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BODYGUARD'
},
{
'ID': 3728,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HORMIGÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CONCRETE'
},
{
'ID': 3729,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CALLEJÓN SIN SALIDA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DEAD END'
},
{
'ID': 3730,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BORDE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EDGE'
},
{
'ID': 3731,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SOLOMILLO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FILET MIGNON'
},
{
'ID': 3732,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AJETREADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HECTIC'
},
{
'ID': 3733,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'IMPUESTO SOBRE LA RENTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'INCOME TAX'
},
{
'ID': 3734,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PROBABILIDAD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LIKELIHOOD'
},
{
'ID': 3735,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TONTERÍAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NONSENSE'
},
{
'ID': 3736,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RENTABLE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PROFITABLE'
},
{
'ID': 3737,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENSEGUIDA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RIGHT AWAY'
},
{
'ID': 3738,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HASTA LA VISTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SO LONG'
},
{
'ID': 3739,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SOBERBIO (EXCELENTE)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SUPERB'
},
{
'ID': 3740,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LA PESTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THE PLAGUE'
},
{
'ID': 3741,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ADJUDICAR,PREMIAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO AWARD'
},
{
'ID': 3742,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONTAR CON',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO COUNT ON'
},
{
'ID': 3743,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CEDER,RENDIRSE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO GIVE IN'
},
{
'ID': 3744,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SOBRESTIMAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO OVERESTIMATE'
},
{
'ID': 3745,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ASENTAR LA CABEZA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SETTLE DOWN'
},
{
'ID': 3746,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MANTENER,APOYAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SUPPORT'
},
{
'ID': 3747,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESENVOLVER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO UNWRAP'
},
{
'ID': 3748,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VALIOSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'VALUABLE'
},
{
'ID': 3749,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SENSIBLE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SENSITIVE'
},
{
'ID': 3750,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'UN CONTRATIEMPO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ASETBACK'
},
{
'ID': 3751,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AGRADECIDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'APPRECIATIVE'
},
{
'ID': 3752,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MOLESTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BOTHERSOME'
},
{
'ID': 3753,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONCIENZUDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CONSCIENTIOUS'
},
{
'ID': 3754,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FECHA TOPE,PLAZO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DEADLINE'
},
{
'ID': 3755,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EFICAZ',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EFFECTIVE'
},
{
'ID': 3756,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FLOTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FLEET'
},
{
'ID': 3757,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HEREDERO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HEIR'
},
{
'ID': 3758,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CADA VEZ MAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'INCREASINGLY'
},
{
'ID': 3759,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PROBABLE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LIKELY'
},
{
'ID': 3760,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BLOC PARA NOTAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NOTEPAD'
},
{
'ID': 3761,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PROMETEDOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PROMISING'
},
{
'ID': 3762,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RIVALIDAD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RIVALRY'
},
{
'ID': 3763,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ACUERDO,ARREGLO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SETTLEMENT'
},
{
'ID': 3764,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BLANDURA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SOFTNESS'
},
{
'ID': 3765,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EXCEDENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SURPLUS'
},
{
'ID': 3766,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LA CRUZ ROJA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THE RED CROSS'
},
{
'ID': 3767,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'APOYAR,RESPALDAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BACK UP'
},
{
'ID': 3768,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CHOCAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO CRASH'
},
{
'ID': 3769,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HACER EL GANSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO GOOF OFF'
},
{
'ID': 3770,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESBORDAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO OVERFLOW'
},
{
'ID': 3771,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AFILAR,SACAR PUNTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SHARPEN'
},
{
'ID': 3772,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RENDIRSE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SURRENDER'
},
{
'ID': 3773,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PERDER TIEMPO (MALGASTAR)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO WASTE TIME'
},
{
'ID': 3774,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VIABILIDAD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'VIABILITY'
},
{
'ID': 3775,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'UN ALBOROTADOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'A TROUBLEMAKER'
},
{
'ID': 3776,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENFOQUE,PLANTEAMIENTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'APPROACH'
},
{
'ID': 3777,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BRISA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BREEZE'
},
{
'ID': 3778,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONSULTOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CONSULTANT'
},
{
'ID': 3779,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MORTAL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DEADLY'
},
{
'ID': 3780,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EFICAZMENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EFFECTIVELY'
},
{
'ID': 3781,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CARNE Y HUESO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FLESH AND BLOOD'
},
{
'ID': 3782,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SERVICIAL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HELPFUL'
},
{
'ID': 3783,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INFLUYENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'INFLUENTIAL'
},
{
'ID': 3784,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PRÉSTAMO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LOAN'
},
{
'ID': 3785,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HOGAR DE ANCIANOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NURSING HOME'
},
{
'ID': 3786,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PERSPECTIVAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PROSPECTS'
},
{
'ID': 3787,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RUTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ROUTE'
},
{
'ID': 3788,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COLONIZADOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SETTLER'
},
{
'ID': 3789,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SUELO (AGRÍCOLA)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SOIL'
},
{
'ID': 3790,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ALREDEDORES',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SURROUNDINGS'
},
{
'ID': 3791,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LOS RESTOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THE REMAINS'
},
{
'ID': 3792,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'REGATEAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BARGAIN'
},
{
'ID': 3793,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TACHAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO CROSS OUT'
},
{
'ID': 3794,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AGARRAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO GRAB'
},
{
'ID': 3795,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SOLAPARSE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO OVERLAP'
},
{
'ID': 3796,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DAR CARRETE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SHOOT THE BULL'
},
{
'ID': 3797,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RODEAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SURROUND'
},
{
'ID': 3798,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DEBILITAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO WEAKEN'
},
{
'ID': 3799,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VIABLE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'VIABLE'
},
{
'ID': 3800,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ACENTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ACCENT'
},
{
'ID': 3801,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'APROPIADAMENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'APPROPRIATELY'
},
{
'ID': 3802,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DE MENTE AMPLIA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BROAD-MINDED'
},
{
'ID': 3803,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONSUMIDOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CONSUMER'
},
{
'ID': 3804,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SORDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DEAF'
},
{
'ID': 3805,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EFICACIA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EFFECTIVENESS'
},
{
'ID': 3806,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INUNDACIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FLOOD'
},
{
'ID': 3807,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESAMPARADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HELPLESS'
},
{
'ID': 3808,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INGENIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'INGENUITY'
},
{
'ID': 3809,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LANGOSTA (DE MAR)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LOBSTER'
},
{
'ID': 3810,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PULPO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'OCTOPUS'
},
{
'ID': 3811,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ORGULLOSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PROUD'
},
{
'ID': 3812,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'REALEZA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ROYALTY'
},
{
'ID': 3813,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INDEMNIZACIÓN POR DESPIDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SEVERANCE PAY'
},
{
'ID': 3814,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AGRIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SOUR'
},
{
'ID': 3815,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENCUESTA,SONDEO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SURVEY'
},
{
'ID': 3816,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CUANTO ANTES MEJOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THE SOONER THE BETTER'
},
{
'ID': 3817,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESTAR EN MEDIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BE IN THE WAY'
},
{
'ID': 3818,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RECORTAR,REDUCIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO CUT BACK'
},
{
'ID': 3819,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'QUEJARSE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO GRIPE'
},
{
'ID': 3820,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DERROCAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO OVERTHROW'
},
{
'ID': 3821,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ACORTAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SHORTEN'
},
{
'ID': 3822,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BARRER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SWEEP'
},
{
'ID': 3823,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENSANCHAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO WIDEN'
},
{
'ID': 3824,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CIRCULO VICIOSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'VICIOUS CIRCLE'
},
{
'ID': 3825,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ALOJAMIENTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ACCOMMODATION'
},
{
'ID': 3826,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ÁRABE (EL IDIOMA)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ARABIC'
},
{
'ID': 3827,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESCOBA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BROOM'
},
{
'ID': 3828,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONCURSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CONTEST'
},
{
'ID': 3829,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SORDOMUDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DEAF-MUTE'
},
{
'ID': 3830,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VIOLENTO,EMBARAZOSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EMBARRASSING'
},
{
'ID': 3831,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INUNDADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FLOODED'
},
{
'ID': 3832,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HERENCIA CULTURAL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HERITAGE'
},
{
'ID': 3833,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HERENCIA (DINERARIA)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'INHERITANCE'
},
{
'ID': 3834,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CERRADURA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LOCK'
},
{
'ID': 3835,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LA VEJEZ',
        'RESPUESTA': 'OLD AGE'
},
{
'ID': 3836,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SIEMPRE QUE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PROVIDED THAT'
},
{
'ID': 3837,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BASURA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RUBBISH'
},
{
'ID': 3838,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VERGÜENZA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SHAME'
},
{
'ID': 3839,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RUEDA DE REPUESTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SPARE TIRE'
},
{
'ID': 3840,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PANTANO,CIÉNAGA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SWAMP'
},
{
'ID': 3841,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EL TERCER MUNDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THE THIRD WORLD'
},
{
'ID': 3842,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESTAR HECHO UN LIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BE MIXED UP'
},
{
'ID': 3843,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TRATAR CON',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO DEAL WITH'
},
{
'ID': 3844,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DAÑAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO HARM'
},
{
'ID': 3845,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ABRUMAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO OVERWHELM'
},
{
'ID': 3846,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PRESUMIR,FARDAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SHOW OFF'
},
{
'ID': 3847,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ACOMETER,RESOLVER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO TACKLE'
},
{
'ID': 3848,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SER TESTIGO DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO WITNESS'
},
{
'ID': 3849,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VINO AÑEJO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'VINTAGE WINE'
},
{
'ID': 3850,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EN CONSECUENCIA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ACCORDINGLY'
},
{
'ID': 3851,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GAMA,SURTIDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ARRAY'
},
{
'ID': 3852,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BUROCRACIA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BUREAUCRACY'
},
{
'ID': 3853,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CHIRIMBOLO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CONTRAPTION'
},
{
'ID': 3854,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENCANTADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DELIGHTED'
},
{
'ID': 3855,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ANIMO,ALIENTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ENCOURAGEMENT'
},
{
'ID': 3856,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GOMA ESPUMA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FOAM RUBBER'
},
{
'ID': 3857,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DUDOSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HESITANT'
},
{
'ID': 3858,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LESIONADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'INJURED'
},
{
'ID': 3859,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LOGÍSTICA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LOGISTICS'
},
{
'ID': 3860,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EN CAMBIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ON THE OTHER HAND'
},
{
'ID': 3861,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MARIONETA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PUPPET'
},
{
'ID': 3862,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RUINAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RUINS'
},
{
'ID': 3863,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VERGONZOSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SHAMEFUL'
},
{
'ID': 3864,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CHISPA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SPARK'
},
{
'ID': 3865,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CISNE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SWAN'
},
{
'ID': 3866,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EL ESTADO DEL BIENESTAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THE WELFARE STATE'
},
{
'ID': 3867,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SER GORDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BE OVERWEIGHT'
},
{
'ID': 3868,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONSIDERAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO DEEM'
},
{
'ID': 3869,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PASÁRSELO BIEN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO HAVEAGOOD TIME'
},
{
'ID': 3870,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FALLECER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO PASS AWAY'
},
{
'ID': 3871,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SUSPIRAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SIGH'
},
{
'ID': 3872,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ECHAR LA SIESTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO TAKE A NAP'
},
{
'ID': 3873,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RESOLVER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO WORK OUT'
},
{
'ID': 3874,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VOLCAN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'VOLCANO'
},
{
'ID': 3875,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RESPONSABLE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ACCOUNTABLE'
},
{
'ID': 3876,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ARTIFICIAL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ARTIFICIAL'
},
{
'ID': 3877,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENTIERRO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BURIAL'
},
{
'ID': 3878,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONTROVERSIA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CONTROVERSY'
},
{
'ID': 3879,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENCANTADOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DELIGHTFUL'
},
{
'ID': 3880,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ALENTADOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ENCOURAGING'
},
{
'ID': 3881,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PARA SIEMPRE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FOR GOOD'
},
{
'ID': 3882,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PUEBLO NATAL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HOMETOWN'
},
{
'ID': 3883,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LOCO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'INSANE'
},
{
'ID': 3884,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'A LARGO LAZO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LONG-RANGE'
},
{
'ID': 3885,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'OPTIMISMO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'OPTIMISM'
},
{
'ID': 3886,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MONEDERO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PURSE'
},
{
'ID': 3887,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'REGLA (PARA MEDIR)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RULER'
},
{
'ID': 3888,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COBIJO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SHELTER'
},
{
'ID': 3889,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESPECIAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SPICES'
},
{
'ID': 3890,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SUDOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SWEAT'
},
{
'ID': 3891,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'POR LO TANTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THEREFORE'
},
{
'ID': 3892,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESTAR BAJO JURAMENTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BE UNDER OATH'
},
{
'ID': 3893,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENCANTAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO DELIGHT'
},
{
'ID': 3894,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INCAPACITAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO INCAPACITATE'
},
{
'ID': 3895,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PELAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO PEEL'
},
{
'ID': 3896,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'APUNTARSE PARA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SIGN UP FOR'
},
{
'ID': 3897,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'APROVECHARSE DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO TAKE ADVANTAGE OF'
},
{
'ID': 3898,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONCLUIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO WRAP UP'
},
{
'ID': 3899,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VOLUNTARIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'VOLUNTEER'
},
{
'ID': 3900,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PRECISIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ACCURACY'
},
{
'ID': 3901,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'QUE YO SEPA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AS FAR AS I KNOW'
},
{
'ID': 3902,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CATÓLICO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CATHOLIC'
},
{
'ID': 3903,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COMODIDAD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CONVENIENCE'
},
{
'ID': 3904,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EXIGENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DEMANDING'
},
{
'ID': 3905,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FONDO,AGUANTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ENDURANCE'
},
{
'ID': 3906,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'POR AHORA,DE MOMENTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FOR THE TIME BEING'
},
{
'ID': 3907,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GANCHO,ANZUELO,GARFIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HOOK'
},
{
'ID': 3908,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LOCURA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'INSANITY'
},
{
'ID': 3909,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'A LARGO PLAZO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LONG-TERM'
},
{
'ID': 3910,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DE OTRO MODO,SI NO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'OTHERWISE'
},
{
'ID': 3911,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BASTANTES',
        'RESPUESTA': 'QUITE A FEW'
},
{
'ID': 3912,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RON',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RUM'
},
{
'ID': 3913,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'JEREZ',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SHERRY'
},
{
'ID': 3914,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PICANTE,CONDIMENTADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SPICY'
},
{
'ID': 3915,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SUDOROSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SWEATY'
},
{
'ID': 3916,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TOZUDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THICK-HEADED'
},
{
'ID': 3917,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DERROTAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BEAT'
},
{
'ID': 3918,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EXIGIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO DEMAND'
},
{
'ID': 3919,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INSINUAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO INSINUATE'
},
{
'ID': 3920,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'IRSE AMONTONANDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO PILE UP'
},
{
'ID': 3921,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INCORPORARSE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SIT UP'
},
{
'ID': 3922,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PARECERSE A (FORMA DE SER)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO TAKE AFTER'
},
{
'ID': 3923,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GRITAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO YELL'
},
{
'ID': 3924,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BUITRE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'VULTURE'
},
{
'ID': 3925,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LOGRO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ACHIEVEMENT'
},
{
'ID': 3926,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'APARTE DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ASIDE FROM'
},
{
'ID': 3927,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GANADO VACUNO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CATTLE'
},
{
'ID': 3928,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CÓMODO,OPORTUNO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CONVENIENT'
},
{
'ID': 3929,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESMORALIZANTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DEMORALIZING'
},
{
'ID': 3930,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PROMETIDO (PARA CASARSE)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ENGAGED'
},
{
'ID': 3931,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CAPATAZ',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FOREMAN'
},
{
'ID': 3932,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CLAXON,BOCINA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HORN'
},
{
'ID': 3933,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INVERSIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'INVESTMENT'
},
{
'ID': 3934,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CHAPUCERO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LOUSY'
},
{
'ID': 3935,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SUPER POBLADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'OVERPOPULATED'
},
{
'ID': 3936,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MATERIAS PRIMAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RAW MATERIALS'
},
{
'ID': 3937,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PISTA DE ATERRIZAJE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RUNWAY'
},
{
'ID': 3938,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESCUDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SHIELD'
},
{
'ID': 3939,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COLUMNA VERTEBRAL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SPINE'
},
{
'ID': 3940,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESPADA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SWORD'
},
{
'ID': 3941,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESPESURA,GROSOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THICKNESS'
},
{
'ID': 3942,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MENDIGAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BEG'
},
{
'ID': 3943,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PARTIR,SALIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO DEPART'
},
{
'ID': 3944,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GUARDAR UN SECRETO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO KEEP A SECRET'
},
{
'ID': 3945,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RECALCAR,SEÑALAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO POINT OUT'
},
{
'ID': 3946,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ABOFETEAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SLAP'
},
{
'ID': 3947,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DAR POR SENTADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO TAKE FOR GRANTED'
},
{
'ID': 3948,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TRABALENGUAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TONGUE TWISTER'
},
{
'ID': 3949,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ADVERTENCIA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WARNING'
},
{
'ID': 3950,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TALÓN DE AQUILES',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ACHILLES HEEL'
},
{
'ID': 3951,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ASFALTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ASPHALT'
},
{
'ID': 3952,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ALTO EL FUEGO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CEASE-FIRE'
},
{
'ID': 3953,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONVINCENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CONVINCING'
},
{
'ID': 3954,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DINAMARCA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DENMARK'
},
{
'ID': 3955,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NOVIAZGO FORMAL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ENGAGEMENT'
},
{
'ID': 3956,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VISION DE FUTURO,PREVISIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FORESIGHT'
},
{
'ID': 3957,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'REHÉN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HOSTAGE'
},
{
'ID': 3958,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'IMPLICACIÓN,INVOLUCRARON',
        'RESPUESTA': 'INVOLVEMENT'
},
{
'ID': 3959,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LEAL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LOYAL'
},
{
'ID': 3960,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ABRUMADOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'OVERWHELMING'
},
{
'ID': 3961,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TRANQUILIZADOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'REASSURING'
},
{
'ID': 3962,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TRISTEZA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SADNESS'
},
{
'ID': 3963,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESCASEZ (TEMPORAL)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SHORTAGE'
},
{
'ID': 3964,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PORTAVOZ',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SPOKESMAN'
},
{
'ID': 3965,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PEZ ESPADA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SWORDFISH'
},
{
'ID': 3966,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COMPLETO Y ESMERADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THOROUGH'
},
{
'ID': 3967,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DOBLAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BEND'
},
{
'ID': 3968,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESPLEGAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO DEPLOY'
},
{
'ID': 3969,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MANTENERSE EN FORMA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO KEEP FIT'
},
{
'ID': 3970,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'REZAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO PRAY'
},
{
'ID': 3971,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RESBALAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SLIP'
},
{
'ID': 3972,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ASUMIR EL MANDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO TAKE OVER'
},
{
'ID': 3973,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DOLOR DE MUELA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TOOTHACHE'
},
{
'ID': 3974,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GARANTÍA (SOBRE UN PRODUCTO)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WARRANTY'
},
{
'ID': 3975,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ACÚSTICA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ACOUSTICS'
},
{
'ID': 3976,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VALORACIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ASSESSMENT'
},
{
'ID': 3977,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CÉLULA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CELL'
},
{
'ID': 3978,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GALLETA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'COOKIE'
},
{
'ID': 3979,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PROFUNDIDAD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DEPTH'
},
{
'ID': 3980,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AGRADABLE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ENJOYABLE'
},
{
'ID': 3981,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PUNTO FUERTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FORTE'
},
{
'ID': 3982,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VIVIENDA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HOUSING'
},
{
'ID': 3983,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CUESTIÓN A DEBATIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ISSUE'
},
{
'ID': 3984,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PULMONES',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LUNGS'
},
{
'ID': 3985,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BUHO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'OWL'
},
{
'ID': 3986,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TEMERARIO,MUY IMPRUDENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RECKLESS'
},
{
'ID': 3987,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BARCO DE VELA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SAILBOAT'
},
{
'ID': 3988,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESCOPETA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SHOTGUN'
},
{
'ID': 3989,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PATROCINADOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SPONSOR'
},
{
'ID': 3990,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CAMISETA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'T-SHIRT'
},
{
'ID': 3991,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PURA SANGRE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THOROUGHBRED'
},
{
'ID': 3992,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TRAICIONAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BETRAY'
},
{
'ID': 3993,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MERECER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO DESERVE'
},
{
'ID': 3994,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MANTENERSE CON (EL RITMO)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO KEEP UP WITH'
},
{
'ID': 3995,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PREDICAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO PREACH'
},
{
'ID': 3996,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SOSPECHAR ALGO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SMELL A RAT'
},
{
'ID': 3997,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TOMAR MEDIDAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO TAKE STEPS'
},
{
'ID': 3998,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CEPILLO DE DIENTES',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TOOTHBRUSH'
},
{
'ID': 3999,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AVISPA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WASP'
},
{
'ID': 4000,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ADQUISICIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ACQUISITION'
},
{
'ID': 4001,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'A TODA COSTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AT ALL COSTS'
},
{
'ID': 4002,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RETO,DESAFIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CHALLENGE'
},
{
'ID': 4003,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'POLICÍA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'COP'
},
{
'ID': 4004,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MERECEDOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DESERVING'
},
{
'ID': 4005,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EMPRENDEDOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ENTERPRISING'
},
{
'ID': 4006,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'QUINCENA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FORTNIGHT'
},
{
'ID': 4007,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': '¿POR QUE?',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HOW COME?'
},
{
'ID': 4008,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NO TIENE SENTIDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IT DOESN\'T MAKE ANY SENSE'
},
{
'ID': 4009,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LUJOSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LUXURIOUS'
},
{
'ID': 4010,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'OSTRA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'OYSTER'
},
{
'ID': 4011,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RECREO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RECREATION'
},
{
'ID': 4012,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AHORROS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SAVINGS'
},
{
'ID': 4013,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PALA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SHOVEL'
},
{
'ID': 4014,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CÓNYUGE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SPOUSE'
},
{
'ID': 4015,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MANTEL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TABLECLOTH'
},
{
'ID': 4016,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESMERO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THOROUGHNESS'
},
{
'ID': 4017,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CHANTAJEAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BLACKMAIL'
},
{
'ID': 4018,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ODIAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO DESPISE'
},
{
'ID': 4019,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ECHAR A PATADAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO KICK OUT'
},
{
'ID': 4020,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ANDAR CON DILACIONES,APLAZAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO PROCRASTINATE'
},
{
'ID': 4021,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RONCAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SNORE'
},
{
'ID': 4022,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RASGAR,ROMPER (TELA, PAPEL)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO TEAR'
},
{
'ID': 4023,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PASTA DE DIENTES',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TOOTH PASTE'
},
{
'ID': 4024,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PAPELERA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WASTE BASKET'
},
{
'ID': 4025,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AVANCE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ADVANCEMENT'
},
{
'ID': 4026,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EN EL MEJOR DE LOS CASOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AT BEST'
},
{
'ID': 4027,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TRAMPOSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CHEATER'
},
{
'ID': 4028,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COBRE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'COPPER'
},
{
'ID': 4029,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PERJUDICIAL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DETRIMENTAL'
},
{
'ID': 4030,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENTUSIASMO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ENTHUSIASM'
},
{
'ID': 4031,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CIMIENTOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FOUNDATION'
},
{
'ID': 4032,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENORME',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HUGE'
},
{
'ID': 4033,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ME SUENA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IT RINGS A BELL'
},
{
'ID': 4034,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LUJO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LUXURY'
},
{
'ID': 4035,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INDOLORO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PAINLESS'
},
{
'ID': 4036,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ARBITRO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'REFEREE'
},
{
'ID': 4037,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SIERRA (HERRAMIENTA)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SAW'
},
{
'ID': 4038,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ASTUTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SHREWD'
},
{
'ID': 4039,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MONTÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'STACK'
},
{
'ID': 4040,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HECHO A MEDIDA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TAILOR-MADE'
},
{
'ID': 4041,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONSIDERADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THOUGHTFUL'
},
{
'ID': 4042,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SANGRAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BLEED'
},
{
'ID': 4043,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CAVAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO DIG'
},
{
'ID': 4044,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SECUESTRAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO KIDNAP'
},
{
'ID': 4045,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BENEFICIARSE DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO PROFIT FROM'
},
{
'ID': 4046,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ABLANDAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SOFTEN'
},
{
'ID': 4047,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TOMAR EL PELO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO TEASE'
},
{
'ID': 4048,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PALILLO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TOOTHPICK'
},
{
'ID': 4049,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DEBILIDAD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WEAKNESS'
},
{
'ID': 4050,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VENTAJOSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ADVANTAGEOUS'
},
{
'ID': 4051,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DETENIDAMENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AT LENGTH'
},
{
'ID': 4052,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TALONARIO DE CHEQUES',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CHECKBOOK'
},
{
'ID': 4053,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CORCHO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CORK'
},
{
'ID': 4054,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DISPOSITIVO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DEVICE'
},
{
'ID': 4055,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENTORNO,MEDIO AMBIENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ENVIRONMENT'
},
{
'ID': 4056,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ASUSTADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FRIGHTENED'
},
{
'ID': 4057,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HUMILDE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HUMBLE'
},
{
'ID': 4058,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': '¡MENOS MAL!',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IT\'S A GOOD THING!'
},
{
'ID': 4059,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VALOR DE MERCADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MARKET VALUE'
},
{
'ID': 4060,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LORO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PARROT'
},
{
'ID': 4061,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'REFERENCIA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'REFERRAL'
},
{
'ID': 4062,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CABEZA DE TURCO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SCAPEGOAT'
},
{
'ID': 4063,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TÍMIDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SHY'
},
{
'ID': 4064,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESTANCADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'STAGNANT'
},
{
'ID': 4065,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MANSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TAME'
},
{
'ID': 4066,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONSIDERACIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THOUGHTFULNESS'
},
{
'ID': 4067,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FAROLEAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BLUFF'
},
{
'ID': 4068,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ELABORAR,CONFECCIONAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO DRAW UP'
},
{
'ID': 4069,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESPEDIR (EN MASA)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO LAY OFF'
},
{
'ID': 4070,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PROPORCIONAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO PROVIDE'
},
{
'ID': 4071,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RESOLVER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SOLVE'
},
{
'ID': 4072,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PENSAR EN VOZ ALTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO THINK OUT LOUD'
},
{
'ID': 4073,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TORNEO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TOURNAMENT'
},
{
'ID': 4074,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ADINERADO,RICO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WEALTHY'
},
{
'ID': 4075,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ADVERSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ADVERSE'
},
{
'ID': 4076,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ALAZAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AT RANDOM'
},
{
'ID': 4077,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CUENTA CORRIENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CHECKING ACCOUNT'
},
{
'ID': 4078,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SOCIEDAD ANÓNIMA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CORPORATION'
},
{
'ID': 4079,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INCAPACITADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DISABLED'
},
{
'ID': 4080,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'A LA LARGA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EVENTUALLY'
},
{
'ID': 4081,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BENEFICIOS SOCIALES DE NOMINA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FRINGE BENEFITS'
},
{
'ID': 4082,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SUPONGO QUE SI',
        'RESPUESTA': 'I GUESS SO'
},
{
'ID': 4083,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': '¡YA ERA HORA!',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IT\'S ABOUT TIME!'
},
{
'ID': 4084,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DOMINIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MASTERY'
},
{
'ID': 4085,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONTRASEÑA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PASSWORD'
},
{
'ID': 4086,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INDEPENDIENTEMENTE DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'REGARDLESS OF'
},
{
'ID': 4087,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CICATRIZ',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SCAR'
},
{
'ID': 4088,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'REPUGNANTE,NAUSEABUNDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SICKENING'
},
{
'ID': 4089,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MANCHA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'STAIN'
},
{
'ID': 4090,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MANDARINA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TANGERINE'
},
{
'ID': 4091,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HILO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THREAD'
},
{
'ID': 4092,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SONROJARSE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BLUSH'
},
{
'ID': 4093,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GOTEAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO DRIP'
},
{
'ID': 4094,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'OMITIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO LEAVE OUT'
},
{
'ID': 4095,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RECURRIR A ENCHUFES',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO PULL STRINGS'
},
{
'ID': 4096,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RESOLVER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SORT OUT'
},
{
'ID': 4097,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'REFLEXIONAR SOBRE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO THINK OVER'
},
{
'ID': 4098,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GRÚA (PARA REMOLCAR)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TOW TRUCK'
},
{
'ID': 4099,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': '¡VAYA FOLLÓN!',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WHAT A MESS!'
},
{
'ID': 4100,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONSEJO,ASESORAMIENTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ADVICE'
},
{
'ID': 4101,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'A EXPENSAS DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AT THE EXPENSE OF'
},
{
'ID': 4102,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LISTA DE VERIFICACIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CHECKLIST'
},
{
'ID': 4103,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COSTOSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'COSTLY'
},
{
'ID': 4104,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DECEPCIONADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DISAPPOINTED'
},
{
'ID': 4105,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DE VEZ EN CUANDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EVERY NOW AND THEN'
},
{
'ID': 4106,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BRECHA,LAGUNA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GAP'
},
{
'ID': 4107,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TENGO UN HAMBRE QUE NO VEAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'I\'M STARVING'
},
{
'ID': 4108,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NO VALE LA PENA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IT\'S NOT WORTH IT'
},
{
'ID': 4109,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COLCHÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MATTRESS'
},
{
'ID': 4110,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NOMINA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PAYROLL'
},
{
'ID': 4111,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LAMENTABLE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'REGRETFUL'
},
{
'ID': 4112,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESPANTA PÁJAROS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SCARECROW'
},
{
'ID': 4113,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PECADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SIN'
},
{
'ID': 4114,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FONDO,AGUANTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'STAMINA'
},
{
'ID': 4115,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AGUA DE GRIFO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TAP WATER'
},
{
'ID': 4116,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AMENAZA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THREAT'
},
{
'ID': 4117,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HERVIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BOIL'
},
{
'ID': 4118,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DARSE DE BAJA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO DROP OUT'
},
{
'ID': 4119,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ALARGAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO LENGTHEN'
},
{
'ID': 4120,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DAR UN PUÑETAZO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO PUNCH'
},
{
'ID': 4121,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DERRAMAR,TIRAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SPILL'
},
{
'ID': 4122,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AMENAZAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO THREATEN'
},
{
'ID': 4123,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CHALET ADOSADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TOWNHOUSE'
},
{
'ID': 4124,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CAPRICHOSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WHIMSICAL'
},
{
'ID': 4125,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AFABLE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AFFABLE'
},
{
'ID': 4126,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ATLETA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ATHLETE'
},
{
'ID': 4127,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'QUÍMICA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CHEMISTRY'
},
{
'ID': 4128,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONSEJERO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'COUNSELOR'
},
{
'ID': 4129,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DECEPCIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DISAPPOINTMENT'
},
{
'ID': 4130,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DE VEZ EN CUANDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EVERY ONCE IN A WHILE'
},
{
'ID': 4131,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DOTADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GIFTED'
},
{
'ID': 4132,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ANALFABETO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ILLITERATE'
},
{
'ID': 4133,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONCEPTO,PARTIDA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ITEM'
},
{
'ID': 4134,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LIO,FOLLÓN,DESORDEN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MESS'
},
{
'ID': 4135,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PEATÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PEDESTRIAN'
},
{
'ID': 4136,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PARIENTES,FAMILIARES',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RELATIVES'
},
{
'ID': 4137,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BUFANDA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SCARF'
},
{
'ID': 4138,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PECADOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SINNER'
},
{
'ID': 4139,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HOMBRE DE ESTADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'STATESMAN'
},
{
'ID': 4140,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FECHA OBJETIVO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TARGET DATE'
},
{
'ID': 4141,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AMENAZADOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THREATENING'
},
{
'ID': 4142,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AUMENTAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BOOST'
},
{
'ID': 4143,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AHOGARSE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO DROWN'
},
{
'ID': 4144,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DECEPCIONAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO LET DOWN'
},
{
'ID': 4145,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'APLAZAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO PUT OFF'
},
{
'ID': 4146,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESCUPIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SPIT'
},
{
'ID': 4147,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ORGANIZAR UNA FIESTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO THROW A PARTY'
},
{
'ID': 4148,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ATLETISMO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TRACK AND FIELD'
},
{
'ID': 4149,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LÁTIGO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WHIP'
},
{
'ID': 4150,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ACOMODADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AFFLUENT'
},
{
'ID': 4151,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INTENTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ATTEMPT'
},
{
'ID': 4152,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BARBILLA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CHIN'
},
{
'ID': 4153,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MOSTRADOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'COUNTER'
},
{
'ID': 4154,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESANIMADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DISCOURAGED'
},
{
'ID': 4155,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'UN DÍA SI Y OTRO NO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EVERY OTHER DAY'
},
{
'ID': 4156,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CHISMORREO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GOSSIP'
},
{
'ID': 4157,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESEQUILIBRIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IMBALANCE'
},
{
'ID': 4158,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MARFIL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IVORY'
},
{
'ID': 4159,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESORDENADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MESSY'
},
{
'ID': 4160,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SEMEJANTES',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PEERS'
},
{
'ID': 4161,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FIABILIDAD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RELIABILITY'
},
{
'ID': 4162,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PLAN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SCHEME'
},
{
'ID': 4163,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'UN ESCÉPTICO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'A SKEPTIC'
},
{
'ID': 4164,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONSTANTE Y EQUILIBRADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'STEADY'
},
{
'ID': 4165,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SABROSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TASTY'
},
{
'ID': 4166,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'UMBRAL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THRESHOLD'
},
{
'ID': 4167,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BOTAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BOUNCE'
},
{
'ID': 4168,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TEÑIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO DYE'
},
{
'ID': 4169,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TUMBARSE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO LIE DOWN'
},
{
'ID': 4170,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'REUNIR LAS CONDICIONES',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO QUALIFY'
},
{
'ID': 4171,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RIZAR EL RIZO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SPLIT HAIRS'
},
{
'ID': 4172,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TIRAR (A LA BASURA)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO THROW AWAY'
},
{
'ID': 4173,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'REMOLQUE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TRAILER'
},
{
'ID': 4174,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SILBATO,PITO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WHISTLE'
},
{
'ID': 4175,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AGRESIVO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AGGRESSIVE'
},
{
'ID': 4176,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ABOGADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ATTORNEY'
},
{
'ID': 4177,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NOCHE BUENA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CHRISTMAS EVE'
},
{
'ID': 4178,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PAISAJE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'COUNTRYSIDE'
},
{
'ID': 4179,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESALENTADOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DISCOURAGING'
},
{
'ID': 4180,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EXAGERACIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EXAGGERATION'
},
{
'ID': 4181,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESTUDIOS DE POSGRADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GRADUATE STUDIES'
},
{
'ID': 4182,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'IMPRESIONANTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IMPRESSIVE'
},
{
'ID': 4183,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FRASCO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'JAR'
},
{
'ID': 4184,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RESERVAS,RECELOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MISGIVINGS'
},
{
'ID': 4185,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PESETERO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PENNY PINCHER'
},
{
'ID': 4186,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FIABLE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RELIABLE'
},
{
'ID': 4187,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BECA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SCHOLARSHIP'
},
{
'ID': 4188,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESCEPTICO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SKEPTICAL'
},
{
'ID': 4189,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EMPINADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'STEEP'
},
{
'ID': 4190,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DECLARACIÓN DE LA RENTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TAX RETURN'
},
{
'ID': 4191,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AHORRATIVO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THRIFTY'
},
{
'ID': 4192,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SOBORNAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BRIBE'
},
{
'ID': 4193,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ABRAZAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO EMBRACE'
},
{
'ID': 4194,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COJEAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO LIMP'
},
{
'ID': 4195,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESHACERSE EN ELOGIOS SOBRE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO RAVE ABOUT'
},
{
'ID': 4196,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EXPRIMIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SQUEEZE'
},
{
'ID': 4197,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DEVOLVER,VOMITAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO THROW UP'
},
{
'ID': 4198,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TRAIDOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TRAITOR'
},
{
'ID': 4199,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AL POR MAYOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WHOLESALE'
},
{
'ID': 4200,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'OBJETIVO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AIM'
},
{
'ID': 4201,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DOLOR DE ESPALDA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BACKACHE'
},
{
'ID': 4202,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ALMEJAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CLAMS'
},
{
'ID': 4203,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VALOR,VALENTÍA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'COURAGE'
},
{
'ID': 4204,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESCUBRIMIENTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DISCOVERY'
},
{
'ID': 4205,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AGOTADO,RENDIDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EXHAUSTED'
},
{
'ID': 4206,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PROMOCIÓN (ESCOLAR)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GRADUATING CLASS'
},
{
'ID': 4207,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INAPROPIADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IMPROPER'
},
{
'ID': 4208,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'POR SI ACASO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'JUST IN CASE'
},
{
'ID': 4209,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENGAÑOSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MISLEADING'
},
{
'ID': 4210,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BUENA SALUD FÍSICA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PHYSICAL FITNESS'
},
{
'ID': 4211,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DIGNO DE ELOGIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'REMARKABLE'
},
{
'ID': 4212,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TIJERAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SCISSORS'
},
{
'ID': 4213,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESCEPTICISMO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SKEPTICISM'
},
{
'ID': 4214,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VOLANTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'STEERING WHEEL'
},
{
'ID': 4215,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONTRIBUYENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TAXPAYER'
},
{
'ID': 4216,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TRONO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THRONE'
},
{
'ID': 4217,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CRIAR,EDUCAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BRING UP'
},
{
'ID': 4218,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PERMITIR,POSIBILITAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ENABLE'
},
{
'ID': 4219,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESPERAR CON ILUSIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO LOOK FORWARD TO'
},
{
'ID': 4220,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'REACCIONAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO REACT'
},
{
'ID': 4221,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'APUÑALAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO STAB'
},
{
'ID': 4222,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HACER COSQUILLAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO TICKLE'
},
{
'ID': 4223,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PERIODO DE PRUEBA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TRIAL PERIOD'
},
{
'ID': 4224,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MAYORISTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WHOLESALER'
},
{
'ID': 4225,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PASILLO (AVIÓN, CINE, ETC.)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AISLE'
},
{
'ID': 4226,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TRABAJO RETRASADO ACUMULADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BACKLOG'
},
{
'ID': 4227,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COMPAÑERO DE CLASE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CLASSMATE'
},
{
'ID': 4228,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COBARDE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'COWARD'
},
{
'ID': 4229,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENFERMEDAD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DISEASE'
},
{
'ID': 4230,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CUENTA DE GASTOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EXPENSE ACCOUNT'
},
{
'ID': 4231,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GRATIFICANTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GRATIFYING'
},
{
'ID': 4232,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EN UN APRIETO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IN ABIND'
},
{
'ID': 4233,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RODILLA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'KNEE'
},
{
'ID': 4234,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MALENTENDIDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MISUNDERSTANDING'
},
{
'ID': 4235,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FÍSICA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PHYSICS'
},
{
'ID': 4236,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONTROL REMOTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'REMOTE CONTROL'
},
{
'ID': 4237,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PAPEL DE BORRADOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SCRATCH PAPER'
},
{
'ID': 4238,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MAÑOSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SKILLFUL'
},
{
'ID': 4239,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TALLO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'STEM'
},
{
'ID': 4240,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TENTADOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TEMPTING'
},
{
'ID': 4241,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DEDO PULGAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THUMB'
},
{
'ID': 4242,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'REVENTAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BURST'
},
{
'ID': 4243,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EVOLUCIONAR,DESARROLLAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO EVOLVE'
},
{
'ID': 4244,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INVESTIGAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO LOOK INTO'
},
{
'ID': 4245,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DARSE CUENTA DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO REALIZE'
},
{
'ID': 4246,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MANCHAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO STAIN'
},
{
'ID': 4247,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ATAR CABOS SUELTOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO TIE LOOSE ENDS'
},
{
'ID': 4248,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TRIBU',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TRIBE'
},
{
'ID': 4249,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PELUCA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WIG'
},
{
'ID': 4250,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ALIANZA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ALLIANCE'
},
{
'ID': 4251,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GLOBO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BALLOON'
},
{
'ID': 4252,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PRECIPICIO,ACANTILADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CLIFF'
},
{
'ID': 4253,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CANGREJO,NECORA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CRAB'
},
{
'ID': 4254,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VERGONZOSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DISGRACEFUL'
},
{
'ID': 4255,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EXPERIMENTADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EXPERIENCED'
},
{
'ID': 4256,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TUMBA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GRAVE'
},
{
'ID': 4257,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EN UN APRIETO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IN APINCH'
},
{
'ID': 4258,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NUDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'KNOT'
},
{
'ID': 4259,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MONOPOLIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MONOPOLY'
},
{
'ID': 4260,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RATERO,CARTERISTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PICKPOCKET'
},
{
'ID': 4261,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ELIMINACIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'REMOVAL'
},
{
'ID': 4262,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESTORNILLADOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SCREWDRIVER'
},
{
'ID': 4263,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FLACO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SKINNY'
},
{
'ID': 4264,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESTEREOTIPO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'STEREOTYPE'
},
{
'ID': 4265,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TIERNO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TENDER'
},
{
'ID': 4266,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'APRETADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TIGHT'
},
{
'ID': 4267,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EXIGIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO CALL FOR'
},
{
'ID': 4268,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SOBRESALIR,DESTACAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO EXCEL'
},
{
'ID': 4269,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PARECERSE A',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO LOOK LIKE'
},
{
'ID': 4270,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NEGARSE A',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO REFUSE'
},
{
'ID': 4271,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESTACAR,SOBRESALIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO STAND OUT'
},
{
'ID': 4272,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ANDAR DE PUNTILLAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO TIPTOE'
},
{
'ID': 4273,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TRAMPOSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TRICKY'
},
{
'ID': 4274,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PRUDENTE,JUICIOSO,SABIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WISE'
},
{
'ID': 4275,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ALIADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ALLY'
},
{
'ID': 4276,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EN QUIEBRA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BANKRUPT'
},
{
'ID': 4277,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ARMARIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CLOSET'
},
{
'ID': 4278,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GRIETA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CRACK'
},
{
'ID': 4279,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DISFRAZ',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DISGUISE'
},
{
'ID': 4280,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PERICIA,HABILIDAD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EXPERTISE'
},
{
'ID': 4281,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GRASIENTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GREASY'
},
{
'ID': 4282,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'POR ADELANTADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IN ADVANCE'
},
{
'ID': 4283,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONOCIMIENTOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'KNOWHOW'
},
{
'ID': 4284,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ES MAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MOREOVER'
},
{
'ID': 4285,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PALOMA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PIGEON'
},
{
'ID': 4286,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DE RENOMBRE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RENOWNED'
},
{
'ID': 4287,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GUIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SCRIPT'
},
{
'ID': 4288,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RASCACIELOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SKYSCRAPER'
},
{
'ID': 4289,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESTOFADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'STEW'
},
{
'ID': 4290,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PROVISIONAL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TENTATIVE'
},
{
'ID': 4291,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESTAÑO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TIN'
},
{
'ID': 4292,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CANCELAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO CALL OFF'
},
{
'ID': 4293,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SALIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO EXIT'
},
{
'ID': 4294,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FORRARSE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO MAKE A KILLING'
},
{
'ID': 4295,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ARREPENTIRSE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO REGRET'
},
{
'ID': 4296,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PARTIR DE CERO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO START FROM SCRATCH'
},
{
'ID': 4297,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LANZAR UNA MONEDA AL AIRE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO TOSS A COIN'
},
{
'ID': 4298,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TROPAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TROOPS'
},
{
'ID': 4299,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GUSANO,LOMBRIZ',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WORM'
},
{
'ID': 4300,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ALMENDRA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ALMOND'
},
{
'ID': 4301,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CEBADA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BARLEY'
},
{
'ID': 4302,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PISTA,INDICIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CLUE'
},
{
'ID': 4303,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CHOQUE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CRASH'
},
{
'ID': 4304,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INSATISFECHO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DISSATISFIED'
},
{
'ID': 4305,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FECHA DE CADUCIDAD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EXPIRATION DATE'
},
{
'ID': 4306,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AVARO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GREEDY'
},
{
'ID': 4307,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EN CUALQUIER CASO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IN ANY CASE'
},
{
'ID': 4308,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EXPERTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'KNOWLEDGEABLE'
},
{
'ID': 4309,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HIPOTECA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MORTGAGE'
},
{
'ID': 4310,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PELIGRO,ESCOLLO,TRAMPA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PITFALL'
},
{
'ID': 4311,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RESERVADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RESERVED'
},
{
'ID': 4312,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GAVIOTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SEA GULL'
},
{
'ID': 4313,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CALUMNIA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SLANDER'
},
{
'ID': 4314,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PALO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'STICK'
},
{
'ID': 4315,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FABULOSO,GENIAL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TERRIFIC'
},
{
'ID': 4316,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HASTA CIERTO PUNTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO A CERTAIN EXTENT'
},
{
'ID': 4317,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CALMARSE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO CALM DOWN'
},
{
'ID': 4318,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESFUMARSE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO FADE AWAY'
},
{
'ID': 4319,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BURLARSE DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO MAKE FUN OF'
},
{
'ID': 4320,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SOLTAR,LIBERAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO RELEASE'
},
{
'ID': 4321,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SEGUIR EN CONTACTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO STAY IN TOUCH'
},
{
'ID': 4322,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENDURECER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO TOUGHEN'
},
{
'ID': 4323,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DIGNO DE CONFIANZA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TRUSTWORTHY'
},
{
'ID': 4324,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SIN VALOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WORTHLESS'
},
{
'ID': 4325,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ALUMINIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ALUMINUM'
},
{
'ID': 4326,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BARRERA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BARRIER'
},
{
'ID': 4327,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENTRENADOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'COACH'
},
{
'ID': 4328,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TRIPULACIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CREW'
},
{
'ID': 4329,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BORRADOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DRAFT'
},
{
'ID': 4330,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CABLE ALARGADOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EXTENSION CORD'
},
{
'ID': 4331,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TASA DE CRECIMIENTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GROWTH RATE'
},
{
'ID': 4332,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EN CUALQUIER CASO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IN ANY EVENT'
},
{
'ID': 4333,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ETIQUETA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LABEL'
},
{
'ID': 4334,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MAYORMENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MOSTLY'
},
{
'ID': 4335,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DE SOBRA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PLENTY OF'
},
{
'ID': 4336,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EMBALSE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RESERVOIR'
},
{
'ID': 4337,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FOCA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SEAL'
},
{
'ID': 4338,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SESGADO,PARCIAL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SLANTED'
},
{
'ID': 4339,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PEGAJOSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'STICKY'
},
{
'ID': 4340,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TEXTURA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TEXTURE'
},
{
'ID': 4341,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LOGRAR,CONSEGUIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ACCOMPLISH'
},
{
'ID': 4342,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LLEVAR A CABO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO CARRY OUT'
},
{
'ID': 4343,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FRACASAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO FAIL'
},
{
'ID': 4344,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CAUSAR PROBLEMAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO MAKE TROUBLE'
},
{
'ID': 4345,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DEPENDER DE,CONFIAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EN TO RELY ON'
},
{
'ID': 4346,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PEGAR (CON PEGAMENTO)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO STICK'
},
{
'ID': 4347,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'REMOLCAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO TOW'
},
{
'ID': 4348,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MATRICULA,TASAS ACADÉMICAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TUITION'
},
{
'ID': 4349,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HERIDA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WOUND'
},
{
'ID': 4350,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SIMPÁTICO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AMIABLE'
},
{
'ID': 4351,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ALBORNOZ',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BATHROBE'
},
{
'ID': 4352,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CARBÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'COAL'
},
{
'ID': 4353,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COSECHA,CULTIVO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CROP'
},
{
'ID': 4354,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'UN INCONVENIENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'A DRAWBACK'
},
{
'ID': 4355,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INSTALACIONES',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FACILITES'
},
{
'ID': 4356,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DIRECTRICES',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GUIDELINES'
},
{
'ID': 4357,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RESPONSABLE DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IN CHARGE OF'
},
{
'ID': 4358,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CHULETAS DE CORDERO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LAMB CHOPS'
},
{
'ID': 4359,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LENGUA MATERNA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MOTHER TONGUE'
},
{
'ID': 4360,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENCHUFE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PLUG'
},
{
'ID': 4361,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DE CARÁCTER FUERTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RESILIENT'
},
{
'ID': 4362,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SEMILLAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SEEDS'
},
{
'ID': 4363,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NEGRERO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SLAVE DRIVER'
},
{
'ID': 4364,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ROÑOSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'STINGY'
},
{
'ID': 4365,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LOS ÁRABES',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THE ARABS'
},
{
'ID': 4366,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LOGRAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ACHIEVE'
},
{
'ID': 4367,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ALCANZAR (DESDE ATRÁS)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO CATCH UP'
},
{
'ID': 4368,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESMAYAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO FAINT'
},
{
'ID': 4369,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HACER USO DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO MAKE USE OF'
},
{
'ID': 4370,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RESCATAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO RESCUE'
},
{
'ID': 4371,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'APESTAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO STINK'
},
{
'ID': 4372,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ATRAPAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO TRAP'
},
{
'ID': 4373,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ATÚN,BONITO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TUNA'
},
{
'ID': 4374,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HERIDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WOUNDED'
},
{
'ID': 4375,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'UN CONOCIDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AN ACQUAINTANCE'
},
{
'ID': 4376,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CARNE DE VACUNO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BEEF'
},
{
'ID': 4377,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COLEGA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'COLLEAGUE'
},
{
'ID': 4378,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CRUCIGRAMA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CROSSWORD PUZZLE'
},
{
'ID': 4379,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TAMBOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DRUM'
},
{
'ID': 4380,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FRACASO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FAILURE'
},
{
'ID': 4381,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONEJILLO DE INDIAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GUINEA PIG'
},
{
'ID': 4382,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EN DECLIVE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IN DECLINE'
},
{
'ID': 4383,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PAISAJE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LANDSCAPE'
},
{
'ID': 4384,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LEMA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MOTTO'
},
{
'ID': 4385,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FONTANERÍA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PLUMBING'
},
{
'ID': 4386,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DECIDIDO,RESUELTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RESOLUTE'
},
{
'ID': 4387,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EGOCÉNTRICO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SELF-CENTERED'
},
{
'ID': 4388,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESCLAVITUD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SLAVERY'
},
{
'ID': 4389,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LA BOLSA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THE STOCK EXCHANGE'
},
{
'ID': 4390,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EL CANAL DE LA MANCHA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THE ENGLISH CHANNEL'
},
{
'ID': 4391,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ADMITIR,RECONOCER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ACKNOWLEDGE'
},
{
'ID': 4392,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CESAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO CEASE'
},
{
'ID': 4393,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VENIRSE ABAJO (UN PLAN)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO FALL THROUGH'
},
{
'ID': 4394,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TACHAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO MARK OUT'
},
{
'ID': 4395,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'JUBILARSE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO RETIRE'
},
{
'ID': 4396,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENDEREZAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO STRAIGHTEN'
},
{
'ID': 4397,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONFIAR EN,FIARSE DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO TRUST'
},
{
'ID': 4398,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PROFESOR PARTICULAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TUTOR'
},
{
'ID': 4399,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ARRUGAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WRINKLES'
},
{
'ID': 4400,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'UNA MOLESTIA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AN INCONVENIENCE'
},
{
'ID': 4401,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DE ANTEMANO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BEFOREHAND'
},
{
'ID': 4402,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ANUNCIO (EN TELEVISIÓN)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'COMMERCIAL'
},
{
'ID': 4403,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CRUCERO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CRUISE'
},
{
'ID': 4404,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TINTORERÍA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DRY CLEANERS'
},
{
'ID': 4405,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'JUEGO LIMPIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FAIR PLAY'
},
{
'ID': 4406,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RESACA (POR BEBER MUCHO)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HANGOVER'
},
{
'ID': 4407,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EN PROFUNDIDAD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IN DEPTH'
},
{
'ID': 4408,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CARRIL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LANE'
},
{
'ID': 4409,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ALPINISTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MOUNTAIN CLIMBER'
},
{
'ID': 4410,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'OSO POLAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'POLAR BEAR'
},
{
'ID': 4411,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INGENIOSO,QUE TIENE RECURSOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RESOURCEFUL'
},
{
'ID': 4412,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONFIANZA EN UNO MISMO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SELF-CONFIDENCE'
},
{
'ID': 4413,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SOMNÍFERO SLEEPING',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PILL'
},
{
'ID': 4414,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TABURETE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'STOOL'
},
{
'ID': 4415,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LA META',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THE FINISH LINE'
},
{
'ID': 4416,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DIRIGIR LA PALABRA A',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ADDRESS'
},
{
'ID': 4417,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PERSEGUIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO CHASE'
},
{
'ID': 4418,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TENER GANAS DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO FEEL LIKE'
},
{
'ID': 4419,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CASAR,HACER JUEGO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO MATCH'
},
{
'ID': 4420,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BATIRSE EN RETIRADA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO RETREAT'
},
{
'ID': 4421,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FORTALECER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO STRENGTHEN'
},
{
'ID': 4422,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PROBARSE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO TRY ON'
},
{
'ID': 4423,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INDUDABLEMENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'UNDOUBTEDLY'
},
{
'ID': 4424,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'APUNTALO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WRITE IT DOWN'
},
{
'ID': 4425,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'UN NUMERO IMPAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AN ODD NUMBER'
},
{
'ID': 4426,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PERTENENCIAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BELONGINGS'
},
{
'ID': 4427,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COMPROMISO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'COMMITMENT'
},
{
'ID': 4428,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ADUANA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CUSTOMS'
},
{
'ID': 4429,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ABURRIDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DULL'
},
{
'ID': 4430,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FAITH'
},
{
'ID': 4431,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DAÑINO,PERJUDICIAL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HARMFUL'
},
{
'ID': 4432,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EN VIGOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IN FORCE'
},
{
'ID': 4433,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RISA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LAUGHTER'
},
{
'ID': 4434,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PUERTO DE MONTAÑA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MOUNTAIN PASS'
},
{
'ID': 4435,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'POLÍTICA (DE ACTUACIÓN)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'POLICY'
},
{
'ID': 4436,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RECURSOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RESOURCES'
},
{
'ID': 4437,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TÍMIDO,COHIBIDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SELF-CONSCIOUS'
},
{
'ID': 4438,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESBELTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SLENDER'
},
{
'ID': 4439,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CIGÜEÑA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'STORK'
},
{
'ID': 4440,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EL ESPÍRITU SANTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THE HOLY SPIRIT'
},
{
'ID': 4441,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LEVANTAR (UNA SESIÓN)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ADJOURN'
},
{
'ID': 4442,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MASTICAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO CHEW'
},
{
'ID': 4443,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AVERIGUAR,ENTERARSE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO FIND OUT'
},
{
'ID': 4444,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DERRETIR,FUNDIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO MELT'
},
{
'ID': 4445,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MODIFICAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO REVISE'
},
{
'ID': 4446,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HACER HUELGA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO STRIKE'
},
{
'ID': 4447,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RECHAZAR,BAJAR (VOLUMEN)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO TURN DOWN'
},
{
'ID': 4448,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INTRANQUILO,PREOCUPADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'UNEASY'
},
{
'ID': 4449,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RADIOGRAFÍA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'X-RAY'
},
{
'ID': 4450,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MOLESTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ANNOYING'
},
{
'ID': 4451,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'APUESTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BET'
},
{
'ID': 4452,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COMPARACIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'COMPARISON'
},
{
'ID': 4453,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RECORTE (PRESUPUESTARIO)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CUTBACK'
},
{
'ID': 4454,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TONTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DUMB'
},
{
'ID': 4455,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FIEL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FAITHFUL'
},
{
'ID': 4456,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INOFENSIVO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HARMLESS'
},
{
'ID': 4457,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EN PRIVADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IN PRIVATE'
},
{
'ID': 4458,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PLEITO,DEMANDA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LAWSUIT'
},
{
'ID': 4459,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CORDILLERA,SIERRA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MOUNTAIN RANGE'
},
{
'ID': 4460,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LA POLÍTICA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'POLITICS'
},
{
'ID': 4461,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CURRICULUM VITAE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RESUME'
},
{
'ID': 4462,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AUTO-ESTIMA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SELF-ESTEEM'
},
{
'ID': 4463,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LONCHA,REBANADA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SLICE'
},
{
'ID': 4464,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TORMENTOSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'STORMY'
},
{
'ID': 4465,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LA EDAD DEL HIELO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THE ICE AGE'
},
{
'ID': 4466,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ACONSEJAR,ASESORAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ADVISE'
},
{
'ID': 4467,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DECLARAR (CON PRETENSIONES)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO CLAIM'
},
{
'ID': 4468,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'REUNIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO GATHER'
},
{
'ID': 4469,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FUSIONAR (EMPRESAS)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO MERGE'
},
{
'ID': 4470,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CODEARSE CON',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO RUB SHOULDERS WITH'
},
{
'ID': 4471,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESFORZARSE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO STRIVE'
},
{
'ID': 4472,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'APARECER,SUBIR (VOLUMEN)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO TURN UP'
},
{
'ID': 4473,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EL PARO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'UNEMPLOYMENT'
},
{
'ID': 4474,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'YATE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'YACHT'
},
{
'ID': 4475,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ANSIEDAD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ANXIETY'
},
{
'ID': 4476,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BIÓLOGO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BIOLOGIST'
},
{
'ID': 4477,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COMPETITIVIDAD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'COMPETITIVENESS'
},
{
'ID': 4478,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RECORTES',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CUTBACKS'
},
{
'ID': 4479,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DEBER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DUTY'
},
{
'ID': 4480,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FALSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FAKE'
},
{
'ID': 4481,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ÁSPERO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HARSH'
},
{
'ID': 4482,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EN RESUMIDAS CUENTAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IN SHORT'
},
{
'ID': 4483,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CAPA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LAYER'
},
{
'ID': 4484,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INGENUO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NAIVE'
},
{
'ID': 4485,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RECORTE DE PRENSA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PRESS CLIPPING'
},
{
'ID': 4486,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AL POR MENOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RETAIL'
},
{
'ID': 4487,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INDEPENDIENTE Y SEGURO DE SI',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SELF-RELIANT'
},
{
'ID': 4488,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ALPARGATAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SLIPPERS'
},
{
'ID': 4489,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PAJA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'STRAW'
},
{
'ID': 4490,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LA GOTA QUE COLMO EL VASO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THE LAST STRAW'
},
{
'ID': 4491,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SOLICITAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO APPLY FOR'
},
{
'ID': 4492,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ACLARAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO CLEAR UP'
},
{
'ID': 4493,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SALIR ADELANTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO GET AHEAD'
},
{
'ID': 4494,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TRASPAPELAR,PERDER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO MISPLACE'
},
{
'ID': 4495,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESCARTAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO RULE OUT'
},
{
'ID': 4496,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TROPEZAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO STUMBLE'
},
{
'ID': 4497,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SUBESTIMAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO UNDERESTIMATE'
},
{
'ID': 4498,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INJUSTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'UNFAIR'
},
{
'ID': 4499,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 5,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'YA LO SUPERARAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'YOU\'LL GET OVER IT'
},
{
'ID': 4500,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ABURRIDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DULL'
},
{
'ID': 4501,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ALCANZAR (DESDE ATRÁS)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO CATCH UP'
},
{
'ID': 4502,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ASEGURARSE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO MAKE CERTAIN'
},
{
'ID': 4503,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BUITRE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'VULTURE'
},
{
'ID': 4504,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CARNE Y HUESO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FLESH AND BLOOD'
},
{
'ID': 4505,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CITA,COMPROMISO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'APPOINTMENT'
},
{
'ID': 4506,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CUANTO ANTES MEJOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THE SOONER THE BETTER'
},
{
'ID': 4507,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESCASO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SCARCE'
},
{
'ID': 4508,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FABRICANTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MANUFACTURER'
},
{
'ID': 4509,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FIABLE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RELIABLE'
},
{
'ID': 4510,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GOMA ESPUMA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FOAM RUBBER'
},
{
'ID': 4511,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GUARDERÍA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DAYCARE CENTER'
},
{
'ID': 4512,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HOMBRE DE ESTADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'STATESMAN'
},
{
'ID': 4513,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LA JUBILACIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RETIREMENT'
},
{
'ID': 4514,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LOS AÑOS CINCUENTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THE FIFTIES'
},
{
'ID': 4515,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NEGLIGENCIA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NEGLIGENCE'
},
{
'ID': 4516,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'OBJETIVO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AIM'
},
{
'ID': 4517,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PERICIA,HABILIDAD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EXPERTISE'
},
{
'ID': 4518,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PORTÁTIL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PORTABLE'
},
{
'ID': 4519,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PREVER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO FORESEE'
},
{
'ID': 4520,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PROCEDIMIENTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PROCEDURE'
},
{
'ID': 4521,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PROPOSITO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PURPOSE'
},
{
'ID': 4522,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'REALZAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ENHANCE'
},
{
'ID': 4523,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'REFERENCIA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'REFERRAL'
},
{
'ID': 4524,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '01',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SOSPECHAR ALGO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SMELL A RAT'
},
{
'ID': 4525,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BIEN TRATADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WELL-TREATED'
},
{
'ID': 4526,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CABEZA DE TURCO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SCAPEGOAT'
},
{
'ID': 4527,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CANDIDATO,SOLICITANTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'APPLICANT'
},
{
'ID': 4528,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DAÑINO,PERJUDICIAL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HARMFUL'
},
{
'ID': 4529,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESACELERAR,IR MAS DESPACIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SLOW DOWN'
},
{
'ID': 4530,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESCUBRIMIENTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DISCOVERY'
},
{
'ID': 4531,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESMORALIZANTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DEMORALIZING'
},
{
'ID': 4532,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DUDOSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HESITANT'
},
{
'ID': 4533,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENORME',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HUGE'
},
{
'ID': 4534,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESTIRAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO STRETCH'
},
{
'ID': 4535,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EXPULSAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO EXPEL'
},
{
'ID': 4536,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FECHA OBJETIVO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TARGET DATE'
},
{
'ID': 4537,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FUERA DE CONTEXTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'OUT OF CONTEXT'
},
{
'ID': 4538,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MALENTENDIDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MISUNDERSTANDING'
},
{
'ID': 4539,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MORTAL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DEADLY'
},
{
'ID': 4540,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'OCIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LEISURE'
},
{
'ID': 4541,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PONERSE NERVIOSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO GET NERVOUS'
},
{
'ID': 4542,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RECETA (MEDICA)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PRESCRIPTION'
},
{
'ID': 4543,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RECHAZAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO REJECT'
},
{
'ID': 4544,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RELACIÓN,COMPENETRACIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RAPPORT'
},
{
'ID': 4545,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RESPONSABLE DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IN CHARGE OF'
},
{
'ID': 4546,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SUGERIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SUGGEST'
},
{
'ID': 4547,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TOMAR MEDIDAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO TAKE STEPS'
},
{
'ID': 4548,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TRANQUILIZADOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'REASSURING'
},
{
'ID': 4549,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '02',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TROPAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TROOPS'
},
{
'ID': 4550,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ADEMAS (DE)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BESIDES'
},
{
'ID': 4551,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AMENAZADOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THREATENING'
},
{
'ID': 4552,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AUTÓNOMO (TRABAJADOR)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SELF-EMPLOYED'
},
{
'ID': 4553,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CEPILLO DE DIENTES',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TOOTHBRUSH'
},
{
'ID': 4554,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CRUCE (DE CALLES)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'INTERSECTION'
},
{
'ID': 4555,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CULEBRA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SNAKE'
},
{
'ID': 4556,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CURRICULUM VITAE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RESUME'
},
{
'ID': 4557,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESCARGAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO UNLOAD'
},
{
'ID': 4558,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DISFRAZ',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DISGUISE'
},
{
'ID': 4559,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ECONÓMICAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ECONOMICS'
},
{
'ID': 4560,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EN VIGOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IN FORCE'
},
{
'ID': 4561,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENGAÑOSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MISLEADING'
},
{
'ID': 4562,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FIRMAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SIGN'
},
{
'ID': 4563,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INCOMODO,INOPORTUNO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'INCONVENIENT'
},
{
'ID': 4564,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INSTALACIONES',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FACILITES'
},
{
'ID': 4565,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LIARSE,CONFUNDIRSE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO GET MIXED UP'
},
{
'ID': 4566,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LOGÍSTICA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LOGISTICS'
},
{
'ID': 4567,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MANSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TAME'
},
{
'ID': 4568,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MASACRE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MASSACRE'
},
{
'ID': 4569,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MATERIAS PRIMAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RAW MATERIALS'
},
{
'ID': 4570,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NOTAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO NOTICE'
},
{
'ID': 4571,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PLUMA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FEATHER'
},
{
'ID': 4572,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RECUPERACIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RECOVERY'
},
{
'ID': 4573,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RECURRIRÁ',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO RESORT TO'
},
{
'ID': 4574,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '03',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VIABLE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'VIABLE'
},
{
'ID': 4575,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AGOTADO (NO EN EXISTENCIA)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'OUT OF STOCK'
},
{
'ID': 4576,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ARMARIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CLOSET'
},
{
'ID': 4577,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AUMENTAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BOOST'
},
{
'ID': 4578,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AVISPA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WASP'
},
{
'ID': 4579,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BUENA SALUD FÍSICA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PHYSICAL FITNESS'
},
{
'ID': 4580,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CARBÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'COAL'
},
{
'ID': 4581,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CÓMODO,OPORTUNO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CONVENIENT'
},
{
'ID': 4582,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONFIADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CONFIDENT'
},
{
'ID': 4583,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONFIANZA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CONFIDENCE'
},
{
'ID': 4584,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONSIDERACIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THOUGHTFULNESS'
},
{
'ID': 4585,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DAR UN PASEO (EN COCHE)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO GO FOR A DRIVE'
},
{
'ID': 4586,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DE OTRO MODO,SI NO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'OTHERWISE'
},
{
'ID': 4587,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EFICAZMENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EFFECTIVELY'
},
{
'ID': 4588,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GAMA,SURTIDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ARRAY'
},
{
'ID': 4589,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HABILIDAD,PERICIA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SKILL'
},
{
'ID': 4590,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INGRESOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'REVENUE'
},
{
'ID': 4591,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INSTALAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO INSTALL'
},
{
'ID': 4592,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LAS PAGINAS AMARILLAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THE YELLOW PAGES'
},
{
'ID': 4593,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'POLÍTICA (DE ACTUACIÓN)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'POLICY'
},
{
'ID': 4594,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PUNTO DÉBIL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WEAK POINT'
},
{
'ID': 4595,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'REFERENTE A',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CONCERNING'
},
{
'ID': 4596,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RENTABILIDAD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PROFITABILITY'
},
{
'ID': 4597,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SEGUIR EN CONTACTO CON',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO STAY IN CONTACT WITH'
},
{
'ID': 4598,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SIN EMBARGO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HOWEVER'
},
{
'ID': 4599,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '04',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SUGERENCIA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SUGGESTION'
},
{
'ID': 4600,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ACERCARSE A',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO APPROACH'
},
{
'ID': 4601,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AHOGARSE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO DROWN'
},
{
'ID': 4602,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AHORROS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SAVINGS'
},
{
'ID': 4603,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ALBORNOZ',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BATHROBE'
},
{
'ID': 4604,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ANIMO,ALIENTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ENCOURAGEMENT'
},
{
'ID': 4605,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ARROZ',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RICE'
},
{
'ID': 4606,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DIGNO DE ELOGIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'REMARKABLE'
},
{
'ID': 4607,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENFOQUE,PLANTEAMIENTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'APPROACH'
},
{
'ID': 4608,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ES MAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MOREOVER'
},
{
'ID': 4609,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DISCULPA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'APOLOGY'
},
{
'ID': 4610,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FAROLEAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BLUFF'
},
{
'ID': 4611,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INFLUYENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'INFLUENTIAL'
},
{
'ID': 4612,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INVERSIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'INVESTMENT'
},
{
'ID': 4613,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'JUBILARSE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO RETIRE'
},
{
'ID': 4614,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LOS MOROS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THE MOORS'
},
{
'ID': 4615,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LLEVAR A CABO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO CARRY OUT'
},
{
'ID': 4616,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PERSONAL (DE PLANTILLA)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PERSONNEL'
},
{
'ID': 4617,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PERTENENCIAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BELONGINGS'
},
{
'ID': 4618,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'REPENTINO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SUDDEN'
},
{
'ID': 4619,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RESTRINGIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO RESTRICT'
},
{
'ID': 4620,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SABIDURÍA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WISDOM'
},
{
'ID': 4621,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SIN DUDA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NO DOUBT'
},
{
'ID': 4622,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SOBREPASAR,SUPERAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SURPASS'
},
{
'ID': 4623,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SUPERAR,SOBREPONERSE A',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO OVERCOME'
},
{
'ID': 4624,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '05',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TENDENCIA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TREND'
},
{
'ID': 4625,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'iCÁLLATE!',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SHUT UP!'
},
{
'ID': 4626,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': '¿POR QUE?',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HOW COME?'
},
{
'ID': 4627,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'APLAZAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TOPUTOFF'
},
{
'ID': 4628,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BRISA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BREEZE'
},
{
'ID': 4629,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CHAPUCERO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LOUSY'
},
{
'ID': 4630,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DAR A ENTENDER,IMPLICAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO IMPLY'
},
{
'ID': 4631,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESPEDIR (EN MASA)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO LAY OFF'
},
{
'ID': 4632,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESPIERTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AWAKE'
},
{
'ID': 4633,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DIRECTRICES',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GUIDELINES'
},
{
'ID': 4634,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENSEGUIDA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PROMPTLY'
},
{
'ID': 4635,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESTAR DE BUEN HUMOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BE IN A GOOD MOOD'
},
{
'ID': 4636,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HASTA AHORA TODO BIEN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SO FAR SO GOOD'
},
{
'ID': 4637,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INSTALACIONES',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FACILITES'
},
{
'ID': 4638,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MAITRE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HEAD WAITER'
},
{
'ID': 4639,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PALOMA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PIGEON'
},
{
'ID': 4640,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PERDONAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO FORGIVE'
},
{
'ID': 4641,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PERIODO DE PRUEBA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TRIAL PERIOD'
},
{
'ID': 4642,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'POR LO TANTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THUS'
},
{
'ID': 4643,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RECURSOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RESOURCES'
},
{
'ID': 4644,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'REGALAR (POR NO QUERER)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TOGIVEAWAY'
},
{
'ID': 4645,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RELÁMPAGO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LIGHTNING'
},
{
'ID': 4646,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SUPERVIVENCIA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SURVIVAL'
},
{
'ID': 4647,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TIJERAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SCISSORS'
},
{
'ID': 4648,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VALER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BE WORTH'
},
{
'ID': 4649,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '06',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VOLCAN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'VOLCANO'
},
{
'ID': 4650,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ACOSTUMBRADO A',
        'RESPUESTA': 'USED TO'
},
{
'ID': 4651,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ADINERADO,RICO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WEALTHY'
},
{
'ID': 4652,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ARDOR (DE ESTOMAGO)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HEART BURN'
},
{
'ID': 4653,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AVERIGUAR,ENTERARSE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO FIND OUT'
},
{
'ID': 4654,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DE RENOMBRE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RENOWNED'
},
{
'ID': 4655,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESPERDICIAR,MALGASTAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO WASTE'
},
{
'ID': 4656,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DIGNO DE ELOGIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PRAISEWORTHY'
},
{
'ID': 4657,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESCUPIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SPIT'
},
{
'ID': 4658,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GRAPA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'STAPLE'
},
{
'ID': 4659,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HABLADOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TALKATIVE'
},
{
'ID': 4660,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INEVITABLE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'UNAVOIDABLE'
},
{
'ID': 4661,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INVERSIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'INVESTMENT'
},
{
'ID': 4662,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LANZAR,ARROJAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO THROW'
},
{
'ID': 4663,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LENGUA MATERNA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MOTHER TONGUE'
},
{
'ID': 4664,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LOGRO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ACHIEVEMENT'
},
{
'ID': 4665,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MIENTRAS TANTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IN THE MEANTIME'
},
{
'ID': 4666,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PASÁRSELO BIEN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO HAVE A GOOD TIME'
},
{
'ID': 4667,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PENSAR EN VOZ ALTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO THINK OUT LOUD'
},
{
'ID': 4668,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PERSPECTIVAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PROSPECTS'
},
{
'ID': 4669,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'QUINCENA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FORTNIGHT'
},
{
'ID': 4670,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RESUMIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SUMMARIZE'
},
{
'ID': 4671,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SENSIBLE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SENSITIVE'
},
{
'ID': 4672,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TRADUCCIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TRANSLATION'
},
{
'ID': 4673,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TRAMPA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TRAP'
},
{
'ID': 4674,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '07',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VOLANTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'STEERING WHEEL'
},
{
'ID': 4675,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'A LA LARGA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IN THE LONG RUN'
},
{
'ID': 4676,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ASUSTAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SCARE'
},
{
'ID': 4677,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AUTO-SUFICIENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SELF-SUFFICIENT'
},
{
'ID': 4678,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AUTORIZAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO AUTHORIZE'
},
{
'ID': 4679,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BENEFICIOS SOCIALES DE NOMINA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FRINGE BENEFITS'
},
{
'ID': 4680,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CANCELAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO CALL OFF'
},
{
'ID': 4681,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CERRAR CON LLAVE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO LOCK'
},
{
'ID': 4682,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONTRIBUYENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TAXPAYER'
},
{
'ID': 4683,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DISGUSTADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'UPSET'
},
{
'ID': 4684,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EMPRENDEDOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ENTERPRISING'
},
{
'ID': 4685,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EN CONSECUENCIA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ACCORDINGLY'
},
{
'ID': 4686,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENCHUFE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PLUG'
},
{
'ID': 4687,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FABRICAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO MANUFACTURE'
},
{
'ID': 4688,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GUIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SCRIPT'
},
{
'ID': 4689,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HOGAR DE ANCIANOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NURSING HOME'
},
{
'ID': 4690,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HOMBRO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SHOULDER'
},
{
'ID': 4691,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INGENUO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NAIVE'
},
{
'ID': 4692,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INMOBILIARIA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'REAL ESTATE'
},
{
'ID': 4693,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MADURO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MATURE'
},
{
'ID': 4694,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ORGANIZAR UNA FIESTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO THROW A PARTY'
},
{
'ID': 4695,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RECALCAR,SEÑALAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO POINT OUT'
},
{
'ID': 4696,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SIGNIFICATIVO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MEANINGFUL'
},
{
'ID': 4697,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TESORO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TREASURE'
},
{
'ID': 4698,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'UN NUMERO IMPAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AN ODD NUMBER'
},
{
'ID': 4699,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '08',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VIDA NOCTURNA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NIGHT LIFE'
},
{
'ID': 4700,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ACERTIJO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RIDDLE'
},
{
'ID': 4701,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ADUANA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CUSTOMS'
},
{
'ID': 4702,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AFEITARSE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SHAVE'
},
{
'ID': 4703,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AL REVÉS (POSICIÓN INVERTIDA)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'UPSIDE DOWN'
},
{
'ID': 4704,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ATLETISMO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TRACK AND FIELD'
},
{
'ID': 4705,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COMPROMISO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'COMMITMENT'
},
{
'ID': 4706,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CHAPUCERO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SLOPPY'
},
{
'ID': 4707,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CHIRIMBOLO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CONTRAPTION'
},
{
'ID': 4708,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DE CARÁCTER FUERTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RESILIENT'
},
{
'ID': 4709,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESEMPEÑAR UN PAPEL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO PLAY A ROLE'
},
{
'ID': 4710,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DOLOROSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PAINFUL'
},
{
'ID': 4711,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENGAÑAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO DECEIVE'
},
{
'ID': 4712,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GABARDINA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'OVERCOAT'
},
{
'ID': 4713,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GANADO VACUNO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CATTLE'
},
{
'ID': 4714,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INCAPACITADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DISABLED'
},
{
'ID': 4715,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INVERTIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO INVEST'
},
{
'ID': 4716,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NO TIENE SENTIDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IT DOESNT MAKE ANY SENSE'
},
{
'ID': 4717,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'POTENTE,PODEROSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'POWERFUL'
},
{
'ID': 4718,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'QUIOSCO DE PRENSA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NEWSSTAND'
},
{
'ID': 4719,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RASCACIELOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SKYSCRAPER'
},
{
'ID': 4720,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RECOMPENSA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'REWARD'
},
{
'ID': 4721,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RUTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ROUTE'
},
{
'ID': 4722,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SIEMPRE QUE...',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WHENEVER...'
},
{
'ID': 4723,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SILBAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO WHISTLE'
},
{
'ID': 4724,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '09',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TRONO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THRONE'
},
{
'ID': 4725,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AL AZAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AT RANDOM'
},
{
'ID': 4726,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ANTIGÜEDAD (EN UNA EMPRESA)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SENIORITY'
},
{
'ID': 4727,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'APUNTAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO AIM'
},
{
'ID': 4728,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BUSCAR Y CONTRATAR A',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PERSONAL TO RECRUIT'
},
{
'ID': 4729,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CABER,AJUSTARSE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TOFIT'
},
{
'ID': 4730,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CARGADO (EL AMBIENTE)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'STUFFY'
},
{
'ID': 4731,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CLAXON,BOCINA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HORN'
},
{
'ID': 4732,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COLONIZADOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SETTLER'
},
{
'ID': 4733,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CRITICAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO CRITICIZE'
},
{
'ID': 4734,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ECHAR LA SIESTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO TAKE A NAP'
},
{
'ID': 4735,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EN NOMBRE DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ON BEHALF OF'
},
{
'ID': 4736,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESPERAR CON ILUSIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO LOOK FORWARD TO'
},
{
'ID': 4737,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESTOFADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'STEW'
},
{
'ID': 4738,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FUSIÓN (DE EMPRESAS)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MERGER'
},
{
'ID': 4739,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HASTA CIERTO PUNTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO A CERTAIN EXTENT'
},
{
'ID': 4740,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LÁTIGO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WHIP'
},
{
'ID': 4741,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LESIONAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO INJURE'
},
{
'ID': 4742,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MANEJAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO HANDLE'
},
{
'ID': 4743,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PESIMISTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PESSIMISTIC'
},
{
'ID': 4744,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'POR CIERTO,A PROPOSITO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BY THE WAY'
},
{
'ID': 4745,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PREDECIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO PREDICT'
},
{
'ID': 4746,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PUERTO DE MONTAÑA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MOUNTAIN PASS'
},
{
'ID': 4747,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RETO,DESAFIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CHALLENGE'
},
{
'ID': 4748,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SEMILLAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SEEDS'
},
{
'ID': 4749,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '10',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TEJADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ROOF'
},
{
'ID': 4750,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'A LA LARGA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EVENTUALLY'
},
{
'ID': 4751,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ADVERTENCIA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WARNING'
},
{
'ID': 4752,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ALQUILAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO RENT'
},
{
'ID': 4753,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'APUÑALAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO STAB'
},
{
'ID': 4754,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BRUJA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WITCH'
},
{
'ID': 4755,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BUROCRACIA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BUREAUCRACY'
},
{
'ID': 4756,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CAPATAZ',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FOREMAN'
},
{
'ID': 4757,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CARACOL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SNAIL'
},
{
'ID': 4758,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CLIP',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PAPER CLIP'
},
{
'ID': 4759,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONFUNDIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO CONFUSE'
},
{
'ID': 4760,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CÓNYUGE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SPOUSE'
},
{
'ID': 4761,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESANIMADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DISCOURAGED'
},
{
'ID': 4762,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESMORALIZAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO DEMORALIZE'
},
{
'ID': 4763,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SER CONSCIENTE DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BE AWARE OF'
},
{
'ID': 4764,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EXIGIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO DEMAND'
},
{
'ID': 4765,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LA LETRA (DE UNA CANCIÓN)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THE LYRICS'
},
{
'ID': 4766,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NEGRERO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SLAVE DRIVER'
},
{
'ID': 4767,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PERDER TIEMPO (MALGASTAR)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO WASTE TIME'
},
{
'ID': 4768,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PROVISIONAL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TENTATIVE'
},
{
'ID': 4769,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SEMANA SANTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EASTER'
},
{
'ID': 4770,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SOPORTAR,AGUANTAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TOBEAR'
},
{
'ID': 4771,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SUELO (AGRÍCOLA)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SOIL'
},
{
'ID': 4772,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TÍMIDO,COHIBIDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SELF-CONSCIOUS'
},
{
'ID': 4773,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TRANQUILIZAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO REASSURE'
},
{
'ID': 4774,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '11',
        'PREGUNTA': 'UNA REUNIÓN AMISTOSA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'A GET-TOGETHER'
},
{
'ID': 4775,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ADIVINAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO GUESS'
},
{
'ID': 4776,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ALREDEDORES',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SURROUNDINGS'
},
{
'ID': 4777,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AVERIA,DESGLOSE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BREAKDOWN'
},
{
'ID': 4778,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BIENESTAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WELFARE'
},
{
'ID': 4779,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BRONCEADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SUNTAN'
},
{
'ID': 4780,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EN CAMBIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ON THE OTHER HAND'
},
{
'ID': 4781,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESBELTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SLENDER'
},
{
'ID': 4782,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESTAÑO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TIN'
},
{
'ID': 4783,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESTAR DISPUESTO A',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BE WILLING TO'
},
{
'ID': 4784,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HACER COSQUILLAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO TICKLE'
},
{
'ID': 4785,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ILIMITADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'UNLIMITED'
},
{
'ID': 4786,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INDEPENDIENTEMENTE DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'REGARDLESS OF'
},
{
'ID': 4787,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LA NATURALEZA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NATURE'
},
{
'ID': 4788,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LUJOSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LUXURIOUS'
},
{
'ID': 4789,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MEDIDA,MEDICIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MEASUREMENT'
},
{
'ID': 4790,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'OLVÍDALO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NEVER MIND'
},
{
'ID': 4791,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PROBABILIDAD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LIKELIHOOD'
},
{
'ID': 4792,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PROMETIDO (PARA CASARSE)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ENGAGED'
},
{
'ID': 4793,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'REFORZAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO REINFORCE'
},
{
'ID': 4794,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'REUNIRSE (INFORMALMENTE)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO GET TOGETHER'
},
{
'ID': 4795,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ROÑOSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'STINGY'
},
{
'ID': 4796,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TEMER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO FEAR'
},
{
'ID': 4797,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TIRAR (A LA BASURA)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO THROWAWAY'
},
{
'ID': 4798,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VALORAR,TASAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO APPRAISE'
},
{
'ID': 4799,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '12',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VIAJE DE IDA Y VUELTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ROUND TRIP'
},
{
'ID': 4800,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'A TODA COSTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ATALLCOSTS'
},
{
'ID': 4801,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'APARTE DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ASIDE FROM'
},
{
'ID': 4802,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'APLASTAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO CRUSH'
},
{
'ID': 4803,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CIGÜEÑA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'STORK'
},
{
'ID': 4804,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COMPARTIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SHARE'
},
{
'ID': 4805,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CUENTA CORRIENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CHECKING ACCOUNT'
},
{
'ID': 4806,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CUERDA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'STRING'
},
{
'ID': 4807,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DEBIDO A',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DUETO'
},
{
'ID': 4808,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESEQUILIBRIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IMBALANCE'
},
{
'ID': 4809,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESMAYAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO FAINT'
},
{
'ID': 4810,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DIRIGIR EL COTARRO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO RUN THE SHOW'
},
{
'ID': 4811,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HACER DAÑO,PERJUDICAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO HURT'
},
{
'ID': 4812,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'IMÁN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MAGNET'
},
{
'ID': 4813,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LOS JUEGOS OLÍMPICOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THE OLYMPIC GAMES'
},
{
'ID': 4814,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LOS RESTOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THE REMAINS'
},
{
'ID': 4815,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MARIONETA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PUPPET'
},
{
'ID': 4816,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MAYORISTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WHOLESALER'
},
{
'ID': 4817,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ORGULLO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PRIDE'
},
{
'ID': 4818,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PROBLEMAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TROUBLE'
},
{
'ID': 4819,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PUBLICAR,EMITIR,LANZAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ISSUE'
},
{
'ID': 4820,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'REPARAR,ARREGLAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO FIX'
},
{
'ID': 4821,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SABOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FLAVOR'
},
{
'ID': 4822,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SALIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO EXIT'
},
{
'ID': 4823,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TRIGO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WHEAT'
},
{
'ID': 4824,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '13',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VENTAJOSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ADVANTAGEOUS'
},
{
'ID': 4825,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': '¡YA ERA HORA!',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IT\'SABOUT TIME!'
},
{
'ID': 4826,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ADQUISICIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ACQUISITION'
},
{
'ID': 4827,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ADVERTENCIA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WARNING'
},
{
'ID': 4828,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ALTIBAJOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'UPS AND DOWNS'
},
{
'ID': 4829,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ATAR CABOS SUELTOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO TIE LOOSE ENDS'
},
{
'ID': 4830,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CULPAR,ECHAR LA CULPA A',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BLAME'
},
{
'ID': 4831,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EL ESPÍRITU SANTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THE HOLY SPIRIT'
},
{
'ID': 4832,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FORRARSE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO MAKE A KILLING'
},
{
'ID': 4833,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HACER USO DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO MAKE USE OF'
},
{
'ID': 4834,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INTENTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ATTEMPT'
},
{
'ID': 4835,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LIO,FOLLÓN,DESORDEN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MESS'
},
{
'ID': 4836,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MALA INTERPRETACIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MISINTERPRETATION'
},
{
'ID': 4837,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MEDICO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PHYSICIAN'
},
{
'ID': 4838,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MINAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO UNDERMINE'
},
{
'ID': 4839,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'OBLIGATORIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MANDATORY'
},
{
'ID': 4840,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PELIRROJO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RED-HEADED'
},
{
'ID': 4841,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PERICIA,HABILIDAD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EXPERTISE'
},
{
'ID': 4842,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PULSAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO PRESS'
},
{
'ID': 4843,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'REGATEAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BARGAIN'
},
{
'ID': 4844,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RESPONSABLE DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IN CHARGE OF'
},
{
'ID': 4845,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RUINAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RUINS'
},
{
'ID': 4846,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SUPONGO QUE SI',
        'RESPUESTA': 'I GUESS SO'
},
{
'ID': 4847,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TORTILLA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'OMELET'
},
{
'ID': 4848,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TOSER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO COUGH'
},
{
'ID': 4849,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '14',
        'PREGUNTA': 'UN POLÍTICO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'POLITICIAN'
},
{
'ID': 4850,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ADVERSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ADVERSE'
},
{
'ID': 4851,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AGARRAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO GRAB'
},
{
'ID': 4852,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BARBILLA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CHIN'
},
{
'ID': 4853,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BENEFICIO Y PERDIDA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PROFIT AND LOSS'
},
{
'ID': 4854,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONTRATACIÓN DE PERSONAL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RECRUITMENT'
},
{
'ID': 4855,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESALENTADOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DISCOURAGING'
},
{
'ID': 4856,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESANIMAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO DISCOURAGE'
},
{
'ID': 4857,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESHACERSE DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO GET RID OF'
},
{
'ID': 4858,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FÍSICA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PHYSICS'
},
{
'ID': 4859,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HIERRO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IRON'
},
{
'ID': 4860,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HORA PUNTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RUSH HOUR'
},
{
'ID': 4861,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HOY EN DIA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NOWADAYS'
},
{
'ID': 4862,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LANZAR UNA MONEDA AL AIRE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO TOSS A COIN'
},
{
'ID': 4863,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LEVANTAR (UNA SESIÓN)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ADJOURN'
},
{
'ID': 4864,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MIOPE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NEARSIGHTED'
},
{
'ID': 4865,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NOTIFICAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO NOTIFY'
},
{
'ID': 4866,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PAUTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PATTERN'
},
{
'ID': 4867,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'POLICÍA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'COP'
},
{
'ID': 4868,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'POR LO TANTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THEREFORE'
},
{
'ID': 4869,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RECURSOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RESOURCES'
},
{
'ID': 4870,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'REEMBOLSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'REFUND'
},
{
'ID': 4871,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RESCATAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TORESCUE'
},
{
'ID': 4872,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RESUMIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SUM UP'
},
{
'ID': 4873,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SUPER POBLADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'OVERPOPULATED'
},
{
'ID': 4874,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '15',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VERGONZOSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SHAMEFUL'
},
{
'ID': 4875,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'A PROPOSITO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ON PURPOSE'
},
{
'ID': 4876,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'APESTAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO STINK'
},
{
'ID': 4877,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CHISPA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SPARK'
},
{
'ID': 4878,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DAR EJEMPLO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SET AN EXAMPLE'
},
{
'ID': 4879,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DEPENDIENTE DE TIENDA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SALES CLERK'
},
{
'ID': 4880,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESATAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO UNTIE'
},
{
'ID': 4881,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESCARTAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO RULE OUT'
},
{
'ID': 4882,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DISPUESTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WILLING'
},
{
'ID': 4883,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENCABEZAMIENTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HEADING'
},
{
'ID': 4884,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESO ES,EN EFECTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THAT\'S RIGHT'
},
{
'ID': 4885,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FIABILIDAD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RELIABILITY'
},
{
'ID': 4886,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GUSANO,LOMBRIZ',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WORM'
},
{
'ID': 4887,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HACER PUENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO TAKE A LONG WEEKEND'
},
{
'ID': 4888,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HIPOTECA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MORTGAGE'
},
{
'ID': 4889,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LOCALIZAR,DETERMINAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO PINPOINT'
},
{
'ID': 4890,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MARFIL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IVORY'
},
{
'ID': 4891,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MASTICAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO CHEW'
},
{
'ID': 4892,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MERECEDOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DESERVING'
},
{
'ID': 4893,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PISTA DE ATERRIZAJE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RUNWAY'
},
{
'ID': 4894,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PORCENTAJE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PERCENTAGE'
},
{
'ID': 4895,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RELACIONADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RELATED'
},
{
'ID': 4896,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SOCIEDAD ANÓNIMA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CORPORATION'
},
{
'ID': 4897,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SOLAPARSE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO OVERLAP'
},
{
'ID': 4898,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TENTADOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TEMPTING'
},
{
'ID': 4899,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '16',
        'PREGUNTA': 'UBICACIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LOCATION'
},
{
'ID': 4900,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'A LARGO PLAZO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LONG-TERM'
},
{
'ID': 4901,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ADJUNTAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ENCLOSE'
},
{
'ID': 4902,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ASPIRADORA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'VACUUM CLEANER'
},
{
'ID': 4903,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ATRAPAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO TRAP'
},
{
'ID': 4904,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CACAHUETES',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PEANUTS'
},
{
'ID': 4905,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CEBADA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BARLEY'
},
{
'ID': 4906,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CISNE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SWAN'
},
{
'ID': 4907,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COMPAÑERO DE CLASE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CLASSMATE'
},
{
'ID': 4908,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DANÉS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DANISH'
},
{
'ID': 4909,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DAR CARRETE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SHOOT THE BULL'
},
{
'ID': 4910,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DERRETIR,FUNDIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO MELT'
},
{
'ID': 4911,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DETERMINAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO DETERMINE'
},
{
'ID': 4912,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESCUDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SHIELD'
},
{
'ID': 4913,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FIABILIDAD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RELIABILITY'
},
{
'ID': 4914,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FINGIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO PRETEND'
},
{
'ID': 4915,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'IMPRESIONANTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IMPRESSIVE'
},
{
'ID': 4916,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'JACTARSE,PRESUMIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BRAG'
},
{
'ID': 4917,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MEJORAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TOIMPROVE'
},
{
'ID': 4918,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MUY PEQUEÑO,DIMINUTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TINY'
},
{
'ID': 4919,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'OSTRA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'OYSTER'
},
{
'ID': 4920,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PROPONER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO PROPOSE'
},
{
'ID': 4921,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PROVISIONAL,TEMPORAL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TEMPORARY'
},
{
'ID': 4922,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SOCIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PARTNER'
},
{
'ID': 4923,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SUPONGO QUE SI',
        'RESPUESTA': 'I GUESS SO'
},
{
'ID': 4924,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '17',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TASA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RATE'
},
{
'ID': 4925,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': '¡VAYA FOLLÓN!',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WHAT A MESS!'
},
{
'ID': 4926,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': '¿QUE PASA?',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WHAT\'S THE MATTER?'
},
{
'ID': 4927,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'A PESAR DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IN SPITE OF'
},
{
'ID': 4928,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ATAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO TIE'
},
{
'ID': 4929,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ATÚN,BONITO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TUNA'
},
{
'ID': 4930,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COLUMNA VERTEBRAL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SPINE'
},
{
'ID': 4931,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CUMPLIDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'COMPLIMENT'
},
{
'ID': 4932,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DOMINIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MASTERY'
},
{
'ID': 4933,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EL ESTADO DEL BIENESTAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THE WELFARE STATE'
},
{
'ID': 4934,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EVOLUCIONAR,DESARROLLAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO EVOLVE'
},
{
'ID': 4935,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FECHA DE CADUCIDAD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EXPIRATION DATE'
},
{
'ID': 4936,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'IMPUESTO SOBRE LA RENTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'INCOME TAX'
},
{
'ID': 4937,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MALENTENDIDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MISUNDERSTANDING'
},
{
'ID': 4938,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MODIFICAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO REVISE'
},
{
'ID': 4939,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MOSTRADOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'COUNTER'
},
{
'ID': 4940,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MUESTRA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SAMPLE'
},
{
'ID': 4941,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PAPELEO BUROCRÁTICO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RED TAPE'
},
{
'ID': 4942,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RECREO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RECREATION'
},
{
'ID': 4943,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RESULTAR ÚTIL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO COME IN HANDY'
},
{
'ID': 4944,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RODEAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SURROUND'
},
{
'ID': 4945,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SOSPECHAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SUSPECT'
},
{
'ID': 4946,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TERRITORIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TERRITORY'
},
{
'ID': 4947,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TODO EL TIEMPO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ALL THE TIME'
},
{
'ID': 4948,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TOMA LAS COSAS CON FILOSOFÍA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TAKE IT EASY'
},
{
'ID': 4949,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '18',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VIRTUD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'VIRTUE'
},
{
'ID': 4950,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': '¡VAYA FOLLÓN!',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WHAT A MESS!'
},
{
'ID': 4951,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ALIVIADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RELIEVED'
},
{
'ID': 4952,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'APUNTAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO WRITE DOWN'
},
{
'ID': 4953,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ATROPELLAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO RUN OVER'
},
{
'ID': 4954,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BLANCO,DIANA,OBJETIVO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TARGET'
},
{
'ID': 4955,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CUMPLIR CON',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO COMPLY WITH'
},
{
'ID': 4956,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DEBILITAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO WEAKEN'
},
{
'ID': 4957,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESCANSAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO REST'
},
{
'ID': 4958,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DUDAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO DOUBT'
},
{
'ID': 4959,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EN UN APRIETO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IN ABIND'
},
{
'ID': 4960,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESCEPTICO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SKEPTIC'
},
{
'ID': 4961,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESPADA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SWORD'
},
{
'ID': 4962,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EXPERTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'KNOWLEDGEABLE'
},
{
'ID': 4963,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FLOJO,SUELTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LOOSE'
},
{
'ID': 4964,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HACER HUELGA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO STRIKE'
},
{
'ID': 4965,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HERIDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WOUNDED'
},
{
'ID': 4966,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HORMIGÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CONCRETE'
},
{
'ID': 4967,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ME TRAE SIN CUIDADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'I DON\'T CARE'
},
{
'ID': 4968,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'O SEA,EN OTRAS PALABRAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IN OTHER WORDS'
},
{
'ID': 4969,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PALA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SHOVEL'
},
{
'ID': 4970,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PEDIR PERDÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO APOLOGIZE'
},
{
'ID': 4971,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RECONOCIMIENTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RECOGNITION'
},
{
'ID': 4972,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SER GORDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BE OVERWEIGHT'
},
{
'ID': 4973,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SER OPTIMISTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BE OPTIMISTIC'
},
{
'ID': 4974,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '19',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SUPERAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO OVERCOME'
},
{
'ID': 4975,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'APROVECHAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO TAKE ADVANTAGE OF'
},
{
'ID': 4976,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ASUSTADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SCARED'
},
{
'ID': 4977,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BIEN INFORMADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WEL-INFORMED'
},
{
'ID': 4978,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONSIDERAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO DEEM'
},
{
'ID': 4979,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONTRASEÑA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PASSWORD'
},
{
'ID': 4980,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DAR POR SENTADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO TAKE FOR GRANTED'
},
{
'ID': 4981,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DE VEZ EN CUANDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EVERY NOW AND THEN'
},
{
'ID': 4982,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DIGNO DE CONFIANZA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TRUSTWORTHY'
},
{
'ID': 4983,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DINERO EN METÁLICO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CASH'
},
{
'ID': 4984,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ECHAR DE MENOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO MISS'
},
{
'ID': 4985,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FUERZA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'STRENGTH'
},
{
'ID': 4986,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HIPOTECA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MORTGAGE'
},
{
'ID': 4987,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'IMPUESTOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TAXES'
},
{
'ID': 4988,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MANTEL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TABLECLOTH'
},
{
'ID': 4989,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MUTUO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MUTUAL'
},
{
'ID': 4990,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PARECERSE A',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO LOOK LIKE'
},
{
'ID': 4991,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PROBABILIDAD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LIKELIHOOD'
},
{
'ID': 4992,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RASCAR,ARAÑAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SCRATCH'
},
{
'ID': 4993,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RECHAZAR,BAJAR (VOLUMEN)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO TURN DOWN'
},
{
'ID': 4994,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RODILLA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'KNEE'
},
{
'ID': 4995,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SUBVENCIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SUBSIDY'
},
{
'ID': 4996,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TRABAJO EN EQUIPO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TEAMWORK'
},
{
'ID': 4997,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'UN CONOCIDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AN ACQUAINTANCE'
},
{
'ID': 4998,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'UN DÍA SI Y OTRO NO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EVERY OTHER DAY'
},
{
'ID': 4999,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '20',
        'PREGUNTA': 'UN BUSCAPLEITOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'A TROUBLEMAKER'
},
{
'ID': 5000,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AFIRMAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO STATE'
},
{
'ID': 5001,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BURLARSE DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO MAKE FUN OF'
},
{
'ID': 5002,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CICATRIZ',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SCAR'
},
{
'ID': 5003,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONSUMIDOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CONSUMER'
},
{
'ID': 5004,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CUENTA DE GASTOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EXPENSE ACCOUNT'
},
{
'ID': 5005,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DISCUTIR (ACALORADAMENTE)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ARGÜE'
},
{
'ID': 5006,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EGOÍSTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SELFISH'
},
{
'ID': 5007,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESMERO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THOROUGHNESS'
},
{
'ID': 5008,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESPESURA,GROSOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THICKNESS'
},
{
'ID': 5009,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FALLECER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO PASS AWAY'
},
{
'ID': 5010,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FARMACÉUTICO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PHARMACIST'
},
{
'ID': 5011,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FORMAR,ENTRENAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO TRAIN'
},
{
'ID': 5012,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INTRANQUILO,PREOCUPADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'UNEASY'
},
{
'ID': 5013,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MATAR TIEMPO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO KILL TIME'
},
{
'ID': 5014,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MIENTRAS TANTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IN THE MEANTIME'
},
{
'ID': 5015,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MILAGRO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MIRACLE'
},
{
'ID': 5016,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NUMEROSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NUMEROUS'
},
{
'ID': 5017,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PAISAJE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LANDSCAPE'
},
{
'ID': 5018,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PAYASO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CLOWN'
},
{
'ID': 5019,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PERMITIR,POSIBILITAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ENABLE'
},
{
'ID': 5020,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'REUNIR LAS CONDICIONES',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO QUALIFY'
},
{
'ID': 5021,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SACERDOTE,CURA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PRIEST'
},
{
'ID': 5022,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SEGUIR EN CONTACTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO STAY IN TOUCH'
},
{
'ID': 5023,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SOBERBIO (EXCELENTE)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SUPERB'
},
{
'ID': 5024,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '21',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VOLVERSE LOCO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO GO CRAZY'
},
{
'ID': 5025,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AGUANTAR EL RITMO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO STAND THE PACE'
},
{
'ID': 5026,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ALMENDRA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ALMOND'
},
{
'ID': 5027,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'APRETADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TIGHT'
},
{
'ID': 5028,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'APROBAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO APPROVE'
},
{
'ID': 5029,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AVERIGUAR,ENTERARSE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO FIND OUT'
},
{
'ID': 5030,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONFIAR EN,FIARSE DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO TRUST'
},
{
'ID': 5031,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CHANTAJEAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BLACKMAIL'
},
{
'ID': 5032,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CHISMORREO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GOSSIP'
},
{
'ID': 5033,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DE MENTE AMPLIA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BROAD-MINDED'
},
{
'ID': 5034,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DURAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO LAST'
},
{
'ID': 5035,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GRATIFICANTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GRATIFYING'
},
{
'ID': 5036,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GUARDA ESPALDAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BODYGUARD'
},
{
'ID': 5037,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MENDIGAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BEG'
},
{
'ID': 5038,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NEGARSE A',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO REFUSE'
},
{
'ID': 5039,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'OBSOLETO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'OBSOLETE'
},
{
'ID': 5040,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PASAR LA PELOTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO PASS THE BUCK'
},
{
'ID': 5041,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'POSTAL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'POSTCARD'
},
{
'ID': 5042,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RADIOGRAFÍA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'X-RAY'
},
{
'ID': 5043,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RECTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'STRAIGHT'
},
{
'ID': 5044,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'REPUGNANTE,NAUSEABUNDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SICKENING'
},
{
'ID': 5045,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'REPUTACIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'REPUTATION'
},
{
'ID': 5046,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RIZAR EL RIZO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SPLIT HAIRS'
},
{
'ID': 5047,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SUSPIRAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SIGH'
},
{
'ID': 5048,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TOALLA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TOWEL'
},
{
'ID': 5049,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '22',
        'PREGUNTA': 'UN BOCAZAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'A LOUDMOUTH'
},
{
'ID': 5050,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ACEITE,PETRÓLEO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'OIL'
},
{
'ID': 5051,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ACOMODADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AFFLUENT'
},
{
'ID': 5052,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ANIMAR,ALENTAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ENCOURAGE'
},
{
'ID': 5053,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ARAÑA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SPIDER'
},
{
'ID': 5054,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ATAR CABOS SUELTOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO TIE LOOSE ENDS'
},
{
'ID': 5055,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CUANTO ANTES MEJOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THE SOONER THE BETTER'
},
{
'ID': 5056,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DE ÉXITO,EXITOSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SUCCESSFUL'
},
{
'ID': 5057,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GARGANTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THROAT'
},
{
'ID': 5058,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HASTA CIERTO PUNTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO A CERTAIN EXTENT'
},
{
'ID': 5059,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INUNDAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO FLOOD'
},
{
'ID': 5060,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INVESTIGAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO LOOK INTO'
},
{
'ID': 5061,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'JUBILARSE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO RETIRE'
},
{
'ID': 5062,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LA HUMANIDAD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MANKIND'
},
{
'ID': 5063,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LA POLÍTICA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'POLITICS'
},
{
'ID': 5064,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MANCHA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'STAIN'
},
{
'ID': 5065,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NO OBSTANTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NEVERTHELESS'
},
{
'ID': 5066,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ODIAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO DESPISE'
},
{
'ID': 5067,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PARTIR,SALIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO DEPART'
},
{
'ID': 5068,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PASAR POR ALTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO OVERLOOK'
},
{
'ID': 5069,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PLEITO,DEMANDA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LAWSUIT'
},
{
'ID': 5070,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RESOLVER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO WORK OUT'
},
{
'ID': 5071,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RIESGO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RISK'
},
{
'ID': 5072,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SENSIBLE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SENSITIVE'
},
{
'ID': 5073,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SIESTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NAP'
},
{
'ID': 5074,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '23',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ÚTIL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'USEFUL'
},
{
'ID': 5075,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ACEITUNA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'OLIVE'
},
{
'ID': 5076,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ACOMODADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WELL-OFF'
},
{
'ID': 5077,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ARCO IRIS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RAINBOW'
},
{
'ID': 5078,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AVARO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GREEDY'
},
{
'ID': 5079,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BENEFICIOSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BENEFICIAL'
},
{
'ID': 5080,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CEBOLLA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ONION'
},
{
'ID': 5081,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COMPARACIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'COMPARISON'
},
{
'ID': 5082,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESORDENADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MESSY'
},
{
'ID': 5083,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ECHAR A PATADAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO KICK OUT'
},
{
'ID': 5084,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EFICACIA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EFFECTIVENESS'
},
{
'ID': 5085,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EN DECLIVE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IN DECLINE'
},
{
'ID': 5086,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESCEPTICO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SKEPTICAL'
},
{
'ID': 5087,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EVOLUCIONAR,DESARROLLAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO EVOLVE'
},
{
'ID': 5088,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GUARDAR UN SECRETO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO KEEP A SECRET'
},
{
'ID': 5089,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INCAPACITAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO INCAPACITATE'
},
{
'ID': 5090,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MALTRATAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO MISTREAT'
},
{
'ID': 5091,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MANDARINA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TANGERINE'
},
{
'ID': 5092,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MAS VALE TARDE QUE NUNCA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BETTER LATE THAN NEVER'
},
{
'ID': 5093,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MEZCLA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BLEND'
},
{
'ID': 5094,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PAÑUELO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HANDKERCHIEF'
},
{
'ID': 5095,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RECUPERARSE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO RECOVER'
},
{
'ID': 5096,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RETRATO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PORTRAIT'
},
{
'ID': 5097,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SALVAJE,SILVESTRE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WILD'
},
{
'ID': 5098,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TERCO,TESTARUDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'STUBBORN'
},
{
'ID': 5099,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '24',
        'PREGUNTA': 'UN TIMO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'A RIP-OFF'
},
{
'ID': 5100,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ABOFETEAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SLAP'
},
{
'ID': 5101,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AGRADECER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO APPRECIATE'
},
{
'ID': 5102,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ANDAR CON DILACIONES,APLAZAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO PROCRASTINATE'
},
{
'ID': 5103,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COBARDE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'COWARD'
},
{
'ID': 5104,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONEJILLO DE INDIAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GUINEA PIG'
},
{
'ID': 5105,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CHOQUE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CRASH'
},
{
'ID': 5106,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DARSE CUENTA DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO REALIZE'
},
{
'ID': 5107,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DIMITIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO RESIGN'
},
{
'ID': 5108,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DOLOR DE GARGANTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SORE THROAT'
},
{
'ID': 5109,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DURO,DIFÍCIL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TOUGH'
},
{
'ID': 5110,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENTIERRO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BURIAL'
},
{
'ID': 5111,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ÉXITO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SUCCESS'
},
{
'ID': 5112,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FABULOSO,GENIAL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TERRIFIC'
},
{
'ID': 5113,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FIEL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FAITHFUL'
},
{
'ID': 5114,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FLECHA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ARROW'
},
{
'ID': 5115,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HILO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THREAD'
},
{
'ID': 5116,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LANGOSTA (DE MAR)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LOBSTER'
},
{
'ID': 5117,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ORDEN DE COMPRA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PURCHASE ORDER'
},
{
'ID': 5118,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RASCACIELOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SKYSCRAPER'
},
{
'ID': 5119,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RECIBO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RECEIPT'
},
{
'ID': 5120,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RENOVACIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RENEWAL'
},
{
'ID': 5121,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RENTABLE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PROFITABLE'
},
{
'ID': 5122,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SEGURO DE SI MISMO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SELF-CONFIDENT'
},
{
'ID': 5123,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SEMEJANTES',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PEERS'
},
{
'ID': 5124,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '25',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SOLOMILLO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FILET MIGNON'
},
{
'ID': 5125,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'APROPIADAMENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'APPROPRIATELY'
},
{
'ID': 5126,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CEDER/RENDIRSE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO GIVE IN'
},
{
'ID': 5127,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COMPARACIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'COMPARISON'
},
{
'ID': 5128,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CUESTIONARIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'QUESTIONNAIRE'
},
{
'ID': 5129,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DARSE CUENTA DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO REALIZE'
},
{
'ID': 5130,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DIGNO DE CONFIANZA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TRUSTWORTHY'
},
{
'ID': 5131,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EN MEDIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IN THE WAY'
},
{
'ID': 5132,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESTADO DE ANIMO,HUMOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MOOD'
},
{
'ID': 5133,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'IMPROBABLE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'UNLIKELY'
},
{
'ID': 5134,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INESPERADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'UNEXPECTED'
},
{
'ID': 5135,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LOS AÑOS CUARENTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THE FORTIES'
},
{
'ID': 5136,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MOLESTAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BOTHER'
},
{
'ID': 5137,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PERDERSE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO GET LOST'
},
{
'ID': 5138,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PLAN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SCHEME'
},
{
'ID': 5139,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'POR LO TANTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THEREFORE'
},
{
'ID': 5140,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'POSPONER,APLAZAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO POSTPONE'
},
{
'ID': 5141,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PROMOCIONAR,PROMOVER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO PROMOTE'
},
{
'ID': 5142,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RECORDAR (RECORDARLE A OTRO)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO REMIND'
},
{
'ID': 5143,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RETAR,DESAFIAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO CHALLENGE'
},
{
'ID': 5144,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RONCAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SNORE'
},
{
'ID': 5145,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SONROJARSE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BLUSH'
},
{
'ID': 5146,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TAMBOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DRUM'
},
{
'ID': 5147,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TONTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DUMB'
},
{
'ID': 5148,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TRABALENGUAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TONGUE TWISTER'
},
{
'ID': 5149,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '26',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VIUDA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WIDOW'
},
{
'ID': 5150,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ACELERAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SPEED UP'
},
{
'ID': 5151,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ACTUALIZAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO UPDATE'
},
{
'ID': 5152,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ANTICIPAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ANTICIPATE'
},
{
'ID': 5153,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ARRIESGAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO RISK'
},
{
'ID': 5154,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CADUCAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO EXPIRE'
},
{
'ID': 5155,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CALMARSE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO CALM DOWN'
},
{
'ID': 5156,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CALLEJÓN SIN SALIDA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DEAD END'
},
{
'ID': 5157,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CLASIFICAR,VALORAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO RATE'
},
{
'ID': 5158,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COLEGA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'COLLEAGUE'
},
{
'ID': 5159,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESAMPARADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HELPLESS'
},
{
'ID': 5160,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EN PRIVADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IN PRIVATE'
},
{
'ID': 5161,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENCANTADOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DELIGHTFUL'
},
{
'ID': 5162,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EXTROVERTIDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'OUTGOING'
},
{
'ID': 5163,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FABRICACIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MANUFACTURING'
},
{
'ID': 5164,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PARIENTES,FAMILIARES',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RELATIVES'
},
{
'ID': 5165,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PASILLO (AVIÓN,CINE,ETC.)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AISLE'
},
{
'ID': 5166,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'POR LO VISTO,AL PARECER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'APPARENTLY'
},
{
'ID': 5167,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RASGAR,ROMPER (TELA,PAPEL)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO TEAR'
},
{
'ID': 5168,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RECETA (DE COCINA)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RECIPE'
},
{
'ID': 5169,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RETO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CHALLENGE'
},
{
'ID': 5170,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RIZAR EL RIZO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SPLIT HAIRS'
},
{
'ID': 5171,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SILLA DE RUEDAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WHEELCHAIR'
},
{
'ID': 5172,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TALÓN DE AQUILES',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ACHILLES HEEL'
},
{
'ID': 5173,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GOTEAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO DRIP'
},
{
'ID': 5174,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '27',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NEGOCIABLE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NEGOTIABLE'
},
{
'ID': 5175,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'iQUIEN SABE!',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WHO KNOWS!'
},
{
'ID': 5176,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ADQUIRIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ACQUIRE'
},
{
'ID': 5177,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ARTIFICIAL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ARTIFICIAL'
},
{
'ID': 5178,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AUNQUE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ALTHOUGH'
},
{
'ID': 5179,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONSTANTE Y EQUILIBRADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'STEADY'
},
{
'ID': 5180,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONTAR CON',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO COUNT ON'
},
{
'ID': 5181,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EL COSTE DE LA VIDA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THE COST OF LIVING'
},
{
'ID': 5182,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ELOGIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PRAISE'
},
{
'ID': 5183,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENFERMEDAD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DISEASE'
},
{
'ID': 5184,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FUERA DE CONTROL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'OUT OF CONTROL'
},
{
'ID': 5185,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INGENIOSO,QUE TIENE RECURSOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RESOURCEFUL'
},
{
'ID': 5186,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INOFENSIVO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HARMLESS'
},
{
'ID': 5187,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INTIMIDAD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PRIVACY'
},
{
'ID': 5188,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INUNDACIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FLOOD'
},
{
'ID': 5189,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NOCHE VIEJA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NEW YEAR\'S EVE'
},
{
'ID': 5190,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'OMITIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO LEAVE OUT'
},
{
'ID': 5191,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PASTA DE DIENTES',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TOOTH PASTE'
},
{
'ID': 5192,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PERMISIVO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LENIENT'
},
{
'ID': 5193,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PRINCIPALMENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MAINLY'
},
{
'ID': 5194,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'REFRESCANTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'REFRESHING'
},
{
'ID': 5195,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SEGUIR EN CONTACTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO STAY IN TOUCH'
},
{
'ID': 5196,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TORMENTA DE NIEVE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SNOWSTORM'
},
{
'ID': 5197,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TRANQUILIZADOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'REASSURING'
},
{
'ID': 5198,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TRANSMITIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO CONVEY'
},
{
'ID': 5199,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '28',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VENIRSE ABAJO (UN PLAN)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO FALL THROUGH'
},
{
'ID': 5200,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ACLARAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO CLEAR UP'
},
{
'ID': 5201,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ACONSEJAR,ASESORAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ADVISE'
},
{
'ID': 5202,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ARCHIVAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO FILE'
},
{
'ID': 5203,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ASFALTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ASPHALT'
},
{
'ID': 5204,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CESAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO CEASE'
},
{
'ID': 5205,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EN CUALQUIER CASO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'IN ANY CASE'
},
{
'ID': 5206,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EN VOZ ALTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ALOUD'
},
{
'ID': 5207,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FECHA TOPE,PLAZO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DEADLINE'
},
{
'ID': 5208,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HACER TRAMPA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO CHEAT'
},
{
'ID': 5209,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INGRESOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'REVENUE'
},
{
'ID': 5210,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LA BOLSA (DE VALORES)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THE STOCK MARKET'
},
{
'ID': 5211,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MATERIAS PRIMAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RAW MATERIALS'
},
{
'ID': 5212,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'OBRA MAESTRA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MASTERPIECE'
},
{
'ID': 5213,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PAPELERA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WASTE BASKET'
},
{
'ID': 5214,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PARA SIEMPRE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FOR GOOD'
},
{
'ID': 5215,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'POR SUPUESTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'OF COURSE'
},
{
'ID': 5216,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RECURRIR A ENCHUFES',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO PULL STRINGS'
},
{
'ID': 5217,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SABROSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TASTY'
},
{
'ID': 5218,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SORDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DEAF'
},
{
'ID': 5219,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SUDAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SWEAT'
},
{
'ID': 5220,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TARDE O TEMPRANO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SOONER OR LATER'
},
{
'ID': 5221,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TENER ÉXITO,TRIUNFAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SUCCEED'
},
{
'ID': 5222,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TRIBU',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TRIBE'
},
{
'ID': 5223,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VALORACIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'APPRAISAL'
},
{
'ID': 5224,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '29',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VALORAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ASSESS'
},
{
'ID': 5225,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AJETREADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HECTIC'
},
{
'ID': 5226,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ALENTADOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ENCOURAGING'
},
{
'ID': 5227,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'APUESTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BET'
},
{
'ID': 5228,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CARACTERÍSTICAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FEATURES'
},
{
'ID': 5229,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CIMIENTOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FOUNDATION'
},
{
'ID': 5230,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DE VEZ EN CUANDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EVERY ONCE IN AWHILE'
},
{
'ID': 5231,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EL PARO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'UNEMPLOYMENT'
},
{
'ID': 5232,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENCUESTA,SONDEO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SURVEY'
},
{
'ID': 5233,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENVOLVER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO WRAP'
},
{
'ID': 5234,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FRACASO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FAILURE'
},
{
'ID': 5235,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GLOBAL,TOTAL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'OVERALL'
},
{
'ID': 5236,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INSATISFECHO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DISSATISFIED'
},
{
'ID': 5237,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'JUSTIFICAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO JUSTIFY'
},
{
'ID': 5238,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'JUZGAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO JUDGE'
},
{
'ID': 5239,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LUZ SOLAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SUNLIGHT'
},
{
'ID': 5240,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NOVELA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NOVEL'
},
{
'ID': 5241,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PRODUCCIÓN,RENDIMIENTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'OUTPUT'
},
{
'ID': 5242,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'QUE YO SEPA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AS FAR AS I KNOW'
},
{
'ID': 5243,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'REANUDAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO RESUME'
},
{
'ID': 5244,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RESOLVER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SORT OUT'
},
{
'ID': 5245,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SATISFACER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SATISFY'
},
{
'ID': 5246,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TEÓRICO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THEORETICAL'
},
{
'ID': 5247,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TRABAJO RETRASADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ACUMULADO BACKLOG'
},
{
'ID': 5248,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'UMBRAL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THRESHOLD'
},
{
'ID': 5249,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '30',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VISION DE FUTURO,PREVISIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FORESIGHT'
},
{
'ID': 5250,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BATA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ROBE'
},
{
'ID': 5251,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BOTAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BOUNCE'
},
{
'ID': 5252,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CON TALENTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TALENTED'
},
{
'ID': 5253,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONTROL REMOTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'REMOTE CONTROL'
},
{
'ID': 5254,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONVERTIRSE EN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO TURN INTO'
},
{
'ID': 5255,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ALENTADOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ENCOURAGING'
},
{
'ID': 5256,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CRUCIGRAMA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CROSSWORD PUZZLE'
},
{
'ID': 5257,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CUESTA ABAJO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DOWNHILL'
},
{
'ID': 5258,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ECHAR LA SIESTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO TAKE A NAP'
},
{
'ID': 5259,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EN EL MEJOR DE LOS CASOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AT BEST'
},
{
'ID': 5260,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'IMPROVISAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO IMPROVISE'
},
{
'ID': 5261,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LLEGAR A DOMINAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO MASTER'
},
{
'ID': 5262,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'OCULTAR,ESCONDER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO HIDE'
},
{
'ID': 5263,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PERFIL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PROFILE'
},
{
'ID': 5264,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PISTA,INDICIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CLUE'
},
{
'ID': 5265,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PRECEDER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO PRECEDE'
},
{
'ID': 5266,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PROXIMIDAD',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PROXIMITY'
},
{
'ID': 5267,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PUEBLO NATAL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HOME TOWN'
},
{
'ID': 5268,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RECORTAR,REDUCIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO CUT BACK'
},
{
'ID': 5269,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'REFLEXIONAR SOBRE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO THINK OVER'
},
{
'ID': 5270,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'REHÉN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HOSTAGE'
},
{
'ID': 5271,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SER ABURRIDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BE BORING'
},
{
'ID': 5272,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SUMAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ADD UP'
},
{
'ID': 5273,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TRATAR CON',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO DEAL WITH'
},
{
'ID': 5274,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '31',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VALIOSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'VALUABLE'
},
{
'ID': 5275,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'A LARGO PLAZO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LONG-RANGE'
},
{
'ID': 5276,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ABURRIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BORE'
},
{
'ID': 5277,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ALTO EL FUEGO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CEASE-FIRE'
},
{
'ID': 5278,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BASADO EN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BASED ON'
},
{
'ID': 5279,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CARECER DE,FALTAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO LACK'
},
{
'ID': 5280,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CARNE DE VACUNO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'BEEF'
},
{
'ID': 5281,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CILCULO VICIOSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'VICIOUS CIRCLE'
},
{
'ID': 5282,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COMPAÑERO DE EQUIPO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TEAMMATE'
},
{
'ID': 5283,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CRECIMIENTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GROWTH'
},
{
'ID': 5284,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DOLOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PAIN'
},
{
'ID': 5285,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENORME',
        'RESPUESTA': 'HUGE'
},
{
'ID': 5286,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EXTENDERSE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SPREAD'
},
{
'ID': 5287,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FABULOSO,GENIAL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TERRIFIC'
},
{
'ID': 5288,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GRAPADORA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'STAPLER'
},
{
'ID': 5289,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GRÚA (PARA REMOLCAR)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TOW TRUCK'
},
{
'ID': 5290,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'IMPROVISAR (HABLANDO)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO AD LIB'
},
{
'ID': 5291,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LA POLÍTICA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'POLITICS'
},
{
'ID': 5292,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MANTENER,APOYAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SUPPORT'
},
{
'ID': 5293,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NO OBSTANTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NEVERTHELESS'
},
{
'ID': 5294,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PAPEL DE BORRADOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SCRATCH PAPER'
},
{
'ID': 5295,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PROVISIONES',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SUPPLIES'
},
{
'ID': 5296,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'REALISTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'REALISTIC'
},
{
'ID': 5297,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SANO Y SALVO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SAFE AND SOUND'
},
{
'ID': 5298,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TEÑIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO DYE'
},
{
'ID': 5299,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '32',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TERREMOTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EARTHQUAKE'
},
{
'ID': 5300,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ACENTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ACCENT'
},
{
'ID': 5301,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AMENAZAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO THREATEN'
},
{
'ID': 5302,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BASURA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TRASH'
},
{
'ID': 5303,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BORDE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EDGE'
},
{
'ID': 5304,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BUSCAR (COMO CONSULTA)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO LOOK UP'
},
{
'ID': 5305,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONVENCER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO CONVINCE'
},
{
'ID': 5306,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DAR UN PASEO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO GO FOR A WALK'
},
{
'ID': 5307,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EL CANAL DE LA MANCHA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THE ENGLISH CHANNEL'
},
{
'ID': 5308,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESTAR DE ACUERDO CON',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO AGREE WITH'
},
{
'ID': 5309,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LOS TITULARES (PRENSA)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THE HEADLINES'
},
{
'ID': 5310,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LUJO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LUXURY'
},
{
'ID': 5311,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MAÑOSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SKILLFUL'
},
{
'ID': 5312,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MARCHA ATRÁS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'REVERSE'
},
{
'ID': 5313,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MÁXIMO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MAXIMUM'
},
{
'ID': 5314,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NEGOCIAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO NEGOTIATE'
},
{
'ID': 5315,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'NOVIAZGO FORMAL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ENGAGEMENT'
},
{
'ID': 5316,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PELIGRO,ESCOLLO,TRAMPA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PITFALL'
},
{
'ID': 5317,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PERSEVERANCIA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PERSEVERANCE'
},
{
'ID': 5318,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RECORTE (PRESUPUESTARIO)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CUTBACK'
},
{
'ID': 5319,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SALIR POR LA CULATA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BACKFIRE'
},
{
'ID': 5320,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SERVILLETA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NAPKIN'
},
{
'ID': 5321,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SIN IMPORTANCIA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MEANINGLESS'
},
{
'ID': 5322,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TUMBARSE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO LIE DOWN'
},
{
'ID': 5323,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ÚNICO EN SU GENERO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'UNIQUE'
},
{
'ID': 5324,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '33',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VOLUNTARIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'VOLUNTEER'
},
{
'ID': 5325,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ANTES DE,ANTERIOR A',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PRIOR TO'
},
{
'ID': 5326,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BRECHA,LAGUNA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GAP'
},
{
'ID': 5327,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CURRICULUM VITAE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RESUME'
},
{
'ID': 5328,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CHILLAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO SCREAM'
},
{
'ID': 5329,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DEMOSTRAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO PROVE'
},
{
'ID': 5330,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DERROTAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO DEFEAT'
},
{
'ID': 5331,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DIRIGIR,APAÑARE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO MANAGE'
},
{
'ID': 5332,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EN ULTRAMAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'OVERSEAS'
},
{
'ID': 5333,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INGENIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'INGENUITY'
},
{
'ID': 5334,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LEAL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LOYAL'
},
{
'ID': 5335,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LEMA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MOTTO'
},
{
'ID': 5336,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PALMERA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PALM TREE'
},
{
'ID': 5337,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PESADILLA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NIGHTMARE'
},
{
'ID': 5338,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PONERSE EN CONTACTO CON',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO CONTACT'
},
{
'ID': 5339,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'QUEDARSE DORMIDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO FALL ASLEEP'
},
{
'ID': 5340,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'QUEJA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'COMPLAINT'
},
{
'ID': 5341,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RANURA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SLOT'
},
{
'ID': 5342,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RECONSIDERAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO RECONSIDER'
},
{
'ID': 5343,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'REMOLQUE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TRAILER'
},
{
'ID': 5344,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RENTABLE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PROFITABLE'
},
{
'ID': 5345,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RESERVADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RESERVED'
},
{
'ID': 5346,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RESPONSABLE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ACCOUNTABLE'
},
{
'ID': 5347,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SUJETAR,SOSTENER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO HOLD'
},
{
'ID': 5348,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TALLO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'STEM'
},
{
'ID': 5349,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '34',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TRAMPOSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CHEATER'
},
{
'ID': 5350,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ADVERTIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO WARN'
},
{
'ID': 5351,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ASEGURAR VERIFICANDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO CHECK ON'
},
{
'ID': 5352,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COBRE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'COPPER'
},
{
'ID': 5353,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COLCHÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MATTRESS'
},
{
'ID': 5354,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'COMPASIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SYMPATHY'
},
{
'ID': 5355,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONSIDERAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO REGARD'
},
{
'ID': 5356,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CUESTA ARRIBA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'UPHILL'
},
{
'ID': 5357,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DEDO PULGAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THUMB'
},
{
'ID': 5358,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DESVENTAJA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'DISADVANTAGE'
},
{
'ID': 5359,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EMBARAZADA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PREGNANT'
},
{
'ID': 5360,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENSAYAR (UN EVENTO)',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO REHEARSE'
},
{
'ID': 5361,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FONTANERÍA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PLUMBING'
},
{
'ID': 5362,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GAVIOTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SEAGULL'
},
{
'ID': 5363,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'IMPLICACIÓN,INVOLUCRARON',
        'RESPUESTA': 'INVOLVEMENT'
},
{
'ID': 5364,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INTRODUCIR POR FASES',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO PHASE IN'
},
{
'ID': 5365,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LA VIA LÁCTEA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THE MILKY WAY'
},
{
'ID': 5366,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LOCO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'INSANE'
},
{
'ID': 5367,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MERECER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO DESERVE'
},
{
'ID': 5368,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MOLESTAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ANNOY'
},
{
'ID': 5369,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MOLESTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ANNOYING'
},
{
'ID': 5370,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ORGULLOSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PROUD'
},
{
'ID': 5371,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RAÍZ',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ROOT'
},
{
'ID': 5372,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SILBATO,PITO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WHISTLE'
},
{
'ID': 5373,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'TONTERÍAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NONSENSE'
},
{
'ID': 5374,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '35',
        'PREGUNTA': 'UNA AMPLIA GAMA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AWIDE RANGE'
},
{
'ID': 5375,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'A EXPENSAS DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AT THE EXPENSE OF'
},
{
'ID': 5376,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ACORDARSE DE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO RECALL'
},
{
'ID': 5377,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AGOTADO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EXHAUSTED'
},
{
'ID': 5378,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'AVANCE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ADVANCEMENT'
},
{
'ID': 5379,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CALUMNIA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SLANDER'
},
{
'ID': 5380,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONTENER',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO CONTAIN'
},
{
'ID': 5381,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONTRIBUIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO CONTRIBUTE'
},
{
'ID': 5382,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONTROVERSIA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CONTROVERSY'
},
{
'ID': 5383,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CONVINCENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CONVINCING'
},
{
'ID': 5384,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CORDILLERA,SIERRA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MOUNTAIN RANGE'
},
{
'ID': 5385,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DECEPCIONAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO LET DOWN'
},
{
'ID': 5386,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'DECIDIDO,RESUELTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RESOLUTE'
},
{
'ID': 5387,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ELECCIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CHOICE'
},
{
'ID': 5388,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EN REBAJAS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ON SALE'
},
{
'ID': 5389,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENSEGUIDA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RIGHT AWAY'
},
{
'ID': 5390,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESTAR EN DESACUERDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO DISAGREE'
},
{
'ID': 5391,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'METICULOSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'METICULOUS'
},
{
'ID': 5392,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ORIENTAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO ORIENT'
},
{
'ID': 5393,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PEDIR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO REQUEST'
},
{
'ID': 5394,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PERFIL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PROFILE'
},
{
'ID': 5395,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PRESIÓN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PRESSURE'
},
{
'ID': 5396,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PULPO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'OCTOPUS'
},
{
'ID': 5397,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'RESERVAS,RECELOS',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MISGIVINGS'
},
{
'ID': 5398,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'REVENTAR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TO BURST'
},
{
'ID': 5399,
        'TIPO': 'VOCABULARIO',
        'NIVEL': 6,
        'LISTA': '36',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SENDA,SENDERO,VEREDA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PATH'
},
{
'ID': 5400,
        'TIPO': 'FELICITACIONES',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': 'FELICITACIONES',
        'PREGUNTA': 'VALE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'OK'
},
{
'ID': 5401,
        'TIPO': 'FELICITACIONES',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': 'FELICITACIONES',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BIEN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GOOD'
},
{
'ID': 5402,
        'TIPO': 'FELICITACIONES',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': 'FELICITACIONES',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SI',
        'RESPUESTA': 'YES'
},
{
'ID': 5403,
        'TIPO': 'FELICITACIONES',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': 'FELICITACIONES',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BIEN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NICE'
},
{
'ID': 5404,
        'TIPO': 'FELICITACIONES',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': 'FELICITACIONES',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MUY BIEN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GREAT'
},
{
'ID': 5406,
        'TIPO': 'FELICITACIONES',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': 'FELICITACIONES',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GENIAL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SUPER'
},
{
'ID': 5407,
        'TIPO': 'FELICITACIONES',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': 'FELICITACIONES',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BIEN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FINE'
},
{
'ID': 5408,
        'TIPO': 'FELICITACIONES',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': 'FELICITACIONES',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BIEN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'RIGHT'
},
{
'ID': 5409,
        'TIPO': 'FELICITACIONES',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': 'FELICITACIONES',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MARAVILLOSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WONDERFUL'
},
{
'ID': 5410,
        'TIPO': 'FELICITACIONES',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': 'FELICITACIONES',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BUEN TRABAJO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GOOD WORK'
},
{
'ID': 5411,
        'TIPO': 'FELICITACIONES',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': 'FELICITACIONES',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BIEN HECHO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WELL DONE'
},
{
'ID': 5412,
        'TIPO': 'FELICITACIONES',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': 'FELICITACIONES',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MUY BIEN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'ALL RIGHT'
},
{
'ID': 5413,
        'TIPO': 'FELICITACIONES',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': 'FELICITACIONES',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESO ES',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THAT\'S RIGHT'
},
{
'ID': 5414,
        'TIPO': 'FELICITACIONES',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': 'FELICITACIONES',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ACERTASTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'YOU\'RE RIGHT'
},
{
'ID': 5415,
        'TIPO': 'FELICITACIONES',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': 'FELICITACIONES',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PERFECTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THAT\'S GREAT'
},
{
'ID': 5416,
        'TIPO': 'FELICITACIONES',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': 'FELICITACIONES',
        'PREGUNTA': 'PERFECTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PERFECT'
},
{
'ID': 5417,
        'TIPO': 'FELICITACIONES',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': 'FELICITACIONES',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EXTRAORDINARIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FLAWLESS'
},
{
'ID': 5418,
        'TIPO': 'FELICITACIONES',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': 'FELICITACIONES',
        'PREGUNTA': 'EXCELENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'EXCELLENT'
},
{
'ID': 5419,
        'TIPO': 'FELICITACIONES',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': 'FELICITACIONES',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ASOMBROSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'AMAZING'
},
{
'ID': 5420,
        'TIPO': 'FELICITACIONES',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': 'FELICITACIONES',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESO ES',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THAT\'S IT'
},
{
'ID': 5421,
        'TIPO': 'FELICITACIONES',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': 'FELICITACIONES',
        'PREGUNTA': 'BASTANTE BIEN',
        'RESPUESTA': 'PRETTY GOOD'
},
{
'ID': 5422,
        'TIPO': 'FELICITACIONES',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': 'FELICITACIONES',
        'PREGUNTA': 'HALA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'WOW'
},
{
'ID': 5423,
        'TIPO': 'FELICITACIONES',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': 'FELICITACIONES',
        'PREGUNTA': 'LO CONSEGUISTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'YOU DID IT'
},
{
'ID': 5424,
        'TIPO': 'FELICITACIONES',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': 'FELICITACIONES',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MUY INTELIGENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CLEVER'
},
{
'ID': 5425,
        'TIPO': 'FELICITACIONES',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': 'FELICITACIONES',
        'PREGUNTA': 'QUE INTELIGENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'YOU\'RE CLEVER'
},
{
'ID': 5426,
        'TIPO': 'FELICITACIONES',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': 'FELICITACIONES',
        'PREGUNTA': 'CORRECTO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CORRECT'
},
{
'ID': 5427,
        'TIPO': 'FELICITACIONES',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': 'FELICITACIONES',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FABULOSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'LOVELY'
},
{
'ID': 5428,
        'TIPO': 'FELICITACIONES',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': 'FELICITACIONES',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ERES EL MEJOR',
        'RESPUESTA': 'YOU\'RE THE BEST'
},
{
'ID': 5430,
        'TIPO': 'FELICITACIONES',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': 'FELICITACIONES',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MUY BIEN HECHO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'NICELY DONE'
},
{
'ID': 5431,
        'TIPO': 'FELICITACIONES',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': 'FELICITACIONES',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ME ALEGRO POR TI',
        'RESPUESTA': 'GOOD FOR YOU'
},
{
'ID': 5432,
        'TIPO': 'FELICITACIONES',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': 'FELICITACIONES',
        'PREGUNTA': 'FANTASTICO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'FANTASTIC'
},
{
'ID': 5433,
        'TIPO': 'FELICITACIONES',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': 'FELICITACIONES',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ERES UN GENIO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'YOU\'RE A GENIUS'
},
{
'ID': 5434,
        'TIPO': 'FELICITACIONES',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': 'FELICITACIONES',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INCREIBLE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'UNBELIEVABLE'
},
{
'ID': 5435,
        'TIPO': 'FELICITACIONES',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': 'FELICITACIONES',
        'PREGUNTA': 'SOBRESALIENTE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'OUTSTANDING'
},
{
'ID': 5436,
        'TIPO': 'FELICITACIONES',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': 'FELICITACIONES',
        'PREGUNTA': 'INCREIBLE',
        'RESPUESTA': 'INCREDIBLE'
},
{
'ID': 5437,
        'TIPO': 'FELICITACIONES',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': 'FELICITACIONES',
        'PREGUNTA': 'GENIAL',
        'RESPUESTA': 'TERRIFIC'
},
{
'ID': 5438,
        'TIPO': 'FELICITACIONES',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': 'FELICITACIONES',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ESPLENDIDO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'SPLENDID'
},
{
'ID': 5439,
        'TIPO': 'FELICITACIONES',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': 'FELICITACIONES',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ASI ME GUSTA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'THAT\'S THE SPIRIT'
},
{
'ID': 5440,
        'TIPO': 'FELICITACIONES',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': 'FELICITACIONES',
        'PREGUNTA': 'ENHORABUENA',
        'RESPUESTA': 'CONGRATULATIONS'
},
{
'ID': 5441,
        'TIPO': 'FELICITACIONES',
        'NIVEL': 1,
        'LISTA': 'FELICITACIONES',
        'PREGUNTA': 'MARAVILLOSO',
        'RESPUESTA': 'MARVELLOUS'
}
]
